Ein Film von EDWARD YANG
A Film by EDWARD YANG
杨德昌的电影
Produziert von YU WEI-YEN, JAN HUNG-TZE und EDWARD YANG
Produced by YU WEI-YEN,
JAN HUNG-TZE, and EDWARD YANG
制作人：余伟彦、简鸿子、杨德昌
Mein Sohn war immer gut in chinesischer Literatur. SOMMER 1959
My son's always done well in Chinese literature.
SUMMER 1959
我儿子的中国文学成绩一直很好。1959 年夏
Er hätte nicht nur 50 Punkte erzielen können.
He couldn't have scored just 50.
他不可能只得50分。
In allen anderen Bereichen kam er auf fast 100 Punkte.
He got close to 100
in everything else.
他在其他所有科目的成绩都接近100分。
Da muss ein Fehler vorliegen.
There must be some mistake.
其中必定有什么错误。
Herr Wang ist auch unser Freund.
Mr. Wang is our friend as well.
王先生也是我们的朋友。
Er versteht unser Vorgehen.
He understands our procedure.
他了解我们的程序。
Wir werden die Ergebnisse Ihres Sohnes noch einmal überprüfen.
We'll double-check
your son's scores.
我们会仔细检查你儿子的分数。
Ich fürchte, ich kann Ihnen die Prüfungsunterlagen nicht zeigen.
I'm afraid I can't show you
the exam papers.
恐怕我不能给你看考卷。
Es verstößt gegen unsere Vorschriften.
It's against our regulations.
这违反了我们的规定。
Du Idiot! Heißer Tee bei diesem Wetter?
You idiot!
Hot tea in this weather?
你这个白痴！这种天气还喝热茶？
Ich verspreche, seine Ergebnisse noch einmal zu überprüfen.
I promise
to double-check his scores.
我保证会仔细检查他的分数。
Wenn der Prüfungsausschuss Fehler gemacht hat,
If the examination board
made any mistakes,
如果考试委员会犯了任何错误，
Wir nehmen alle notwendigen Anpassungen vor.
we'll make
any necessary adjustments.
我们将做出任何必要的调整。
Du kannst mir vertrauen.
You can trust me.
你可以相信我。
Wissen Sie, die Abendschule an der Jianguo High ist nicht schlecht.
You know, night school
at Jianguo High isn't bad.
你知道，建国中学的夜校还不错。
LISA YANG, CHANG CHEN
Chang Kuo-Chu, Elaine Jin
CHANG KUO-CHU, ELAINE JIN
Drehbuch und Dialog von EDWARD YANG, YAN HONG-YA ALEX YANG, LAl MING-TANG
Script And Dialogue by EDWARD YANG,
YAN HONG-YA ALEX YANG, LAl MING-TANG
剧本和对话：EDWARD YANG、YAN HONG-YA ALEX YANG、LAL MING-TANG
Kamera: CHANG HUI-KUNG, Ll LONG-YU
Cinematography by
CHANG HUI-KUNG, Ll LONG-YU
摄影：张惠昆、李隆宇
Ton von TU DUU-CHIH
Sound by
TU DUU-CHIH
音效：杜笃志
Herausgegeben von BOWEN CHEN
Edited by
BOWEN CHEN
编辑：BOWEN CHEN
Produktionsleiter WU ZHUANG
Production Manager
WU ZHUANG
Geplant von TAN YUN-SHENG
Planned by
TAN YUN-SHENG
谭云生策划
Präsentiert von Cheng Sul-Je, Lin Hsin-Nan Stan Lai, Edward Yang
Presented by CHENG SUl-JE, LIN
HSIN-NAN STAN LAI, EDWARD YANG
演讲者：郑素洁、林信南、赖志坚、杨德昌
Ausführende Produzenten JAN HUNG-TZE, JIANG FENG-CHYI
Executive Producers
JAN HUNG-TZE, JIANG FENG-CHYI
Produziert von YU WEI-YEN
Produced by
YU WEI-YEN
余伟彦制作
Regie: EDWARD YANG
Directed by
EDWARD YANG
导演：杨德昌
Ja, Ming-shew ...
Yeh Ming-shew...
叶明绍……
Wang Li&flQ'Yu---
王莉&flQ'Yu---
Chang Guang-hsi …
Chang Guang-hsi...
张光熙……
Lin Deng-fell …
Lin Deng-fell . .
林登倒下了。。
Die Vorgenannten haben sich qualifiziert
The preceding have qualified
前述已符合条件
für das Bildungsministerium
for the Education Department
教育部
an der Nationalen Universität für Politikwissenschaft.
at the National Political
Science University.
在国立政治大学。
Als nächstes für die Abteilung Politikwissenschaft
Next, for the Political Science
Department
接下来是政治学系
an der National Political Science University,
at National Political
Science University,
在国立政治大学，
Folgende 28 Studierende haben sich qualifiziert:
the following
28 students have qualified:
以下 28 名学生已获得资格：
Hsu Hsin-iang, Wang Shi-yeh.
Hsu Hsin-Iiang, Wang Shi-yeh...
许新阳, 王世业.
Millionen Festlandchinesen flohen 1949 nach Taiwan
Millions of mainland Chinese
fled to Taiwan in 1949
1949 年，数百万中国大陆人逃往台湾
mit der nationalistischen Regierung nach ihrer Niederlage im Bürgerkrieg
with the Nationalist government
after its defeat in the civil war
国民政府在内战失败后
von den chinesischen Kommunisten.
by the Chinese Communists.
由中国共产党领导。
Ihre Kinder wuchsen in einer unruhigen Atmosphäre auf
Their children were brought up
in an uneasy atmosphere
他们的孩子在不安的环境中长大
durch die Unsicherheit ihrer Eltern hinsichtlich der Zukunft.
created by their parents'
uncertainty about the future.
是由父母对未来的不确定性造成的。
Viele gründeten Straßengangs, um eine Identität zu finden
Many formed street gangs
to search for an identity
许多人组建街头帮派来寻找身份
und ihr Sicherheitsgefühl zu stärken.
and to strengthen
their sense of security.
增强群众安全感。
SEPTEMBER 1960
1960 年 9 月
Warum diese Farbe?
Why this color?
为什么是这个颜色？
Warum sich über die Farbe Gedanken machen?
Why worry about the color?
为什么要担心颜色？
Es ist ein Schwarz-Weiß-Film!
It's a black-and-white film!
这是一部黑白影片！
Wie kann ich so eine schreckliche Farbe tragen?
How can I wear
such an awful color?
我怎么能穿这么难看的颜色？
Ich habe dir gesagt, du sollst dich ändern, also ändere dich!
I told you to change,
so change!
我叫你改，你就改吧！
Es gibt keine Umkleidekabine.
There's no dressing room.
没有更衣室。
Ich habe dir gesagt, du sollst dich umziehen und nicht nackt gehen!
I told you to change,
not to go nude!
我叫你改变，不是叫你裸奔！
Warum bist du so aufgeregt? Beweg dich!
What are you so upset for?
Move!
你为什么这么烦恼？走开！
Waren wir uns nicht über das Kleid einig?
Didn't we agree on the dress?
我们不是已经就礼服问题达成一致了吗？
Jetzt ändern Sie die Dinge auf der Stelle!
Now you're changing things
on the spot!
现在您正在现场改变一切！
Hört alle zu: Das ist unsere letzte Chance.
Listen, everyone:
This is our last shot.
各位，听着：这是我们的最后一次机会。
Lass es uns hinter uns bringen!
Let's get it over with!
让我们把它解决掉吧！
Da oben ist jemand!
Someone's up there!
有人在上面！
Junge, was machst du da oben?
Kid, what are you doing up there?
孩子，你在上面干什么？
Du kommst nicht davon, du kleine Göre!
You're not getting away,
you little brat!
你别想逃跑，你这个小混蛋！
Glaubst du, du kannst weglaufen?
Think you can run away?
你以为你可以逃跑吗？
Du solltest in der Schule sein. Was machst du hier?
You should be in school.
What are you doing here?
你应该在学校。你在这里做什么？
Wie heißen Sie?
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
Abendschule? Welche Klasse?
Night school? What class?
夜校？什么课？
Ich weiß, wie ich Sie zum Reden bringen kann!
I have ways to make you talk!
我有办法让你开口！
8-6-O-8-9.
8-6-O-8-9。
Wer ist das? Lauf nicht weg!
Who's that? Don't run off!
那是谁？别跑！
Bleiben Sie, wo Sie sind!
Stay where you are!
留在原地！
Verdammte Kinder! Ich bring euch um!
Fucking kids! I'll kill you!
操你丫的！我要杀了你们！
Knutsch, Knutsch!
Smooch, smooch!
亲吻，亲吻！
Gib einen Kuss! Erziele einen Fehlschuss!
Have a kiss! Score a Miss!
亲一口！得分小姐！
Zeit für Techtelmechtel!
Hanky-panky time!
鬼鬼祟祟的时间！
Aufmerksamkeit.
Attention.
注意力。
Gruß.
Salute.
礼炮。
Nehmen Sie Platz.
Be seated.
就座。
Hey, Flugzeug! Flieg her!
Hey, Airplane!
Fly over here!
嘿，飞机！飞过来！
Wo hast du die Taschenlampe her?
Where'd you get the flashlight?
你从哪儿弄来的手电筒？
Xiao Si’r hat es aus dem Filmstudio mitgenommen.
Xiao Si'r snatched it
from the film studio.
是小四儿从电影制片厂抢来的。
Halt die Klappe, Unterhose! Hör auf, nach dem Test zu fragen!
Shut up, Underpants!
Stop asking about the test!
闭嘴，内裤！别再问测试的事了！
Höschen, Höschen, dünn und schick!
Panty, panty, flimsy and fancy!
内裤，内裤，脆弱又花哨！
Wenn Sie ins Schwitzen kommen, verwenden Sie es als Taschentuch.
If you get sweaty,
use it as a hanky.
如果你出汗了，可以把它当作手帕使用。
Hol eins für deine Mama!
Get one for your mommy!
给你的妈妈买一个吧！
Ruhe, es ist Red Bean.
Hush up. it's Red Bean.
安静点。这是红豆。
Leuchte sie damit an.
Shine it on her.
照耀着她。
Mach weiter!
Go on!
继续！
Wie funktioniert es?
How's it work?
怎么運作？
Was habt ihr kleinen Gören vor?
What are you little brats up to?
你们这群小家伙在干什么呢？
- Ich wette, sie sind rot! - Blödsinn!
- I bet you they're red!
- Bullshit!
- 我敢打赌它们是红色的！ - 胡说！
- Wollen wir wetten? - Wie viel?
- Wanna bet?
- How much?
- 想打赌吗？ - 多少？
- Zehn Dollar. - Nein, einen.
- Ten bucks.
- No, one.
- 十块钱。 - 不，一块钱。
- Ein Dollar? - Das nennst du eine Wette?
- One buck?
- You call that a bet?
- 一块钱？ - 你把这叫做赌注？
Scheiße, was für ein Geizhals!
Shit, what a Cheapskate!
妈的，真是个吝啬鬼！
Mit Ihnen kann man zu geizig wetten.
You're too cheap to bet with.
你太小气了，不值得跟你打赌。
Du zahlst nie.
You never pay up.
你从不付钱。
- Sieht aus, als ob etwas nicht stimmt. - Muss etwas Schlimmes sein.
- Looks like somethings up.
- Must be something bad.
- 看起来有些不对劲。 - 肯定有什么不好的事情。
Es geht dich einen Scheißdreck an.
It's none of your damn business.
这不关你的事。
Es kommt zu einer Schlägerei. Sly wird in der Grundschule in die Enge getrieben.
There's a fight.
Sly's cornered at the grade school.
打架了。史莱被逼到了小学的角落。
Sir, geben Sie mir das. - Okay.
Si'r, let me have that.
- Okay.
先生，把这个给我吧。 - 好的。
- Sexbombe, wir brauchen deine Hilfe. - Kein Problem.
- Sex Bomb, we need your help.
- No problem.
- Sex Bomb，我们需要你的帮助。 - 没问题。
- Ich gehe nicht. - Wer hat dich gefragt?
- I'm not going.
- Who asked you?
- 我不去。 - 谁问你了？
Vergiss ihn. Lass uns gehen.
Forget about him.
Let's go.
忘掉他吧，我们走吧。
- Er wird wieder zum Pornostand gehen. - Pornofreak!
- He'll hit the porn stand again.
- Porn freak!
- 他会再次光顾色情摊位。 - 色情狂！
Halt!
Hold it!
坚持住！
Sly, alles in Ordnung?
Sly, you okay?
史莱，你还好吗？
Scheiße!
Shit!
拉屎！
Warum hast du so lange gebraucht?
What took you so long?
您为什么花了这么长时间？
Wir können uns nicht einmal um unser eigenes Revier kümmern!
Can't even take care
of our own turf!
连自己的地盘都照顾不好！
Geben wir es auf oder was?
Are we giving it up or what?
我们是放弃还是怎样？
Hast du eine Zigarette dabei?
Got a smoke on you?
你身上有烟吗？
Hey, Deuce.
嘿，Deuce。
Scheiße! Wie konnte das passieren?
Shit! How did this happen?
妈的！这是怎么回事？
Sie haben mich alleine erwischt, das ist alles.
They got me alone, that's all.
他们只抓到了我一个人，就是这样。
Ich habe sie bisher alleine auf Abstand gehalten.
I held them off
by myself till now.
我一直独自阻止他们直到现在。
Versuchen Sie das nächste Mal.
You try that next time.
你下次试试看。
Ich mache Ihnen keine Vorwürfe.
I'm not blaming you.
我没有责怪你。
Aber was machst du so spät noch hier?
But what are you
doing here so late?
但是你这么晚来这里干什么？
Das geht Sie nichts an.
None of your business.
关你屁事。
Wie konnten wir zulassen, dass die 217-Bande unser Revier beschmutzt?
How could we let the 217 gang
mess with our turf?
我们怎能让217帮来搅乱我们的地盘？
Ich sage Ihnen, alle haben es auf uns abgesehen.
I tell you,
everyone's out to get us.
我告诉你，大家都想来救我们。
Wenn es nicht die 217 Jungs wären, wären es andere gewesen.
If it weren't the 217 boys,
it'd be others.
如果不是这 217 名男孩，就会是其他人。
Wenn dein Bruder nicht bald zurückkommt, sind wir erledigt.
If your brother doesn't
come back soon, we're through.
如果你哥哥不快点回来，我们就完了。
- Schatz ist nicht hier. Ich bin hier. - Du bist hier!
- Honey's not here. I am.
- You are!
- 亲爱的不在这里。我在。- 你在！
Bitte verprügeln Sie mich nicht!
Please don't beat me up!
请不要打我！
Es tut mir leid! Schlag mich nicht!
I'm sorry!
Don't beat me up!
对不起！别打我！
Ich bin nur mitgelaufen.
I was just tagging along.
我只是跟着来的。
Ich gehöre nicht dazu. Wir sind keine Feinde!
I'm not one of them.
We're not enemies!
我不是他们中的一员。我们不是敌人！
Sie beide wollen also etwas Großes erreichen?
So you two want
to go big time?
那么你们两个想要大干一场吗？
Der Junge ist zu laut. Bring ihn zum Schweigen.
This kid's too noisy.
Shut him up.
这孩子太吵了。让他闭嘴。
Schlag mich nicht!
Don't hit me!
别打我！
Beobachten Sie genau.
Watch closely.
仔细观察。
Schauen Sie genau hin.
Get a good look.
好好看看。
Wir brauchen keine feigen Hühner.
We don't need
chickenshit cowards.
我们不需要胆小鬼。
Aufstehen.
Get up.
起床。
Aufstehen!
Get up!
起床！
Geh zurück und erzähl es deinem großen Bruder!
Go back
and tell your big brother!
回去跟你大哥说一声吧！
Leg dich nie mit den Jungs von Little Park an!
Never fuck
with the Little Park boys!
永远不要和 Little Park 的男孩们发生性关系！
Warum schaltest du das Licht an und aus?
Why are you switching
the lights on and off?
你为什么打开和关闭灯？
Meine Sicht wird verschwommen. Ich weiß nicht, warum.
My eyes go blurry.
I don't know why.
我的眼睛变得模糊。我不知道为什么。
Gehen Sie früher ins Bett, dann ist alles in Ordnung.
Get to bed earlier
and you'll be okay.
早点睡觉，你会没事的。
Warum bist du so spät zu Hause?
Why are you home so late?
你为什么这么晚回家？
Wir blieben alle danach, um über den Test zu sprechen.
We all stayed afterwards
to talk about the test.
考试结束后我们都留下来讨论考试的事情。
Das geht nicht! Ich kann es nicht unterdrücken!
It won't work!
I can 'I button it!
不行！我扣不了！
Mach, dass es vorerst klappt. Der Bus kommt.
Make it work for now.
The bus is coming.
先让它运转起来。公交车来了。
Lao Er, warum bist du nicht wach?
Lao Er, why aren't you up?
老二，你怎么还不起来？
Muss ich dich jeden Tag aus dem Bett zerren?
Do I have to drag you
out of bed every day?
我是不是每天都得把你从床上拖起来？
Morgen, es ist abgefallen!
Morn, it fell off!
早上好，它掉下来了！
Zum Annähen ist keine Zeit. Benutze vorerst eine Stecknadel.
There's no time to sew it on.
Use a pin for now.
没有时间缝上它了。暂时用别针吧。
Was ist los? Schon wieder aus deinen Klamotten herausgewachsen?
What's wrong?
Outgrew your clothes again?
怎么了？衣服又穿不下了？
Mama, ich kann keine Stecknadel finden!
Mom, I can't find a pin!
妈妈，我找不到别针了！
- Ich bin o“. - Wo gehst du so früh hin?
- I'm o“.
- Where are you going this early?
- 我好早啊。- 你这么早要去哪儿？
- Es ist Samstag. - /z"s r00 früh, sogar für Samstag.
- It's Saturday.
- /z"s r00 early even for Saturday.
- 今天是星期六。- /z"s r00 即使是星期六也来得早。
Unsere Klasse ist beim wöchentlichen Treffen an der Reihe.
It's our class's turn
at the weekly meeting.
现在轮到我们班参加周会了。
- Keine Schuhe im Haus! - Ich brauche meinen Kompass!
- No shoes in the house!
- I need my compass!
- 屋里不能穿鞋！ - 我需要我的指南针！
- Wow! Frisch aus der Wanne! - Was bringen die dir denn bei!
- Wow! Just out of the tub!
- What do they teach you!
- 哇哦！刚从浴缸里出来！- 他们教你什么！
Sie sind wie die Amerikaner und baden morgens.
You're like Americans,
bathing in the morning.
你们就像美国人一样，早上洗澡。
- Das geht dich nichts an! - Los geht's.
- It's none of your business!
- Let's go.
- 这不关你的事！ - 我们走吧。
Auf Wiedersehen.
Good-bye.
再见。
Ich werde verfügbar sein
I'll be available
我会
jeden Samstagnachmittag im Krankenrevier.
every Saturday afternoon
at the infirmary.
每个星期六下午在医务室。
Ich verdanke meiner Alma Mater so viel
I owe so much to my alma mater
我欠母校太多了
und an Rektor He für das, was ich heute erreicht habe.
and to Principal He
for what I've achieved today.
也感谢何校长，感谢他让我取得了今天的成就。
Ich bin ehrlich gesagt der Meinung, dass ich diese Anerkennung nicht verdiene.
I honestly feel
I don't deserve this recognition.
我确实觉得我不配获得这种认可。
Ich empfinde es als meine Pflicht, mich freiwillig in Ihrer Klinik zu engagieren.
I feel it's my duty to volunteer
to serve in your clinic.
我认为自愿到您的诊所服务是我的责任。
Danke schön.
Thank you.
谢谢。
Schüler 8-6-0-8-9!
Student 8-6-0-8-9!
学生 8-6-0-8-9！
Melden Sie sich umgehend beim Ordnungsamt!
Report to the conduct office
at once!
立刻去行为办公室报告！
Diejenigen unter Ihnen, die Baseball mögen, sollten zuhören.
Those of you
who like baseball, listen up.
喜欢棒球的朋友们，听好了。
Ein Tagesschüler
A day school student
一名日校学生
habe Herrn Chen gestern mit einem Baseballschläger verletzt.
hurt Mr. Chen yesterday
with a baseball bat.
昨天用棒球棒打伤了陈先生。
Hast du davon gehört?
Did you hear about it?
你听说过吗？
Ab heute
Starting today,
从今天开始，
Alle Baseballschläger müssen registriert werden.
all baseball bats
must be registered.
所有棒球棒均须注册。
Alle nicht registrierten Fledermäuse werden beschlagnahmt.
All unregistered bats
will be confiscated.
所有未登记的球棒将被没收。
Hörst du mich?
You hear me?
你听见了吗？
Er war es! Ich bin mir sicher!
It was him! I'm positive!
就是他！我敢肯定！
Ich habe deine Taschenlampe nicht mitgenommen.
I didn't take your flashlight.
我没有拿你的手电筒。
Wo ist der andere Junge?
Where's the other boy?
另外一个男孩在哪儿？
Wer ist der andere Junge?
Who's the other boy?
另外一个男孩是谁？
Wir wollten nichts Böses.
We didn't mean any harm.
我们并不想造成任何伤害。
Er hat es nicht genommen, das schwöre ich.
He didn't take it, I swear.
我发誓，他没有拿走它。
- Waren Sie gestern bei ihm? - Ja.
- Were you with him yesterday?
- Yes.
- 你昨天和他在一起吗？ - 是的。
Geh da rüber!
Get over there!
快去那边！
- Warst du es, der mein Fenster eingeschlagen hat? - Nein.
- Was it you who broke my window?
- No.
- 是你打破了我的窗户吗？ - 不是。
Was ist los?
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
Zhang Zhen lungerte im Filmstudio herum.
Zhang Zhen was hanging
around the film studio.
张震正在电影片场附近闲逛。
Jetzt fehlt etwas.
Now something's missing.
现在缺少了一些东西。
Diese Studenten werden jedes Jahr schlauer.
These students get
craftier every year.
这些学生一年比一年狡猾。
Aber Ihr Filmstudio ist gleich nebenan.
But your film studio
is right next door.
但你的电影制片厂就在隔壁。
Nein danke.
No, thanks.
不，谢谢。
Ich kann dieses Problem nicht für Sie lösen.
I can't solve
this problem for you.
我无法帮你解决这个问题。
Natürlich nicht.
Of course not.
当然不是。
Ein Schüler hat einem Lehrer den Schädel eingeschlagen
A student cracked
a teacher's skull
一名学生打破了一名老师的头骨
mit einem von denen vor kurzem.
with one of those recently.
最近有其中的一个。
Das ist ein echtes Problem!
It's a real problem!
这确实是个问题！
Sie sollten lieber hart gegen sie vorgehen.
You'd better come down
hard on them.
你最好严厉惩罚他们。
Unser Schulleiter legt Wert auf die Entwicklung ihres freien Geistes.
Our principal insists
on developing their free spirits.
我们的校长坚持培养他们的自由精神。
Unser Schultor ist nie verschlossen.
Our school gate's never locked.
我们的校门从来不锁。
Sie sollten Ihre Tore besser fest verschließen.
You better lock your gates tight.
你最好把门锁紧。
Sie lassen Ihres offen und wir lassen unseres offen.
You leave yours open,
and we'll leave ours open.
你们的保持开放，我们也将保持开放。
Wir können uns gegenseitig besuchen!
We can visit each other!
我们可以互相拜访！
Warum verbreitest du Gerüchte über mich?
Why are you spreading
rumors about me?
你为什么散布关于我的谣言？
Was habe ich gesagt?
What did I say?
我说了啥？
Du hast gesagt, ich sei an dem Abend mit einem Mädchen in der Schule gewesen.
You said I was with a girl
that night at the school.
你说那天晚上我在学校和一个女孩在一起。
Sie haben nichts gesehen, verstanden?
You didn't see a thing,
understand?
你什么也没看到，明白吗？
- Das ist mein Platz. - Nehmen Sie meinen hinten.
- That's my seat.
- Take mine in the back.
- 那是我的座位。 - 坐在后面的座位上。
Gruß.
Salute.
礼炮。
Lassen Sie mich das kopieren.
Let me copy off you.
让我抄袭你的说法。
Schauen Sie einfach, was passiert, wenn Sie es nicht tun.
Just see what happens
if you don't.
看看如果不这样做会发生什么。
- Hast du Nummer 4 beantwortet? - Vergiss es. Lass uns Ball spielen.
- Did you answer No. 4?
- Forget it. Let's play ball.
- 你回答了第 4 个问题吗？ - 算了，我们一起玩吧。
Okay.
好的。
Fick dich!
Fuck you!
去你的！
Schau mich nicht so an.
Don't give me that look.
别用那种眼神看着我。
Sie ließen mich nicht kopieren, was?
Wouldn't let me copy, huh?
不让我抄袭是吧？
Starr weiter, harter Kerl.
Keep staring, tough guy.
继续盯着吧，硬汉。
Probieren Sie es einfach aus. Ich fordere Sie heraus.
Just try it. I dare you.
试试吧。我向你挑战。
Hallo, Sir.
Hello, sir.
你好先生。
Wir spielen nur herum.
We're just playing around.
我们只是在玩玩而已。
Kommt ihr Jungs gerne in mein Büro?
You boys enjoy
coming to my office?
你们喜欢来我的办公室吗？
Dann stehe ich Ihnen jederzeit gerne zur Verfügung.
If so,
I'm at your service anytime.
如果是的话，我随时为您服务。
Er ist kein gewöhnlicher Bücherwurm.
He's not your regular bookworm.
他并不是普通的书呆子。
Wenn es zu Auseinandersetzungen kommt, macht er keine Scherze.
If you lock horns,
he doesn't fuck around.
如果你们发生争执，他不会胡闹。
Was ist mit meinem Schläger?
What about my bat?
我的球棒怎么样？
Ich besorge dir noch eins.
I'll get you another one.
我再给你拿一个。
Das habe ich mir gerade gekauft.
I just bought that one.
我刚买了那个。
Siebzig Dollar!
Seventy bucks!
七十块钱！
Bitte überbring das, Onkel Fat.
Please deliver this, Uncle Fat.
请把这个交给我吧，胖叔叔。
Sie haben Männer in der Familie. Die können das verstehen!
You've got men in the family.
They can pick it up!
你家里还有男人。他们可以接手！
Und?!
Si?!
和？！
Hör auf zu trinken, ja?
Stop drinking, will you?
别再喝酒了，好吗？
Du solltest besser gehen.
You'd better go.
你最好走吧。
Was ist mit deinem Gesicht passiert?
What happened to your face?
你的脸怎么了？
Ich habe es mir beim Baseballspielen verletzt.
I hurt it playing baseball.
我在打棒球时伤了它。
Hast du es dir beim Baseball verletzt?
You hurt it playing baseball?
你打棒球时受伤了吗？
Kaufen wir bei Onkel Fat nicht mehr auf Kredit.
Let's not buy from Uncle Fat
on credit anymore.
我们不要再向胖叔叔赊购东西了。
Er war in letzter Zeit wirklich gemein. Ich habe keine Ahnung, warum.
He's been real mean lately.
I have no idea why.
他最近很坏。我不知道为什么。
Er ist eifersüchtig, dass du zur Universität gehst.
He's jealous of you
going to the university.
他嫉妒你上大学。
Seine Tochter ist auch dieses Jahr wieder durch die Prüfung gefallen.
His daughter failed
the exam again this year.
他的女儿今年考试又没及格。
Schon wieder diese Musik vom Obststand!
That music
from the fruit stand again!
水果摊上又传来那首音乐！
Es wird jeden Tag lauter.
It's louder every day.
每天都会更吵。
Acht Jahre Krieg mit den Japanern.
Eight years of war
with the Japanese.
与日本人进行了八年的战争。
Jetzt leben wir in einem japanischen Haus und hören japanische Musik.
Now we live in a Japanese house
and listen to Japanese music.
现在我们住在日本的房子里，听日本音乐。
Vergessen Sie nicht, dass wir am Sonntag zum Abendessen zu Wang eingeladen sind.
Don't forget we're invited
to Wang's for dinner Sunday.
别忘了周日我们被邀请到王家吃饭。
Muss ich gehen? Sind da nicht nur Erwachsene?
Do I have to go?
Won't it be all grown-ups?
我一定要去吗？那不是都是成年人吗？
- Warum hast du so wenig gegessen? - Es werden viele Kinder da sein.
- Why'd you eat so little?
- There'll be lots of children.
- 你为什么吃得这么少？ - 会有很多孩子。
Ich bin satt.
I'm full.
我吃饱了。
Sollen wir ein Geschenk mitbringen?
Shall we bring a present?
我们要带礼物吗？
Sicher.
Sure.
当然。
„Die Rechnung mit Sly wird bis heute beglichen sein.“
“The score with Sly
will be settled by this day.”
“今天，斯莱的账就算算了。”
Hier, 70 Dollar.
Here, 70 bucks.
给，70块钱。
Alles klar! Wo hast du es her?
All right!
Where'd you get it?
好的！你从哪儿弄来的？
Stellen Sie nicht zu viele Fragen.
Don't ask too many questions.
不要问太多问题。
Kennedys Erfahrung in der Außenpolitik
Kennedy's experience
in foreign affairs
肯尼迪的外交经历
ist sehr begrenzt.
is very limited.
非常有限。
Angesichts der kommunistischen Weltgemeinschaft
Faced with the world's
communist community,
面对世界共产主义大家庭，
die amerikanische Öffentlichkeit wird der Präsidentschaft nicht vertrauen
the American public
won't entrust the presidency
美国公众不会信任总统
an einen jungen, unerfahrenen Kerl wie ihn.
t0 a young,
inexperienced fellow like him.
对他这样年轻、缺乏经验的人来说。
Thomas, geh nach hinten.
Thomas, get in the back.
托马斯，到后面去。
Kleines Mädchen, stell dich hinter deine Mutter.
Little girl,
stand behind your mother.
小女孩，站在你妈妈身后。
Wan-wan, versteck dich nicht hinten. Du bist immer so schüchtern.
Wan-wan, don't hide in back.
You're always so shy.
婉婉，别躲在后面了，你总是这么害羞。
Wang, Sie laden uns jedes Mal ein, wenn Sie von einer Dienstreise zurückkommen.
Wang, you have us over every time
you return from an official trip.
王先生，您每次出差回来都欢迎我们。
„Offizielle Reise“! Ich gehe aus Spaß hin.
“Official trip”!
I go for the fun of it.
“正式旅行”！我是为了好玩才去的。
Amerika ist unglaublich. Die Wolkenkratzer -
America's incredible.
The skyscrapers -
美国真是不可思议。摩天大楼——
- Machst du Witze? - Auf keinen Fall!
- Are you kidding?
- Absolutely not!
- 你在开玩笑吗？ - 绝对不是！
Sie haben Wolkenkratzer und Disneyland!
They've got skyscrapers,
and Disneyland!
他们有摩天大楼和迪士尼乐园！
Mickey Maus. Ein toller Ort für Kinder.
Mickey Mouse.
A great place for kids.
米老鼠。孩子们的好去处。
Sie gaben mir eine Führung durch eine Atombombenfabrik.
They gave me a tour
of an atomic bomb factory.
他们带我参观了原子弹工厂。
Wenn ich ein Experte wäre,
If I were an expert,
如果我是专家，
Ich hätte gelernt, meine eigene Atombombe zu bauen.
I'd have learned to make
my own A-bomb.
我会学会制造自己的原子弹。
Dann könnte ich die Kommunisten in die Luft jagen.
Then I could blow
the Communists to hell.
然后我就可以把共产党炸下地狱。
Okay, Zeit für das Bild.
Okay, time for the picture.
好的，现在该拍照了。
Schaut alle hierher.
Everyone look this way.
大家都朝这边望去。
Sagen Sie nichts, bis es offiziell bekannt gegeben wird.
Don't say anything
until it's officially announced.
在官方宣布之前不要说任何话。
Danke schön.
Thank you.
谢谢。
Das ist eine schöne Überraschung.
This is a nice surprise.
这真是一个惊喜。
Nicht der Rede wert. Wir sind so alte Freunde.
Don't mention it.
We're such old friends.
别客气，我们都是老朋友了。
Aber es gibt etwas, woran ich Sie erinnern muss.
But there's something
I must remind you of.
但有一件事我必须提醒你。
Es sind 12 Jahre vergangen
It's been 12 years
12年过去了
seit wir aus Shanghai hierher gekommen sind.
since we came here
from Shanghai.
因为我们是从上海来这里的。
Es ist unwahrscheinlich, dass wir jemals zurückkehren.
It's unlikely
we'll ever make it back.
我们可能永远也无法再回去了。
Solange noch Zeit ist,
While there's still time,
趁还有时间，
wir sollten einige langfristige Pläne machen.
we should make
some long-term plans.
我们应该制定一些长期计划。
Ihre alte intellektuelle Shanghai-Mentalität -
Your old Shanghai
intellectual mentality -
你的老上海知识分子心态——
werde es los.
get rid of it.
摆脱它。
Passen Sie auf Ihr Temperament auf.
Watch your temper.
注意你的脾气。
Sie müssen lernen, flexibel zu sein.
You have to learn to be flexible.
你必须学会​​灵活变通。
Oberflächlich betrachtet,
On the surface,
从表面上看，
Ich helfe Ihnen, diese Beförderung zu bekommen.
I'm helping you
get this promotion.
我正在帮助你获得这次晋升。
Eigentlich wirst du mir in Zukunft helfen.
Actually, you'll be helping me
in the future.
事实上，你将来会帮助我的。
Wir sind Klassenkameraden. Alte Freunde.
We're classmates.
Old friends.
我们是同学。老朋友。
Wie in einer Gang.
Like in a gang.
就像在帮派里一样。
Verstehen?
Understand?
理解？
Si'r wieder in die Tagesschule versetzen
Getting Si'r transferred
back to day school
让 Sir 转回日校
ist mit meinen aktuellen Anschlüssen kein Problem.
is no problem
with my current connections.
我当前的连接没有问题。
Danke.
Thanks.
谢谢。
Die Abendschule ist furchtbar.
The night school's awful.
夜校太糟糕了。
Ich mache mir Sorgen, dass er böse wird.
I worry about him turning bad.
我担心他会变坏。
Was machst du?
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Hau ab.
Get lost.
迷路。
- Sie haben sich einen guten Platz zum Beobachten ausgesucht. - Was?
- You picked a good spot to watch.
- What?
- 你选了个好地点观看。- 什么？
Aus dem Weg!
Out of the way!
走开！
Mama, mir ist langweilig. Lass uns nach Hause gehen.
Mom, I'm bored.
Let's go home.
妈妈，我无聊，我们回家吧。
Bald, bald.
Soon,soon.
快了，快了。
Es ist noch wie neu.
It's still like new.
它还像新的一样。
Ich benutze es fast nie.
I almost never use it.
我几乎从来不用它。
Ich habe selten die Gelegenheit, eine so schöne Uhr zu tragen.
I rarely have the occasion
to wear such a nice watch.
我很少有机会戴这么漂亮的手表。
Wie die Zeit vergeht.
How time flies.
时间过得真快。
Als ich dir diese Uhr gab ...
When I gave you that watch...
当我给你那块手表的时候……
Warum haben Sie Professor Hsia vor Frau Hsia erwähnt?
Why did you mention Professor Hsia
in front of Mrs. Hsia?
你干嘛在夏太太面前提起夏教授啊？
Ich habe es nicht getan.
I didn't.
我没有。
Sie hat meine Uhr gesehen.
She saw my watch.
她看到了我的手表。
Warum ist Professor Hsia allein nach Shanghai zurückgekehrt?
Why did Professor Hsia
go back to Shanghai alone?
夏教授为何只身回上海？
Der Wunsch, weitere Verwandte herbeizuholen, muss ein Vorwand gewesen sein.
Bringing more relatives over
must have been an excuse.
带更多的亲戚过来肯定是一个借口。
Frau Hsia lebt seitdem wie eine Witwe.
Mrs. Hsia's lived
like a widow ever since.
从此，夏女士就过着寡妇般的生活。
Worüber hat Wang mit Ihnen gesprochen?
What was Wang
talking to you about?
王跟你谈了什么？
Ach, nichts.
Oh, nothing.
哦，没什么。
Er kann dabei helfen, Si'r auf die Tagesschule zu versetzen.
He can help get Si'r
transferred to day school.
他可以帮助小四转学到日校。
Es sollte kein Problem geben.
There shouldn't be any problem.
应该没有什么问题。
Was ist mit meiner Lehrbefähigung?
What about
my teaching certificate?
我的教师资格证怎么办？
Meine Probleme scheinen Sie nicht allzu sehr zu beunruhigen.
You don't seem too concerned
about my problems.
你好像不太关心我的问题。
Zum Glück kam mein Arbeitsvertrag dieses Jahr schon früher.
Luckily my letter of employment
came early this year.
幸好我的聘书今年来得早。
Jedes Jahr erlebe ich den gleichen Stress.
Every year I go
through the same stress.
每年我都会承受同样的压力。
Sie wissen, was ich meine.
You know what I mean.
你知道我的意思。
Wessen Schuld ist das?
Whose fault is that?
那是谁的错？
Ich habe Ihnen gesagt, Sie sollten Ihre offiziellen Papiere mitbringen, wenn wir Shanghai verlassen.
I told you to bring your official papers
when we left Shanghai.
我告诉过你，我们离开上海时要带上你的公证件。
Das habe ich. Ich habe sie in die Bonbondose getan, die wir mitgebracht hatten.
I did. I put them
in the candy tin that we brought.
是的。我把它们放在我们带来的糖果罐里。
Lesen Sie nicht im Bus. Sie ruinieren Ihre Augen.
Don't read on the bus.
You'll ruin your eyes.
不要在公交车上看书。这会毁了你的眼睛。
Diese Abendkurse müssen Sirs Augen wehtun.
Those night classes
must be hurting Si'r's eyes.
那些晚课肯定对小四的眼睛有伤害。
Sie behaupten, dass die kostenlosen Impfungen in der Schule helfen würden.
They claim the free shots
at school will help.
他们声称学校的免费疫苗接种会有所帮助。
Ich hoffe, dass wir ihm dadurch keine Brille kaufen müssen.
I hope it will save us
from having to buy him glasses.
我希望这能省去我们给他买眼镜的麻烦。
Er möchte Ihnen ein Geheimnis verraten.
He has a secret to tell you.
他有一个秘密要告诉你。
Welches Geheimnis?
What secret?
什么秘密？
Sag es ihr. Sie gibt dir etwas umsonst.
Tell her.
She'll give you a freebie.
告诉她。她会给你一份免费赠品。
Ich komme oft hierher, weil du so hübsch bist.
I come here often
because you're so pretty.
我经常来这里，因为你太漂亮了。
Ich nehme das. - Du musst bezahlen! Gib es zurück!
I'll take this.
- You have to pay! Give it back!
我要这个。-你必须付钱！还给我！
- Ich habe kein Geld. - Dann gib es zurück.
- I have no money.
- Then give it back.
- 我没有钱。 - 那就还给我吧。
NEIN.
No.
不。
NEIN?
No?
不？
Nicht auspacken!
Don't unwrap it!
别拆开它！
Pack es nicht aus!
Don't you unwrap it!
别拆开它！
Gib es zurück!
Give it back!
还给我！
Sie sind rot!
They're red!
它们是红色的！
- Du schuldest mir 10 Dollar! - Nein, einen!
- You owe me 1O bucks!
- No, one!
- 你欠我 10 块钱！ - 不，一块钱！
Tiger, du betrügst!
Tiger, you're cheating!
老虎你作弊了！
Fass das nicht an!
Don't touch that!
别碰那个！
Einer nach dem anderen. Wissen Sie nicht, wie man sich anstellt?
One at a time.
Don't you know how to line up?
一次一个。你不知道怎么排队吗？
Wang Chun-ming.
Viermal täglich. Kommen Sie wieder, wenn es nicht hilft.
Four times a day.
Come back if it doesn't help.
一天四次。如果没有帮助就再来。
Bauchschmerzen?
A stomachache?
胃痛吗？
Bist du sicher?
You're sure?
你确定嗎？
Du willst mich doch nicht zum Narren halten? - Nein.
You're not trying to fool me?
- No.
你不是想愚弄我吧？ - 不是。
So einfach kann man Sie nicht nach Hause schicken.
You can't get sent home
that easily.
你不能那么轻易地被送回家。
Kommen Sie morgen für eine weitere Behandlung in meine Klinik.
Come to my clinic tomorrow
for another treatment.
明天来我的诊所接受另一次治疗。
Fräulein Ling.
Miss Ling.
凌小姐。
Kannst du alleine gehen? - Ich denke schon.
Can you walk by yourself?
- I think so.
你能自己走路吗？ - 我认为可以。
Probieren Sie es aus.
Give it a try.
尝试一下。
Lass es uns tun. Du da.
Let's do this. You there.
咱们开始吧。你在那里。
Bitte helfen Sie ihr zurück in ihr Klassenzimmer.
Please help her back
to her classroom.
请帮助她回到教室。
Es ist okay. Ich kann alleine gehen.
It's okay.
I can walk by myself.
没事的，我可以自己走。
Es ist okay. Ich kann alleine gehen.
It's okay.
I can walk by myself.
没事的，我可以自己走。
Sie können zum Unterricht zurückkehren.
You can go back to class.
你可以回课堂了。
Mir geht es gut.
I'm fine.
我很好。
Unser Militärberater.
Our military adviser.
我们的军事顾问。
- Eine Packung New Paradise. - Dreihundertfünfzig.
- A pack of New Paradise.
- Three fifty.
- 一包新天堂。 - 三点五十分。
- Sie sind neu hier. - Das stimmt.
- You're new here.
- That's right.
- 你是新来的。 - 没错。
- Woher kommen Sie? - Taichung.
- Where are you from?
- Taichung.
- 你来自哪里？ - 台中。
Einmal hat er mich beim Schwänzen erwischt.
He caught me
cutting class once.
有一次他发现我逃课。
Ich habe in der Nähe von Taichung gelebt, auf dem Luftwaffenstützpunkt CCK.
I used to live near Taichung,
at the CCK air base.
我曾经住在台中附近的 CCK 空军基地。
Es erinnert mich an Wuhan auf dem Festland.
It reminds me of Wuhan,
on the mainland.
这让我想起了大陆的武汉。
Wir können nicht für immer hier bleiben.
We can't stay here forever.
我们不能永远呆在这里。
Sie können mich hier nicht ewig warten lassen.
You can't keep me
waiting here forever.
你不能让我永远在这里等。
Der Chef nimmt mich nächsten Monat mit nach Hongkong.
The boss is taking me
to Hong Kong next month.
老板下个月要带我去香港。
Sie möchten etwas aus Hongkong?
You want anything
from Hong Kong?
您想要什么来自香港的东西吗？
Lass mich darüber nachdenken. Ich werde es dir heute Abend erzählen.
Let me think about it.
I'll tell you tonight.
让我考虑一下。今晚我就告诉你。
Zeit für Make-up.
Time for makeup.
化妆时间到了。
Oh, ich kann morgen Abend nicht.
Oh, I can't make it
tomorrow evening.
哦，我明天晚上不能来。
Feldmarschall Wong lädt mich zum Abendessen ein.
Field Marshal Wong
is taking me to dinner.
黄元帅带我去吃饭。
Wir haben das Date gestern vereinbart... äh, letzten Monat.
We made the date yesterday...
uh, last month.
我们昨天约了……呃，上个月。
Wenn Sie kündigen möchten, sagen Sie es dem Chef und ersparen Sie uns beiden den Ärger!
If you want to quit, tell the boss
and save us both the trouble!
如果你想辞职，就跟老板说，省得我们双方麻烦！
Das habe ich nicht gesagt. Hören Sie auf, nach Ausreden zu suchen.
I didn't say that.
Stop looking for excuses.
我没这么说过。别再找借口了。
Soll ich nach Ausreden suchen?
Me look for excuses?
我找借口？
Du bist derjenige, der nach Ausreden sucht!
You're the one
looking for excuses!
你就是那个找借口的人！
Soll ich nach Ausreden suchen?
Me look for excuses?
我找借口？
Und warum so viel Make-up? Es bringt meine Vorzüge nicht zur Geltung.
And why all the heavy makeup?
It doesn't show my finest features.
为什么要化这么浓的妆？这不利于我展现出最好的一面。
Welche Funktionen?
What features?
有哪些特点？
Was haben Sie außer der Sympathie Ihres Chefs noch zu bieten?
Besides the boss liking you,
what else have you got?
除了老板喜欢你之外，你还有什么？
Mit dir ist nicht zu reden!
There's no talking to you!
没法跟你说话！
Habe ich etwas zu Ihrem Skript gesagt?
Did I say anything
about your script?
我有说过关于你的剧本的事吗？
Woher hast du es kopiert?
Where'd you copy it from?
你从哪儿复制来的？
Ich sage es dem Chef. Zur Hölle mit dir!
I'm telling the boss.
To hell with you!
我要告诉老板。去你的！
Verschwinde, verdammt noch mal!
Get the hell out!
滚出去！
Wer ist hier der Regisseur, Sie oder ich?
Who's the director here,
you or me?
这里谁是导演，你还是我？
Meckern über zu viel Make-up!
Bitching about
too much makeup!
抱怨化妆太浓！
Was zur Hölle!
What the hell!
我勒个去！
Schau in den Spiegel!
Look in the mirror!
照照镜子！
Dieses Gesicht braucht so viel Make-up wie möglich!
That face needs
all the makeup it can get!
这张脸需要浓妆艳抹！
Junge Dame.
Young lady.
小姐。
In welcher Klasse bist du?
What grade are you in?
你几年级？
Achte.
Eighth.
第八。
Assistent!
Assistant!
助手！
Dieses junge Mädchen ist nicht schlecht. Was denkst du?
This young girl isn't bad.
What do you think?
这小姑娘不错啊，你们觉得呢？
Holen Sie sich ihre Adresse.
Get her address.
获取她的地址。
Die Rolle erfordert einen Teenager.
The role calls for a teenager.
这个角色需要一名青少年。
Du gehst auf die 40 zu und hast die Frechheit, zu meckern?
You're pushing 40,
and you have the nerve to bitch?
你已经快 40 岁了，还好意思抱怨？
Hätten Sie Interesse an einem Probeaufnahmentermin?
Would you be interested
in a screen test?
你有兴趣参加试镜吗？
Sie wohnen also auch in der Nähe von Little Park?
So you live
by Little Park too?
那么你也住在小公园附近吗？
Viele meiner Klassenkameraden leben dort.
Lots of my classmates
live there.
我的许多同学都住在那里。
Wirst du den Probeauftritt machen?
You gonna do the screen test?
你要参加试镜吗？
Mein Freund wird wütend sein, wenn er es herausfindet.
My boyfriend will be angry
if he finds out.
如果我的男朋友知道了一定会生气的。
Gehst du zurück zum Unterricht?
You going back to class?
你要回课堂吗？
Wohin können wir sonst gehen?
Where else can we go?
我们还能去哪里？
Woher kennen Sie diesen Ort?
How do you know about this place?
您怎么知道这个地方的？
Ich habe hier in der Nähe gewohnt.
I used to live near here.
我曾经住在这附近。
Ich sehe keine Häuser.
I don't see any houses.
我没有看到任何房子。
Wenn ich ein Mann wäre, würde ich gerne zur Armee gehen.
If I were a guy,
I'd love to be in the army.
如果我是男性，我愿意参军。
Warum habt ihr alle Angst vor der Armee?
Why are you guys
all afraid of the army?
你们为什么都怕军队？
Davor haben wir Angst.
We're afraid of that.
我们害怕这个。
Oh, schau mal. Ein Paar.
Oh, look. A couple.
噢，看，一对。
Mit einem unserer Mädchen ausgehen, was?
Dating one of our girls, eh?
和我们的一个女孩约会，嗯？
Das wird Sie etwas kosten, verstehen Sie?
It'll cost you, you hear?
这会让你付出代价，你听见了吗？
- Ignoriere ihn. - Ignoriere mich?
- Ignore him.
- Ignore me?
- 别理他。 - 别理我？
Das würde er nicht wagen!
He wouldn't dare!
他不敢！
Versteckst du deine Uhr oder was?
You hiding your watch
or what?
你把手表藏起来了还是怎么了？
Ich habe keines.
I don't have one.
我没有。
Bist du nicht der Typ mit der leisen Stimme? Soll ich dich durchsuchen?
Aren't you the soft-spoken one!
Want me to search you?
你说话不是轻声细语的吗！要我搜查你吗？
Mieser Stift.
Lousy pen.
糟糕的笔。
Ein Mädchen daten, ohne das nötige Geld zu haben -
Dating a girl
without the dough -
和没钱的女孩约会 -
Nein, nicht! Los geht's!
No, don't! Let's go!
不，别这样！我们走吧！
Schnell! Los geht's, Schwester?!
Hurry! Let's go, Si?!
快点！我们走吧，Si？！
Steig ein. Ich nehme dich mit.
Get on.
I'll give you a ride.
上车，我载你一程。
Das ist ein Umweg. Weiter vorne kommt ein Bus.
It's out of your way.
There's a bus up ahead.
这不碍事。前面有公交车。
Ich bin auch auf dem Weg zum Little Park!
I'm heading for Little Park too!
我也要去小公园！
Möchten Sie nicht zurückgewinnen, was Sie verloren haben?
Don't you want to win back
what you lost?
难道你不想把你失去的东西赢回来吗？
Du hast eine tolle Einstellung! Ich werde sie behalten.
You've got some attitude!
I'll keep it myself.
你很有态度！我会保持这种态度。
Lass mich in ruhe!
Leave me alone!
请别打扰我！
Threads, wo warst du?
Threads, where you been?
线程，你去哪儿了？
Es ist so dunkel hier. Wie wär’s, wenn du das Licht anmachst?
It's so dark in here.
How about turning on some lights?
这里太暗了。开点灯怎么样？
Sie schulden 2.140.
You owe 2,140.
你欠 2,140。
Möchten Sie jetzt bezahlen oder versuchen, es zurückzugewinnen?
Wanna pay up now
or try to win it back?
想立即付款还是尝试赢回？
Natürlich zurückgewinnen.
Win it back, of course.
当然是赢回来。
Verrückt, wie wäre es, wenn wir ihm eine Chance geben?
Crazy, how about letting him
have a shot?
疯了，让他试一试怎么样？
Dieser Bücherwurm?
That bookworm?
那个书呆子？
Wow, von der Jianguo High!
Wow, from Jianguo High!
哇，来自建国中学！
Angst, dass Sie verlieren?
Scared you'll lose?
害怕会输吗？
Stapeln Sie sie.
Rack 'em up.
把它们架起来。
Das ist es. Lassen Sie ihn aus Erfahrung lernen.
That's it.
Let him learn from experience.
就这样吧，让他吸取经验教训吧。
Lao Er, lass es uns tun. – Warte eine Minute.
Lao Er, let's do it.
- Wait a minute.
老二，咱们也得这么做。——等一下。
Lao Er? "Stechen"?
Lao Er? “Prick”?
老二？ “刺”？
Hast du noch keins?
Haven't you got one already?
你不是已经有一个了吗？
Das hier ist für dich.
This one's for you.
这个是给你的。
Lass dich von ihm nicht stören.
Don't let him bother you.
别让他打扰你。
Glatzkopf, dieser Junge heißt Prick.
Baldy, this kid's called Prick.
秃头，这孩子叫混蛋。
Was ist los? - Nichts.
What's wrong?
- Nothing.
有什么问题吗？ - 没什么。
Nichts? Du siehst beschissen aus.
Nothing?
You look like shit.
没什么？你看起来糟透了。
Was hast du in letzter Zeit gemacht?
What have you
been up to lately?
最近在忙些什么呢？
Nicht viel. Es war hart.
Not much.
Things have been tough.
没什么。情况很艰难。
Ich habe gehört, Sie geben ein Konzert.
I hear
you're putting on a concert.
我听说你要举办一场音乐会。
Damit lässt sich kein Geld verdienen. Nicht wie mit Ihrem Schwindel hier.
There's no money in that.
Not like your racket here.
那样做赚不了钱。不像你们这里的骗局。
Hast du wieder was mit diesen Rock'n'Roll-Jungs am Laufen?
Got something going
with those rock and roll boys again?
那些摇滚男孩又有什么新动向吗？
Das ist so ziemlich alles, was sie zu bieten haben.
That's about all
they've got going.
这就是他们所要做的全部事情了。
Nicht schon wieder diese Jungs aus Little Park!
Not those Little Park boys again!
不再是那些小公园男孩了！
Fünf Bälle, Seitentasche.
Five ball, side pocket.
五个球，侧袋。
Siebener, Ecktasche.
Seven ball, corner pocket.
七号球，角袋。
Viererball, Ecktasche.
Four ball, corner pocket.
四球，角袋。
Was für ein Glücksfall! Der Junge hat einfach Glück!
What a fluke!
The kid's got all the luck!
太幸运了！这孩子真是太幸运了！
Verdammt! Stell sie auf.
Damn! Set 'em up.
该死！设下陷阱。
Komm, mach sie fertig.
Come on, set 'em up.
来吧，把它们设置好。
Ihr seid nicht so streng mit uns.
You guys are going easy on us.
你们对我们太宽容了。
Nehmen Sie sich Zeit. Wir gewinnen alles zurück.
Take your time.
We'll win it all back.
慢慢来。我们会赢回一切的。
Bleib ruhig.
Keep your cool.
保持冷静。
Nehmen Sie sich Zeit. Lassen Sie es ruhig angehen.
Take your time.
Take it easy.
慢慢来，放松点。
Jede Menge Zeit. Zweihundert pro Spiel.
Plenty of time.
Two hundred a game.
时间充足。每场比赛两百美元。
Interessant... interessant.
Interesting... interesting.
有趣...有趣。
Hast du nicht den Unterricht geschwänzt, um nach Hause zu gehen?
Didn't you ditch class to go home?
你不是逃课回家了吗？
Ja, aber ich bin nicht nach Hause gegangen.
Yeah, but I didn't go home.
是啊，不过我没回家。
Komm und hilf mir dabei.
Come help me with this.
来帮我做这件事。
Für wen zum Teufel hältst du mich?
Who the fuck you take me for?
你他妈把我当成谁了？
Misch dich verdammt nochmal nicht in meine Angelegenheiten ein!
Stay the hell out of my business!
别管我的事！
Mein Alter ist für den Zuschauerraum zuständig.
My old man's in charge
of the auditorium.
我老爸是礼堂的负责人。
Wir teilen uns den Erlös des Konzerts.
We share the profits
from the concert.
我们分享音乐会的利润。
Warum sollte Threads so stark gekürzt werden?
Why give Threads
such a big cut?
为什么要给 Threads 这么大的分成？
- Threads ist hier, um zu helfen! - Wie helfen?
- Threads is here to help!
- Help how?
- Threads 在此为您提供帮助！ - 如何提供帮助？
Er nutzt unsere Bande aus.
He's taking advantage
of our gang.
他正在利用我们团伙。
Lassen Sie mich Ihnen etwas sagen.
Let me tell you something.
让我告诉你一些事情。
Ich werde ihm sagen, dass er die Halle nicht benutzen darf.
I'm gonna tell him
he can't use the hall.
我要告诉他他不能使用大厅。
Die Frage ist: Würden Sie aufhören zu singen?
The question is:
Would you stop singing?
问题是：你会停止唱歌吗？
Was zum Teufel sagst du?
What the fuck are you saying?
你他妈在说什么？
Lass mich gehen!
Let me go!
放开我！
Lass ihn gehen. Es ist cool.
Let him go. it's cool.
放他走吧。没关系。
Fick dich, Mann!
Fuck you, man!
去你丫的！哥们！
Was zum Teufel sagst du?
What the fuck are you saying?
你他妈在说什么？
Jade, das geht dich nichts an! Raus hier!
Jade, it's none
of your business! Get out!
杰德，这不关你的事！滚出去！
Lass mich gehen!
Let me go!
放开我！
Diesmal bist du zu weit gegangen!
You've gone too far this time!
这次你太过分了！
Wichser!
Motherfucker!
混蛋！
Gehen Sie nicht hinein.
Don't go inside.
不要进去。
Du hast angefangen. - Ich?
You started it.
- Me?
是你先开始的。- 我？
Sie sagten, Sie hätten Jade in dieser Nacht mit Sly gesehen.
You said you saw Jade
with Sly that night.
你说那天晚上你看到 Jade 和 Sly 在一起。
Jetzt ist die Kacke am Dampfen.
Now the shit's hit the fan.
现在事情变得糟糕透了。
- Ich habe nicht gesagt, dass es Jade ist. - Wer sonst sollte es sein?
- I didn't say it was Jade.
- Who else would it be?
- 我没说是 Jade。- 还能是谁？
Mein kostbares kleines Baby!
My precious little baby!
我珍贵的小宝贝！
Ich werde dich mit einem Bissen verschlingen!
I'll swallow you up in one bite!
我要一口把你吞掉！
Blind Man ist schon eifersüchtig auf dich.
Blind Man's jealous
of you already.
盲人已经嫉妒你了。
Wenn Honey hier wäre,
If Honey were here,
如果 Honey 在这里，
nichts davon wäre passiert.
none of this
would have happened.
这一切都不会发生。
Threads würde es nicht wagen, uns zu unterschätzen.
Threads wouldn't dare
underestimate us.
斯雷德斯不敢低估我们。
Jetzt wollen sowohl Deuce als auch Sly der Boss sein.
Now both Deuce and Sly
want to be boss.
现在 Deuce 和 Sly 都想当老板。
Katze, du bist dran!
Cat, you're on!
猫，你上场了！
Und jetzt?
Now what?
现在该怎么办？
Warum hast du gesagt, ich sei in dieser Nacht mit Sly zusammen gewesen?
Why did you say
I was with Sly that night?
你为什么说那天晚上我和 Sly 在一起？
Ich habe nicht gesagt, dass du es warst. Ich konnte nicht klar sehen.
I didn't say it was you.
I couldn't see clearly.
我又没说是你，我看不清楚。
Warst du es nicht?
Wasn't it you?
难道不是你吗？
Ja, das war es.
Yeah... it was.
是的...确实如此。
Entschuldigung! Das habe ich nicht so gemeint! Ich dachte, niemand wäre zu Hause!
Sorry! I didn't mean it!
I thought no one was home!
对不起！我不是故意的！我以为没人在家！
Kleiner Dieb! Wenn etwas gestohlen wird, suchen wir dich!
Little thief! If anything's stolen,
we'll come looking for you!
小偷！如果有东西被偷了，我们会来找你！
Wo ist Sir? - Ich schätze, er ist draußen.
Where's Si'r?
- I guess he's out.
Si'r 在哪儿？ - 我猜他出去了。
Was machst du hier?
What are you doing here?
你在这里干什么？
Bitte deine große Schwester, ein paar Liedtexte für mich zu transkribieren, okay?
Ask your big sister to transcribe
some lyrics for me, okay?
让你姐姐帮我抄写一下歌词好吗？
Schwesterherz, kannst du ihm helfen?
Sis, can you help him?
姐姐，你能帮助他吗？
Erneut Songtexte transkribieren?
Transcribing lyrics again?
又抄录歌词了？
Sie möchten amerikanische Lieder singen, obwohl Sie kein Wort Englisch können!
You want to sing American songs
when you don't know a word of English!
你一个英语单词都不懂，你却想唱美国歌！
Sei nicht böse. Ich habe nicht absichtlich geschaut.
Don't be mad.
I didn't look on purpose.
别生气。我不是故意看的。
Ich habe nichts gesehen.
I didn't see anything.
我什么也没看见。
Aber ich muss sagen, das Kleid sieht toll aus!
But I gotta say
that dress looks great!
但我不得不说那件衣服看起来很棒！
Ich habe nicht viel Zeit.
I don't have a lot of time.
我没有很多时间。
Sie ist darauf hereingefallen.
She fell for it.
她上当了。
Dein süßes Gerede hat wieder funktioniert.
Your sweet talk worked again.
你的甜言蜜语又起作用了。
Schwester, ich habe meine Brotdose vergessen. Morn sagt, du sollst sie mir aufwärmen.
Sis, I forgot my lunch box.
Morn says to reheat it for me.
姐姐，我忘了带饭盒了。妈妈让我再热一下。
Wo ist Morn?
Where's Morn?
莫恩在哪儿？
Aufsicht bei einer Prüfung.
Supervising an exam.
监督考试。
Wow, ein neues Kleid!
Wow, a new dress!
哇，一件新衣服！
Das ist seltsam.
That's strange.
这很奇怪。
Hast du es eingesteckt?
Did you plug it in?
您插上电源了吗？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Verdammt.
Damn it.
该死的。
Es funktioniert nicht.
It's not working.
它不起作用。
Was nun?
What now?
现在怎么办？
Ich weiß. Bring mir dein Radio.
I know.
Bring me your radio.
我知道。把你的收音机拿给我。
Wow, das hast du kopiert!
Wow, you copied this one!
哇，你抄袭了这个！
- Was machst du? - Nichts. Ich repariere es nur.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing. Just fixing it.
- 你在做什么？ - 没什么。只是在修理它。
- Ich gehe! - Ohne dein Mittagessen?
- I'm going!
- Without your lunch?
- 我要走了！ - 没带午饭？
Geben Sie Ihr Taschengeld nicht für Junkfood aus!
Don't spend your pocket money
on junk food!
不要把你的零花钱花在垃圾食品上！
Lass es dauern!
Make it last!
让它持久！
Wird das funktionieren?
Will this work?
这能行吗？
Nichts kleineres?
Nothing smaller?
没有更小的吗？
Sir, wollt ihr Jungs zu Mittag essen?
Si'r, you boys want lunch?
先生，你们要吃午饭吗？
- Nicht jetzt. - Ich habe gegessen.
- Not right now.
- I ate.
- 现在不行。 - 我吃饭了。
- Warum funktioniert es nicht? - Es sollte funktionieren.
- Why isn't it working?
- It should be.
- 为什么它不起作用？ - 它应该起作用。
Sicher, dass du es wieder zusammengebaut hast, oder?
Sure you put it
back together right?
你确定它能重新组装起来吗？
Sei nicht dumm. Ich habe alles nummeriert.
Don't be stupid.
I numbered everything.
别傻了。我把所有东西都编号了。
Du hast es vermasselt.
You fucked it up.
你把事情搞砸了。
Bleib cool, Mann.
Stay cool, man.
保持冷静，老兄。
Sehen?
See?
看？
Du Scheißkerl. Ich such dir was Neues.
Piece of shit.
I'll find you a new one.
真是个废物。我给你找个新的吧。
Hast du Geld?
Got any money?
有钱吗？
Wann hatte ich jemals Geld?
When have I ever had money?
我什么时候有过钱？
_' Und du? ' T'Y'"9, um mich abzuzocken?
_' And you?
' T'Y'"9 to rip me off?
_' 那你呢？' 你''9 想骗我吗？
Komm. Geh rein und hol dir etwas.
Come on.
Go inside and get some.
来吧。进去拿点吧。
Siehst du das?
You see that?
你看到了嗎？
Was?
What?
什么？
Mein Alter ist drinnen.
My old man's inside.
我老爸在里面。
Was für ein Tag, Mann.
What a day, man.
多么糟糕的一天啊，哥们。
Tiger.
老虎。
Was ist mit Mings verletztem Bein los?
What's the deal
with Ming's injured leg?
明的腿受伤了，怎么回事？
Ich habe gehört, es kommt vom Basketballspielen mit dir.
I heard it was from
playing basketball with you.
我听说是和你一起打篮球的时候。
Komm, lass uns woanders reden.
Come on.
Let's talk somewhere else.
来吧，我们换个地方聊吧。
Warum können wir hier nicht reden?
Why can't we talk here?
我们为什么不能在这里谈话？
Wenn wir hier reden,
If we talk here,
如果我们在这里谈话，
es wird nicht gut für Sie aussehen.
it won't look good for you.
这对你来说不太好。
Interessant. Sag mir, was nicht gut aussehen wird.
Interesting.
Tell me what won't look good.
有趣。告诉我什么看起来不太好。
Sie sollten sich darüber im Klaren sein, wessen Mädchen Ming ist.
You should be clear
about whose girl Ming is.
你应该清楚，明是谁家的女孩。
- Mir geht es gut.
- I am.
- Good.
- 我很好。
Wenn Honey es herausfände, wäre er nicht erfreut.
If Honey found out,
he wouldn't be pleased.
如果霍妮知道了，他会不高兴的。
Meine Aufgabe ist es, dafür zu sorgen, dass er es nicht herausfindet.
My job is to make sure
he doesn't find out.
我的工作是确保他不会发现。
Er wird es nicht herausfinden.
He won't find out.
他不会发现的。
Das sollte er besser nicht.
He better not.
他最好不要。
Behalten Sie das im Hinterkopf.
Keep that in mind.
记住这一点。
Hey, ich bin noch nicht fertig mit dir.
Hey, I'm not done with you.
嘿，我还没跟你算完。
Was ist die große Idee?
What's the big idea?
有什么好主意？
Was machst du?
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Das ist zwischen ihm und mir.
This is between him and me.
这是我和他之间的事。
Ihr seid beide Klassenkameraden. Warum die ganze Aufregung?
You two are classmates.
Why all the fuss?
你们两个是同学，干嘛这么大惊小怪？
Fick dich!
Fuck you!
去你的！
- Das bleibt zwischen ihm und mir. - Und Ming!
- This is between him and me.
- And Ming!
- 这是我和他之间的事。 - 还有明！
Geht er nicht auch mit Ming aus?
Isn't he going out with Ming too?
他不是也和 Ming 一起出去吗？
Jemand hat sie in dieser Nacht in einem Klassenzimmer gesehen.
Someone saw them
in a classroom that night.
那天晚上有人在教室里看到了他们。
Sagen Sie uns, was los ist.
Tell us what's wrong.
告诉我们出了什么问题。
Erzählen Sie es uns. Wir möchten es wissen.
Tell us.
We want to know.
告诉我们。我们想知道。
Erzähl es deiner Little Park-Gang.
Go tell your Little Park gang.
去告诉你的小公园帮派。
Ich kenne Honey seit Jahren.
I've known Honey for years.
我认识 Honey 很多年了。
Ich nehme es jederzeit mit euch allen Weicheiern auf!
I'll take all you sissies on
anytime!
我随时都会接受你们这些胆小鬼！
Und jetzt geh zurück in den Unterricht.
Now get back to class.
现在回课堂。
Geh zurück in den Unterricht!
Get back to class!
回课堂去！
Mama, leih mir deine Ohrringe und deine Uhr.
Mom, let me borrow
your earrings and watch.
妈妈，让我借一下你的耳环和手表。
Sicher, aber seien Sie mit der Uhr besonders vorsichtig.
Sure, but be extra careful
with the watch.
当然，但是要格外小心手表。
Wie kommt es, dass nur noch 800 NT$ übrig sind?
How come
there's only NT$8OO left?
怎么就剩下800元了？
Ich habe unsere Rechnung bei Onkel Fat bezahlt
I paid our tab at Uncle Fat's
我在胖叔叔家付了账
damit er beim nächsten Kauf auf Kredit nicht meckert.
so he won't squawk
next time we buy on credit.
这样我们下次赊购时他就不会吵闹了。
Wang hat Ihnen eine Beförderung verschafft
Wang got you a promotion
王帮你升职了
aber keine Gehaltserhöhung.
but not a raise in pay.
但工资却没有加薪。
Was ist los?
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Nichts.
Nothing.
没有什么。
Was ist mit dem Radio?
What's with the radio?
收音机怎么了？
Was ist los?
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
Ich habe gesehen, wie Si'r es in der Mittagspause auseinandergenommen hat.
I saw Si'r taking it apart
at lunchtime.
午餐的时候我看到四儿在拆它。
Verdammt.
Damn it.
该死的。
Aufstehen.
Stand up.
起来。
Wo ist deine Komposition?
Where's your composition?
你的作文在哪儿？
Du bist der Einzige, der keins abgegeben hat.
You're the only one
who didn't hand one in.
你是唯一一个没有交作业的人。
Verzeihung.
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Das ist Ma, unsere neue Austauschschülerin.
This is Ma,
our new transfer student.
这是我们新转来的学生马。
Heißen wir ihn willkommen.
Let's welcome him.
让我们欢迎他。
Wie ich schon sagte,
As I was saying,
正如我所说，
Chinesische Schriftzeichen offenbaren eine große Logik.
Chinese characters
reveal a great logic.
汉字蕴含着伟大的逻辑。
Fremdsprachen sind da nicht vergleichbar.
Foreign languages
can't compare.
外语无法相比。
Sechsundzwanzig Buchstaben gemischt und angepasst – das ist alles.
Twenty-six letters
mixed and matched - that's all.
二十六封字母混合搭配——就这样。
Eintönig und langweilig.
Monotonous and tedious.
单调、乏味。
Nehmen Sie das Schriftzeichen „Shan“, das „Berg“ bedeutet.
Take the character shan,
meaning “mountain.”
以“shan”这个字为例，它的意思是“山”。
Buchstabieren Sie es für mich auf Englisch.
Spell it in English for me.
用英语拼写给我听。
Wie langweilig!
How tedious!
多么乏味啊！
Er ist der Typ, der an der Banqiao High jemanden niedergestochen hat.
He's the guy who knifed someone
at Banqiao High.
他就是在板桥中学持刀伤人的那个人。
Wang Mao, steh auf.
Wang Mao, stand up.
王茂，站起来。
Sie haben noch etwas hinzuzufügen?
You have something to add?
您还有什么要补充吗？
NEIN.
No.
不。
Worüber haben Sie dann gesprochen?
Then what
were you discussing?
那你们在讨论什么？
Sir, was ist mit „ich“?
Sir, what about “I”?
先生，那“我”呢？
Was meinst du, was ist mit dir?
What do you mean,
what about you?
你是什​​么意思，你怎么样？
Nein, ich meine, was ist nach dem, was Sie gesagt haben, mit dem Zeichen für „ich“?
No, I mean from what you said,
what about the character for “I”?
不，我的意思是从你所说的来看，“我”这个字怎么样？
Komm herauf.
Come up here.
上来。
Kommen Sie nach vorne.
Come up front.
到前面来。
Sie wissen, dass das Zeichen W0 bedeutet
You know
the character W0 means
你知道字符 W0 意味着
- Ja. - Dann schreib es.
- Yeah.
- Then write it.
- 是的 - 那就写吧。
Sie mögen dieses Wort, nicht wahr?
You're fond of that word,
aren't you?
你喜欢这个词，不是吗？
Schreib es hundertmal.
Write it a hundred times.
写一百遍。
Mach weiter!
Go on!
继续！
Es scheint Ihnen Spaß zu machen.
You seem to enjoy it.
你看上去很喜欢它。
Schreiben Sie weiter!
Keep writing!
继续写！
Das sind zwei. Gut.
That's two. Good.
一共两个。很好。
Weitermachen.
Keep going.
继续前进。
Wer zischt da?
Who's hissing?
谁在发出嘶嘶声？
Zhang Zhen, steh auf.
Zhang Zhen, stand up.
张震，站起来。
Wer hat mich angezischt? Sprich lauter.
Who hissed at me?
Speak up.
谁对我发出嘘声？大声说出来。
Ich weiß nicht.
I don't know.
我不知道。
Wen haben Sie dann angeschaut?
Then who were you looking at?
那你当时在看谁？
Wer war es?
Who was it?
那是谁？
Ich habe niemanden gesehen.
I didn't see anyone.
我没有看见任何人。
Bußgeld.
Fine.
美好的。
Wenn Sie es nicht sagen wollen: Sie waren es.
If you won't say, it was you.
如果你不说，那就是你。
Bleib stehen.
Stay standing.
保持站立。
Blättern wir zu Seite 33.
Let's turn to page 33.
我们翻到第33页。
Das ist 8/ 'r./
Mao 8/ 'r./
那是 8/'r./
Xiao Sir!
Xiao Si'r!
- Hast du Pornos? - Ja.
- You got any porn?
- Yes.
- 你有色情内容吗？ - 是的。
Xiao Sir!
Xiao Si'r!
- Hast du mich nicht rufen gehört? - Nein.
- Didn't you hear me calling?
- No.
- 你没听见我的呼唤吗？ - 没有。
Morgen ist der Probevorstellungstermin. Willst du mitkommen?
The screen test is tomorrow.
Wanna come?
明天试镜。要来吗？
Sicher.
Sure.
当然。
Was ist los?
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Nichts.
Nothing.
没有什么。
Sie schienen Angst zu haben, mich zu sehen.
You seemed scared to see me.
你看上去很害怕见到我。
Hast du Angst, dass man uns zusammen sieht?
You afraid
we'll be seen together?
你怕别人看见我们在一起吗？
Boah, auf einem Date, was?
Whoa, out on a date, huh?
哇哦，出去约会了，嗯？
Komm, lass uns hier nicht reden.
Come on.
Let's not talk here.
得了，别在这里说话了。
- Gib mir den Porno. - Hier.
- Let me have that porn.
- Here.
- 让我看看那个色情片。 - 给。
Ich dachte, deinem Freund würde es nicht gefallen, wenn du an der Probeaufnahme teilnehmen würdest.
I thought your boyfriend wouldn't like it
if you took the screen test.
我认为你的男朋友不会喜欢你去试镜。
Hast du deshalb Angst, mit mir gesehen zu werden?
Is that why you're afraid
of being seen with me?
这就是你害怕被人看见和我在一起的原因吗？
Ich will einfach keinen Ärger.
I just don't want any trouble.
我只是不想惹麻烦。
Ich weiß, dass Honey dein Freund ist.
I know Honey
is your boyfriend.
我知道 Honey 是你的男朋友。
Du willst immer noch nicht zugeben, dass du Angst vor mir hast?
You still won't admit
you're afraid of me?
你还是不肯承认你怕我吗？
Du bist lustig.
You're funny.
你真有趣。
Worüber lachst du?
What are you laughing at?
你笑什么？
Sie sind so ehrenhaft. Das wird Ihnen Ärger einbringen.
You're so honorable.
It'll get you in trouble.
你太诚实了。这会给你带来麻烦的。
Warum?
Why?
为什么？
Honey ist wie du.
Honey's like you.
亲爱的就像你一样。
Alle haben Angst vor ihm,
Everyone's scared of him,
大家都怕他，
aber sie merken nicht, dass er heterosexuell ist.
but they don't realize
he's straight as an arrow.
但他们没有意识到他是个直男。
Er kann Dinge nicht ertragen, die unfair sind.
He can't stand things
that are unfair.
他无法忍受不公平的事情。
Er nimmt es auf sich, die Dinge in Ordnung zu bringen.
He takes it on himself
to straighten things out.
他主动承担起解决一切问题的责任。
Ich versuchte ihn zu überzeugen
I tried to convince him
我试图说服他
dass er die Welt nicht alleine verändern kann.
that he can't change
the world by himself.
他无法独自改变世界。
Er würde mit mir streiten
He'd argue with me
他会和我争论
und geben Sie mir die Schuld, weil ich ihn entmutigt habe.
and blame me
for discouraging him.
并责怪我打击了他。
Aber jetzt, da er weg ist,
But now that he's gone,
但现在他已经走了，
Ich vermisse ihn so sehr.
I miss him so much.
我非常想念他。
Ich weine und weine einfach.
I just cry and cry.
我只是不断哭泣。
Ich habe gehört, es lag an dir
I heard
it was because of you
我听说是因为你
dass Honey Redhead, den ehemaligen Chef von 217, getötet hat,
that Honey killed Redhead,
the former 217 boss,
哈妮杀死了 217 的前老板红发
und begab sich dann auf die Flucht.
and then went on the run.
然后就开始逃亡。
Stimmt das?
Is that true?
这是真的吗？
Kommst du morgen zu meinem Probeauftritt?
Will you come watch
my screen test tomorrow?
明天你会来看我的试镜吗？
Wenn ich komme, werde ich dort oben sein.
If I come, I'll be up there.
如果我来的话，我就会在那里。
Wirst du es tun?
You gonna do it?
你会这么做吗？
Es gibt einen Ort des Friedens und der Ruhe
There is a place
of peace and calm
有一个和平与安宁的地方
Sind Sie sicher, dass Ihr wöchentlicher Bibelunterricht und Chor
Are you sure your weekly
Bible class and choir
你确定你的每周圣经课和合唱团
wird sich das nicht auf Ihre Schulnoten auswirken?
won't affect
your grades at school?
不会影响你的学习成绩吗？
Hattest du eine schöne Zeit?
Did you have a good time?
你玩得开心嗎？
Vorsichtig!
Careful!
小心！
Dein Vater und ich haben uns bei einem Tanz in Shanghai kennengelernt.
Your father and I met
at a dance back in Shanghai.
你父亲和我是在上海的一次舞会上认识的。
Wir Mädchen am Lehrerseminar waren sehr verwestlicht.
We girls at the Teachers College
were very westernized.
我们师范学院的女生非常西化。
Wer hätte gedacht, dass ich diesem Bauernjungen begegnen würde?
Who'd have dreamed
I'd meet this peasant boy?
谁会想到我会遇见这个农家小子？
Er war gerade aus Guangzhou in Shanghai angekommen.
He'd just arrived in Shanghai
from Guangzhou.
他刚从广州飞抵上海。
Zum Glück führte Wang ihn herum und zeigte ihm die reale Welt.
Luckily Wang took him around
and showed him the real world.
幸运的是，王带他四处走走，让他见识了真实的世界。
Er war ein echter Bauernjunge.
He was a real peasant boy.
他是一个地地道道的农家子弟。
Viele Mädchen mochten ihn und er wusste es nicht einmal.
Lots of girls liked him,
and he didn't even know it.
很多女孩喜欢他，但他却不知道。
Ich fand ihn wirklich etwas Besonderes.
I thought he was real special.
我认为他真的很特别。
S?r.
S? r.
是。
Komm mit mir.
Come with me.
跟我来。
Was ist los?
What's the matter?
怎么了？
- Wo ist die Uhr? - Welche Uhr?
- Where's the watch?
- What watch?
- 手表在哪儿？ - 什么手表？
Mamas Uhr. Hat Cat sie gestohlen?
Mom's watch.
Did Cat steal it?
妈妈的手表。猫偷了它吗？
Unmöglich!
Impossible!
不可能的！
Ich hatte es mittags, aber heute Abend war es weg.
I had it at lunchtime,
but tonight it was gone.
我午餐时吃过它，但是今晚它就消失了。
War er heute Nachmittag nicht hier?
Wasn't he here this afternoon?
他今天下午不是来了吗？
Ich habe es genommen.
I took it.
我接手了。
Was? Was ist in dich gefahren? Warum?
What?
What got into you? Why?
怎么了？你怎么了？为什么？
Ich schulde jemandem Geld.
I owe someone money.
我欠别人钱。
Sind Sie jemandem Geld schuldig?
Owe someone money?
欠人钱吗？
Wie viel? - Vierhundert.
How much?
- Four hundred.
多少钱？ - 四百。
Du hast es verpfändet, nicht wahr?
You pawned it, didn't you?
你把它典当了，不是吗？
Ich schwöre, du wirst mein Ende sein!
I swear,
you'll be the end of me!
我发誓，你会让我完蛋的！
Mama wird dir die Haut abziehen, wenn sie es herausfindet!
Mom will skin you alive
if she finds out!
如果妈妈发现了，她会活剥你的皮的！
Wie kommt es, dass Sie so viel schulden?
How come you owed so much?
你怎么欠了这么多？
Threads nahm mich mit zum Billardspielen mit den Village Boys.
Threads took me to shoot pool
with the Village boys.
特雷斯带我去与村里的男孩们一起打台球。
Wir haben viel verloren.
We lost big.
我们损失惨重。
Jetzt legt er sich mit den Jungs von Little Park an.
Now he's messing
with the Little Park boys.
现在他正在和小公园里的男孩们混在一起。
Ich muss sauber raus, bevor die Hölle losbricht.
I gotta get out clean
before all hell breaks loose.
我必须在一切崩溃之前全身而退。
Morn trägt die Uhr sowieso nie.
Morn never wears
the watch anyway.
无论如何，莫恩从来不戴这块手表。
Hier.
Here.
这里。
Holen Sie die Uhr zurück.
Go get the watch back.
去把手表拿回来。
Ich sage, ich habe Sie geschickt, um ein paar Sprachbücher zu holen.
I'll say I sent you
for some language books.
我会说我派你去取一些语言书籍。
Denken Sie unbedingt daran, eines mitzubringen.
Be sure you bring one back.
请务必带一个回来。
Frau Fang!
Mrs. Fang!
方太太！
Hat sie schon lange Asthma?
Has she had asthma long?
她患哮喘很久了吗？
Sie hatte schon früher Anfälle, aber noch nie so schwere.
She's had attacks before,
but never this serious.
她以前也曾遭受过袭击，但从未如此严重。
Die meisten Asthmamedikamente wirken bei ihr nicht mehr.
Most asthma medication
is no longer effective on her.
大多数哮喘药物对她不再有效。
Bei Wetterumschwüngen muss sie besonders vorsichtig sein.
She must be especially careful
when the weather changes.
天气变化时她必须特别小心。
Lassen Sie sie nicht an unbelüfteten Orten sein
Don't let her be
in unventilated places
不要让她待在不通风的地方
oder zu müde werden.
or get too tired.
或者太累了。
Ist das nicht Ihre Adresse?
Isn't this your address?
这不是你的地址吗？
Sie leben bei mir.
They live with me.
他们和我住在一起。
Es ist so viel?
It's that much?
就那么多？
Könnten Sie mir nicht einen kleinen Rabatt geben?
Couldn't you give me
a little discount?
你不能给我一点折扣吗？
Ihre Tochter sagte, sie kennt Sie.
Her daughter said
she knows you.
她的女儿说她认识你。
Deshalb habe ich sie hierher gebracht.
That's why I brought her here.
这就是我带她来这里的原因。
Sie haben ihre Tochter schon einmal behandelt, richtig?
You've treated
her daughter before, right?
您之前曾治疗过她的女儿，对吗？
Nun ja.
Well... yes.
嗯...是的。
Aber ich kann solche Entscheidungen nicht treffen.
But I can't make
decisions like this.
但我无法做出这样的决定。
Denkst du an etwas Trauriges?
Are you thinking
about something sad?
你在想一些悲伤的事吗？
Kannst du mir davon erzählen?
Can you tell me about it?
你能告诉我吗？
Vielleicht wissen Sie nicht, wo Sie anfangen sollen.
Maybe you don't know
where to start.
也许您不知道从哪里开始。
Kannst du es mir jetzt sagen?
Can you tell me now?
你现在可以告诉我吗？
Okay-
okay-
好的-
Nicht schlecht. Sehr gut.
Not bad. Very good.
还不错，非常好。
Was nun, Sir?
What now, sir?
先生，现在怎么办？
Versuchen wir es mit einem historischen Kostüm.
Let's try a historical costume.
我们来尝试一下历史服装吧。
Bist du sicher?
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
In Ordnung.
All right.
好的。
Sir, die Chefin ist da!
Sir, the boss lady's here!
先生，老板娘来了！
Was höre ich da über meine Hauptdarstellerin?
What's this I hear
about my leading lady?
我听到了有关我的女主角的什么消息？
Die Rolle erfordert einen Teenager,
The part calls for a teenager,
这个角色需要一个青少年，
also haben wir einen Teenager bekommen.
so we got a teenager.
所以我们就得到了一个青少年。
Können Sie den Kassenerfolg garantieren?
Can you guarantee
the box office?
你能保证票房吗？
Nun ja, die Zeiten sind hart …
Well, times are hard...
嗯，时局艰难……
es ist ganz offensichtlich.
it's very obvious.
这是非常明显的。
Sie beide haben genau die gleichen Fehler gemacht.
You two made
the exact same mistakes.
你们两个犯了完全相同的错误。
Ich habe ihn nicht abschreiben lassen. Er hat es einfach gemacht.
I didn't let him copy.
He just did.
我没让他抄袭，他自己就抄了。
Wen willst du täuschen? Genau dieselben Fehler.
Who are you trying to fool?
The exact same mistakes.
你想愚弄谁？一模一样的错误。
Kein Wort mehr und kein Wort weniger.
Not one word more
or one word less.
一个字也不能多，一个字也不能少。
Tadel für euch beide.
Demerits for both of you.
你们俩都有缺点。
Ich habe absichtlich Fehler gemacht und er hat sie kopiert.
I made mistakes on purpose,
and he copied them.
我故意犯错误，他就抄袭。
Traust du dich noch, zu widersprechen?
You still dare to talk back?
你還敢嗎？
Ich habe nichts falsch gemacht.
I didn't do anything wrong.
我没有做错什么。
So sprechen Sie mit einem Lehrer?
You speak
to a teacher like that?
你这样跟老师说话吗？
Ich habe nichts falsch gemacht.
I didn't do anything wrong.
我没有做错什么。
Widersprechen Sie weiter. Das bringt Ihnen einen weiteren Tadel ein!
Keep talking back.
It'll get you another demerit!
继续顶嘴。你会再被扣分一次！
Warum?
Why?
为什么？
Wer widerspricht einem Lehrer so?
Who's talking back
to a teacher like that?
谁会这样跟老师顶嘴？
Ihr zwei schon wieder!
You two again!
又是你们两个！
Wir haben unsere Vorschriften. Mir sind die Hände gebunden.
We have our regulations.
My hands are tied.
我们有自己的规定。我却束手无策。
Probieren Sie zur Abwechslung diesen neuen Tee.
Try this new tea for a change.
尝试一下这种新茶来换换口味。
Er war offensichtlich ein Opfer,
He was obviously a victim,
他显然是受害者，
und Sie bestrafen ihn ohne eine Untersuchung.
and you're punishing him
without an investigation.
你们没有经过调查就惩罚他。
Das ist nicht fair!
This isn't fair!
这不公平！
Ich schicke meinen Sohn zu dir,
I send my son to you,
我派我的儿子来见你，
in der Hoffnung, dass er ein anständiger, ehrlicher Mensch wird.
hoping he'll become
a decent, honest person.
希望他能成为一个正派、诚实的人。
Wenn er Fehler macht, hoffe ich, dass Sie ihn korrigieren.
If he makes mistakes,
I hope you'll correct him.
如果他犯了错误，我希望你能纠正他。
Aber wenn Sie sich so verhalten -
But when you act like this -
但当你这样做的时候——
es ist einfach nicht fair!
it's just not fair!
这不公平！
Was ist das? Lao Fan!
What is this? Lao Fan!
这是啥？老范！
Was zur Hölle ist das? - Was ist los?
What the hell is this?
- What's the matter?
这到底是什么情况？ - 发生什么事了？
Das geht Sie nichts an.
None of your business.
关你屁事。
Ihr Sohn hat Glück. Der andere Junge wurde von der Schule verwiesen.
Your son's lucky.
The other boy's been expelled.
你儿子真幸运。另一个男孩被开除了。
Wegen all seiner Verfehlungen! Das ist irrelevant!
Because of all his demerits!
That's irrelevant!
因为他有那么多缺点！那不重要！
Sie halten Ihren Sohn für einen Musterschüler?
You think your son
is a model student?
您认为您的儿子是一名模范学生吗？
Ich habe ihn selbst schon oft geschnappt.
I've nabbed him myself
many times.
我亲自抓过他很多次。
Das hat hiermit nichts zu tun!
That has nothing
to do with this!
这与此无关！
Das ist keine Bildung! Sie schikanieren die guten Schüler!
This isn't education!
You harass the good students!
这不是教育！你欺负好学生！
Reg dich nicht auf.
Don't get excited.
别激动。
Wir haben unsere Vorschriften. Da kann ich nicht helfen.
We have our regulations.
There's no way I can help.
我们有自己的规定。我帮不上什么忙。
Ich bin nicht hier, um Ihnen zu helfen. Ich bin hier, um Gerechtigkeit zu erlangen.
I'm not here for your help.
I'm here for justice.
我来这里不是为了帮助你。我来这里是为了伸张正义。
Ich bin nicht auf der Suche nach persönlichen Gefälligkeiten. Ich brauche Ihre Hilfe nicht.
I'm not looking for personal favors.
I don't need your help.
我不是在寻求个人恩惠。我不需要你的帮助。
Wie können Sie so eine bürokratische Haltung haben?
How can you have
such a bureaucratic attitude?
你怎么会有这么官僚的态度？
Ich kann es nicht glauben!
I can't believe it!
我简直不敢相信！
Es ist meine Schuld.
It's my fault.
这是我的错。
Ich habe die Fassung verloren.
I lost my cool.
我失去了冷静。
Das ist eine schlechte Angewohnheit von mir.
It's a bad habit of mine.
这是我的一个坏习惯。
Ich kann nichts dafür. Wenn ich diese Bürokraten sehe –
I can't help it.
When I see these bureaucrats -
我没办法。当我看到这些官僚时——
Er hat es verdient.
He deserved it.
这是他应得的。
Aber du hast mich wirklich überrascht.
But you really surprised me.
但你确实让我很惊讶。
Das ist nicht das, was Sie lernen sollten.
That's not what
you should be learning.
这不是你应该学的。
Sie können den Tadel auch gleich in Kauf nehmen.
You might as well
take the demerit.
你不妨接受这个过失。
Eine Person, die sich entschuldigt
A person who'll apologize
会道歉的人
für Unrecht, das er nicht begangen hat
for wrongs he didn't commit
因为他没有犯下过错
ist zu allen möglichen schrecklichen Dingen fähig.
is capable of all sorts
of terrible things.
能够做出各种可怕的事情。
Aber so etwas scheint so oft zu passieren.
But that kind of thing
seems to happen so often.
但这种事情似乎经常发生。
Genau.
Exactly.
确切地。
Der Zweck der Bildung ist die Suche nach der Wahrheit des Lebens
The purpose of education
is to search for the truth of life
教育的目的是探寻生命的真理
zu glauben.
to believe in.
相信。
Wenn Sie nicht mutig genug sind, daran zu glauben,
If you can't be brave enough
to believe in it,
如果你没有足够的勇气去相信它，
was ist dann der Sinn des Lebens?
then what's the purpose of life?
那么生命的意义是什么？
Sir, Sie haben Glück.
Si'r, you're lucky.
先生，您很幸运。
Ich hoffe, dieser Vorfall
I hope this incident
我希望这次事件
erweist sich als etwas Positives und nicht als Rückschlag.
proves to be something positive
and not a setback.
事实证明这是积极的事情，而不是挫折。
Sie müssen daran glauben, dass Ihre Zukunft
You must believe that your future
你必须相信你的未来
wird durch Ihre eigene harte Arbeit bestimmt.
is determined
by your own hard work.
是由自己的努力决定的。
Bist du immer noch unglücklich?
You still unhappy?
你还不开心吗？
Darüber, dass ich Ihnen diesen Tadel eingebrockt habe?
About me getting you
this demerit?
关于我给你记这个过失？
Nein, ich mache mir Sorgen darüber, was Mama denken wird.
No, I'm worried
about what Mom will think.
不，我担心妈妈会怎么想。
Ich mache mir Sorgen um dich.
I'm worried for your sake.
我很担心你。
Deine arme Mutter.
Your poor mother.
你可怜的妈妈。
Nach all den Jahren macht sie sich immer noch Sorgen um mich.
All these years,
and she still worries about me.
这么多年了，她还是很担心我。
Erinnern:
Remember:
记住：
Dinge mit einem Loch in der Mitte bereiten Kopfschmerzen.
Things with a hole in the middle
bring headaches.
中间有洞的东西会带来头痛。
Was bedeutet das?
What's that mean?
那是什么意思？
Nichts. Das wirst du herausfinden, wenn du erwachsen bist.
Nothing. You'll find out
when you grow up.
没什么。当你长大了你就会知道。
Was studieren Sie?
What are you studying?
你在学什么？
Ich lerne an einer Paukschule.
I'm studying at a cram school.
我在补习班学习。
Nein, ich meine das Buch. Es ist so dick.
No, I mean the book.
It's so thick.
不，我是说那本书。它太厚了。
Wir alle wissen, dass Ihre Tochter
We all know
that your daughter goes
我们都知道你女儿去了
zum besten College.
to the best college.
考入最好的大学。
Das habe ich nicht gemeint.
I didn't mean that.
我不是那个意思。
Ja, das wette ich.
Yeah, I'll bet.
是的，我敢打赌。
Aber wen interessiert es, wohin sie geht?
But who cares where she goes?
但谁在乎她去哪儿？
Meine Tochter läuft nicht mit Jungs herum
My daughter doesn't go
running around with boys
我女儿不会和男孩们一起跑来跑去
und ihre Hände halten.
and holding their hands.
并握住他们的手。
Warten Sie jetzt eine Sekunde.
Now, wait a second.
现在，等一下。
Wir sind alle Nachbarn. Warum dieser Ton?
We're all neighbors.
Why that tone?
我们都是邻居。为什么是那样的语气？
Genau. Ich sage das zu Ihrem Besten.
Exactly. I'm saying
this for your own good.
没错。我这么说是为了你好。
Verstehen Sie mich nicht falsch.
Don't get me wrong.
别误会我的意思。
Die Kinder von heute sind nicht das, was Sie denken,
Kids nowadays
aren't what you think,
现在的孩子和你想象的不一样，
mit ihren Verabredungen und ihren Straßengangs.
with their dating
and their street gangs.
以及他们的约会和街头帮派。
Nehmen wir ihn zum Beispiel, in der Abendschule und so.
Take him, for example,
at night school and all.
就拿他来说吧，他在夜校等等。
Er muss schwer zu handhaben sein.
He must be tough to handle.
他一定很难对付。
Eine gute Schule ist also nicht alles, oder?
So a good school
isn't everything, is it?
那么，好的学校并不是一切，不是吗？
Finden Sie etwas Besseres, mit dem Sie Ihre Zeit verbringen können!
Find something better to do
with your time!
找一些更好的事情来利用你的时间！
Ich habe also keinen bequemen Job wie Sie.
So I don't have
a cushy job like yours.
所以我没有像你一样轻松的工作。
Ich habe bei der Eisenbahn gearbeitet, wissen Sie!
I worked for the railroads,
you know!
你知道吗，我曾在铁路部门工作过！
Und ich habe selbst gekündigt! Niemand hat mich gefeuert!
And I quit myself!
No one fired me!
我自己辞职了！没人解雇我！
Wenn Sie mit Ihrem Gehalt Besseres anfangen könnten,
If you had better things
to do with your salary,
如果你有更好的办法来利用你的薪水，
du würdest es mir nicht überlassen!
you wouldn't turn it over to me!
你不会把它交给我的！
Ohne meinen Kredit würden Sie verhungern!
Without my credit,
you'd starve!
如果没有我的信任，你会饿死的！
Was ist in dich gefahren, Vater?
What's gotten into you, Father?
父亲，您怎么了？
Sie wollen einen weiteren Herzinfarkt?
You want another heart attack?
你想再一次心脏病发作吗？
- Du hast wieder getrunken. - Kümmere dich um deine eigenen Angelegenheiten!
- You've been drinking again.
- Mind your own business!
- 你又喝酒了。 - 管好你自己的事！
Wenn Menschen verhandeln, entschärfen sie das Problem.
When people negotiate,
they defuse the issue.
当人们谈判时，他们会化解问题。
Am Ende bekommen Sie für ihn einen großen Tadel!
You end up getting him
a major demerit!
你最终让他得到了一个大过！
Der Tadel ist nebensächlich.
The demerit is beside the point.
这些缺点都不是重点。
Er muss lernen, gerecht und ehrenhaft zu sein.
He must learn
to be just and honorable.
他必须学会公正、光荣。
Jetzt ist es an der Zeit, auf Prinzipien zu bestehen
This is the time
to insist on principles
现在是坚持原则的时候
und den Kindern ein gutes Beispiel geben.
and set a good example
for the children.
并为孩子们树立良好的榜样。
Dies ist nicht die Zeit für Prinzipien!
This isn't the time for principles!
现在不是讲原则的时候！
Ich gehe auf die Toilette.
I'm going to the bathroom.
我要去洗手间。
- Du bringst immer alles durcheinander. - Unsinn.
- You always mess things up.
- Nonsense.
- 你总是把事情搞砸。 - 胡说。
Ich habe mein Leben im Frieden mit mir selbst gelebt.
I've lived my life
at peace with myself.
我过着平静的生活。
Ich habe nie etwas vermasselt.
I've never messed things up.
我从来没有把事情搞糟过。
Was ist dein Problem? Ich habe gelesen.
What's your problem?
I was reading.
你有什么问题？我正在看书。
Gib mir!
Gimme!
给我！
So spät noch ausgehen?
Going out this late?
这么晚还出去？
Ich muss mir ein Buch von einem Freund ausleihen.
I need to borrow
a book from a friend.
我需要向朋友借一本书。
Beeil dich nach Hause und renne nicht herum!
Hurry home,
and don't be running around!
赶紧回家吧，别到处乱跑了！
Frau Fang war nett zu uns.
Mrs. Fang was kind to us.
方太太对我们很好。
Mein Asthma hat es wieder getan.
My asthma's done it again.
我的哮喘又发作了。
Ich kann ihr nicht vorwerfen, dass sie mich gehen ließ.
I can't blame her
for letting me go.
我不能责怪她放我走。
Ming...
明……
beeil dich und werde erwachsen.
hurry and grow up.
快快长大吧。
Meine Zukunft hängt von dir ab.
My future depends on you.
我的未来取决于你。
Endlich.
Finally.
最后。
Sie haben uns alle warten lassen.
You kept us all waiting.
你让我们大家都久等了。
Geh rein.
Get inside.
进去吧。
Bewegen!
Move!
移动！
Was starrst du so? Hast du ein Problem?
What are you staring at?
You got a problem?
你在看什么？有问题吗？
Bewegen!
Move!
移动！
Beeil dich-
Hurry UP-
赶快-
es ist okay. Sie wollen dich drinnen haben.
it's okay.
They want you inside.
没关系。他们希望你进来。
Komm rein, Lao Er.
Come on in, Lao Er.
进来吧，老二。
Nimm das Fahrrad für ihn.
Take the bike for him.
帮他骑自行车。
Dafür kann man Frau Fang nicht die Schuld geben.
You can't blame
Mrs. Fang for this.
这事你不能怪罪方太太。
Sie kennen meinen Asthmazustand.
You know my asthma condition.
你知道我的哮喘状况。
Wer weiß, wann es Probleme macht?
Who knows when it'll act up?
谁知道它什么时候会发作？
Warum so ein großes Ding daraus machen, dass wir zurückziehen?
Why make a big thing
about us moving back?
为何要大肆宣扬我们搬回去的事？
Jetzt ist alles anders.
Things are different now.
现在情况不同了。
Schauen Sie sich all die Mäuler an, die ich stopfen muss.
Look at all these mouths
I have to feed.
看看我要养活的这么多人。
Sie sind der einzige Verwandte, den wir haben.
You're the only relative we have.
你是我们唯一的亲人。
Wohin können wir sonst gehen?
Where else can we go?
我们还能去哪里？
Sie haben uns mit Ihrem Regiment nach Taiwan gebracht.
You brought us to Taiwan
with your regiment.
您率领您的军团来到了台湾。
Wenn Sie uns nicht wollen, schicken Sie uns weg.
If you don't want us,
send us away.
如果你不要我们，就把我们送走。
Warum die ganze Aufregung?
Why all the fuss?
为什么这么大惊小怪？
Ich ziehe immer aus, sobald ich Arbeit finde.
I always move out
the minute I find work.
我一找到工作总是立刻搬走。
Dieser Ort gehört der Armee.
This place belongs
to the army.
这个地方属于军队。
Auch hier bist du ein Trittbrettfahrer.
You're a freeloader here too.
在这儿你也是个寄生虫。
Ein Trittbrettfahrer?
A freeloader?
寄生虫？
In ihrem Alter habe ich gegen die Japaner und die Kommunisten gekämpft!
At her age, I was fighting
the Japs and the Commies!
在她这个年纪，我正在与日本鬼子和共产党作战！
Lassen Sie mich Ihnen sagen: Ich bin dieses Land.
Let me tell you:
I am this country.
我告诉你们：我就是这个国家。
Dieser Ort gehört der Armee, also gehört er mir.
This place belongs to the army,
so it's mine.
这个地方是军队的，所以是我的。
Was für ein Witz!
What a joke!
真是笑话！
Nehmen wir also an, Sie schulden 350 davon.
So we'll say
you owe 350 of it.
因此我们会说你欠 350 英镑。
Ich bin dafür nicht verantwortlich.
I'm not responsible for it.
我对此不负责任。
Nicht wahr? Er sagt, er sei nicht dafür verantwortlich.
You're not? He says
he's not responsible for it.
你不是吗？他说这事不由他负责。
Für was halten Sie uns?
What do you take us for?
你把我们当成什么了？
Ich war in letzter Zeit etwas knapp bei Kasse.
I've been a little short
on cash recently.
我最近有点缺钱。
Shandong, du vertraust mir, nicht wahr?
Shandong,
you trust me, don't you?
山东，你相信我，是吗？
Kommen Sie hierher. Tun Sie, was ich sage.
Come this way. Do as I say.
往这边来。照我说的做。
Seien Sie kein Hitzkopf wie ich.
Don't be a hothead like me.
别像我一样性情急躁。
Etwas abkühlen lassen.
Cool down a bit.
冷静一下。
Ich habe gehört...
I heard...
我听说...
Ihre Konzertkarten verkaufen sich gut.
your concert tickets
have been selling well.
你的演唱会门票卖得很好。
Gar nicht.
Not at all.
一点也不。
Jemand versucht, alles zu ruinieren.
Someone's trying to ruin it all.
有人试图破坏这一切。
Dein Konzert mit den Little Park Boys
Your concert
with the Little Park boys
您与 Little Park 男孩的音乐会
hat uns in ein schlechtes Licht gerückt.
has made us look bad.
让我们的形象变得很糟糕。
Du teilst die Leckereien immer mit den anderen Jungs.
You always share the goodies
with the other guys.
你总是与其他人分享好东西。
In deinem fettigen kleinen Kopf,
In this greasy little head of yours,
在你这油腻的小脑袋里，
was sind wir wirklich?
what are we really?
我们到底是什么？
Ich werde dir in den Arsch treten
I'm gonna kick your ass
我要踢你的屁股
selbst wenn Shandong Sie glimpflich davonkommen lässt.
even if Shandong
lets you off easy.
就算山东放过你。
Mist, schon wieder Strom!
Shit, the power again!
妈的，又有力量了！
Threads, rennt nicht weg. Bleibt, wo ihr seid.
Threads, don't run off.
Stay where you are.
线不要跑掉。留在原地。
Wie kann ein Idiot wie Sly so viel Einfluss haben?
How could a jerk like Sly
have so much pull?
像 Sly 这样的混蛋怎么会有这么大的影响力？
Den ganzen Einfluss hat sein alter Herr, nicht er.
It's his old man who has
all the clout, not him.
拥有所有影响力的是他的父亲，而不是他。
Was erwartest du von mir?
What do you expect me to do?
你希望我做什么？
Ich sage dir was.
I tell you what.
我告诉你什么。
Ich werde Ihnen eine Pause bei der Rückzahlung des Geldes gönnen, das Sie mir schulden.
I'll give you a break
on the money you owe me.
我会免除你欠我的钱。
Tu mir nur einen Gefallen.
Just do me one favor.
就帮我一个忙。
Ich möchte mich mit Sly treffen.
I want to meet with Sly.
我想和 Sly 见面。
Unmöglich! Die beiden Banden sind erbitterte Feinde.
Impossible! The two gangs
are bitter enemies.
不可能！这两个帮派是死对头。
Wo sind die Independent News?
Wheres the Independent News?
独立新闻在哪里？
Befehle von oben. Wir bekommen jetzt nur noch die Central Daily.
Orders from upstairs.
We only get the Central Daily now.
楼上命令。我们现在只能收到《中央日报》。
Wieder ins Kino gehen? Und was ist mit den Schularbeiten?
Going to the movies again?
What about school work?
又去看电影了？学校作业怎么办？
Spielen Sie einfach Ihr Spiel.
Just play your game.
玩你的游戏就好。
Die Tage ziehen sich hin, seit Sie rausgeworfen wurden, nicht wahr?
The days drag
since you got expelled, huh?
自从被开除之后，日子过得真慢啊？
Scheiße. Was machst du hier?
Shit.
What are you doing here?
妈的。你在这里干什么？
Ich bin ihr Partner im Konzert geworden.
I've becomes partners
with them in the concert.
我已经和他们在演唱会上成为搭档了。
Dann bin ich raus.
Then I'm out.
那我就出去了。
Komm, sei nicht so voreilig.
Come on, don't be so rash.
得了，别这么鲁莽。
Warum sollte man einen so schönen Saal leer stehen lassen?
Why let such a beautiful hall
sit vacant?
为何让如此美丽的大厅空置？
Sehen Sie es so.
Look at it this way.
从这个角度来看。
Solange Sie beide zusammenarbeiten können,
As long as the two of you
can work together,
只要你们两个能一起努力，
es gibt keine Begrenzung für die hereinströmenden Dollars.
there's no limit
to the bucks that'll roll in.
滚滚而来的金钱是没有限制的。
Denken Sie darüber nach.
Think about it.
想一想。
Die ganze 217-Bande wird hinter Ihnen stehen.
The whole 217 gang
will be behind you.
整个217帮派都会支持你。
Wem außer Ihnen werden die Jungs von Little Park folgen?
Who else will the Little Park boys
follow but you?
除了你以外，小公园男孩还会追随​​谁？
Du willst, dass ich meine Brüder verrate.
You want me
to betray my brothers.
你想让我背叛我的兄弟。
Keine Chance.
Not a chance.
没机会。
Schließen Sie Frieden bei einer Zigarette.
Make peace over a smoke.
抽根烟就能达成和平。
Komm, nimm eins.
Come on, have one.
来吧，吃一个。
Scheiße! Jetzt spielst du den Indianer?
Shit!
Now you're playing the Indian?
妈的！你现在扮演印第安人？
Es scheint, Sie haben...
It seems you have...
看来你已经...
Frauenprobleme.
woman problems.
女人的问题。
Ausfahrt?
Jade?
出口？
Da gibt es kein Problem.
No problem there.
没问题。
Ich rede nicht von Jade.
I'm not talking about Jade.
我不是在谈论 Jade。
Ich habe es geheim gehalten …
I've kept it under wraps...
我一直保密……
sonst würden wir hier nicht reden.
or else we wouldn't
be here talking.
否则我们就不会在这里谈话了。
Rechts?
Right?
正确的？
Wenn Sie Probleme haben ...
If you've got problems...
如果您有问题...
Ich kann sie für Sie lösen.
I can solve them for you.
我可以帮你解决。
Nicht das hier.
Not that one.
不是那一个。
Das erste Lied auf Seite A.
The first song on side A.
A 面的第一首歌曲。
Bewegt euch nicht!
Don't anyone move.
谁都别想动。
Wer von euch ist Tiger?
Which one of you is Tiger?
你们当中谁是老虎？
Du willst dich nicht zeigen, was?
Won't show yourself, huh?
不会现身吧？
Was für ein Mist!
What a load of crap!
真是一派胡言！
Wann kann ich den Liedtext bekommen? – Hängt von meiner großen Schwester ab.
When can I get the lyrics?
- Depends on my big sister.
我什么时候可以拿到歌词？ - 取决于我的姐姐。
Morgen, ok?
Tomorrow, okay?
明天可以吗？
- Versuchst du immer noch, dich zu verstecken? - Ich bin nicht Tiger.
- Still trying to hide?
- I'm not Tiger.
- 仍然想躲藏？ - 我不是老虎。
Bist du nicht, oder?
You're not, huh?
你不是吧？
NEIN!
No!
不！
Ich bin es nicht!
It's not me!
不是我！
Wer war dann der Typ, der mit Ming am Schießstand war?
Then who was the guy with Ming
at the shooting range?
那么在射击场和明在一起的那个人是谁？
Bewegen Sie es.
Move it.
移動它。
Hast du deinen Kick bekommen?
Did you get your kicks
你得到乐趣了吗
mit einem unserer Mädchen herumalbern?
fooling around
with one of our girls?
和我们的一个女孩鬼混？
- Stehen Sie stramm! - Achtung!
- Stand at attention!
- Attention!
— 立正！ — 注意！
Wissen Sie nicht, wie man stramm steht?
Don't you know
how to stand at attention?
难道你不知道立正吗？
Woher kommt ihr Jungs?
Where are you boys from?
你们这些孩子来自哪里？
Suchst du Ärger, Wichser?
Looking for trouble, fucker?
找麻烦啊混蛋？
Wissen Sie, auf wessen Revier Sie sich befinden?
You know whose turf you're on?
你知道你在谁的地盘吗？
Es ist Ma, General Mas Sohn.
It's Ma, General Ma's son.
是马将军的儿子。
Fick dich! Wo ist dein Revier?
Fuck you!
Where's your turf?
去你妈的！你的地盘在哪儿？
Wo immer ich bin, ist mein Revier.
Wherever I am is my turf.
我所在的地方就是我的地盘。
Es war alles ein Missverständnis.
It was all a misunderstanding.
这完全是一场误会。
Okay, dann ist alles geklärt.
Okay, then it's all settled.
好的，那就都定了。
Kehren wir zum Dorf zurück.
Let's get back to the village.
我们回村子吧。
Danke.
Thanks.
谢谢。
Kein Problem. Einige von ihnen haben mich erkannt.
No problem.
Some of them recognized me.
没问题。有些人认出了我。
Ich dachte, du wärst ein Musterschüler,
I thought you were
a model student,
我以为你是个模范学生，
aber du machst mit Mädchen rum und gerätst in Schlägereien.
but you mess around with girls
and get into fights.
但你却和女孩们鬼混，还打架。
Sie haben Streit mit mir angefangen.
They picked a fight with me.
他们向我挑起争端。
Wegen eines Mädchens Ärger zu bekommen, ist einfach nur dumm.
Getting in trouble over a girl
is just plain dumb.
为了一个女孩而陷入麻烦简直是愚蠢至极。
Verstehen?
Understand?
理解？
Wo sind sie hin?
Where'd they go?
他们去哪儿了？
Es ist vorbei.
It's over.
结束了。
Was zur Hölle soll das alles?
What the hell's all this?
这到底是什么情况？
Wir sind gekommen, um dich zu retten.
We came to save you.
我们是来救你的。
Du hast die tatsächlich in Kämpfen eingesetzt? Scheiße!
You've actually used these
in fights? Shit!
你真的在打架时用过这些吗？妈的！
Du willst kämpfen? Nimm das.
You wanna fight?
Take this.
想打架吗？拿着这个。
Das ist eine echte Waffe.
This is a real weapon.
这是真正的武器。
Heiliger Strohsack! Cool, Mann!
Holy smokes! Cool, man!
太棒了！太酷了，哥们！
Haben Sie das bei dem Typen an der Banqiao High School verwendet?
Is this what you used
on that guy at Banqiao High?
这就是你对板桥中学那家伙用的东西吗？
Wo hast du es her?
Where'd you get it?
你從哪買到的？
Genau hier, über der Decke.
Right here, above the ceiling.
就在这里，在天花板上面。
Früher lebte hier ein japanischer General.
A Japanese general
used to live here.
一位日本将军曾经住在这里。
Schauen Sie zu Hause auf Ihrem Dachboden nach. Vielleicht finden Sie etwas.
Check your attic at home.
You might find something.
检查一下家里的阁楼。你可能会发现一些东西。
Ich habe einmal eine Kugel für ein japanisches Gewehr gefunden.
I found a bullet
for a Japanese rifle once.
我曾经发现过一颗日本步枪的子弹。
Scheiße! Was ist das jetzt?
Shit! What's this now?
妈的！这是什么情况？
Ein Tonbandgerät aus der Zeit, als Eisenhower hierher kam.
A tape recorder from when
Eisenhower came here.
艾森豪威尔来这里时的录音机。
Ein amerikanischer Reporter hat es meinem alten Herrn überlassen.
An American reporter left it
to my old man.
一位美国记者把它留给了我老爸。
Es kann einen bellenden Hund aus zehn Meilen Entfernung aufnehmen.
It can record a barking dog
ten miles away.
它可以记录十英里外的狗叫声。
Was machst du, Katze?
What are you doing, Cat?
你在做什么呢，猫？
Das Haus auseinanderreißen?
Tearing the house apart?
把房子拆了？
Ich suche nach Ratten.
I'm looking for rats.
我正在寻找老鼠。
Du bist wieder zurückgezogen.
You've moved back again.
你又搬回来了。
Man sagt, dass man bei jedem Umzug einen neuen Freund findet.
They say every time you move,
you find a new boyfriend.
据说你每次搬家，你就会找到一个新男朋友。
Und wie wäre es dieses Mal mit mir?
How about me this time?
这次我怎么样？
Verstehen Sie nicht, was ich sage?
Don't understand
what I'm saying?
不明白我的意思吗？
Das verstehen Sie, nicht wahr?
You understand that,
don't you?
你明白这一点，不是吗？
Sie haben Nerven, in einer solchen Situation zurückzugehen.
You got some nerve,
moving back at a time like this.
你还真是有胆量，在这种时候回来。
Ihretwegen werden wir wahrscheinlich alle in Schwierigkeiten geraten.
We'll probably all end up
in trouble because of you.
我们可能都会因你而陷入困境。
Scheiße! Machst du schon wieder diesen „armes kleines Ich“-Blick?
Shit! Putting on
that “poor little me” look again?
妈的！又摆出一副“可怜的我”的表情？
Irgendwelche Neuigkeiten von Honey?
Any word from Honey?
有 Honey 的消息吗？
- Schauen Sie, wer endlich auftaucht! - Wurde die Anwesenheitskontrolle durchgeführt?
- Look who finally shows up!
- Did they call roll?
- 看看谁终于出现了！ - 他们点名了吗？
Nein, es war eine Studienzeit.
No, it was a study period.
不，这是一段学习时间。
Was zur Hölle ist das?
What the hell's that?
那到底是什么？
Cats Plattenspieler.
Cat's record player.
猫的唱片机。
Hey, kannst du mir ein paar Karten besorgen?
Hey, can you get me
some tickets?
嘿，你能给我拿些票吗？
Für das Konzert? Frag Cat.
For the concert?
Ask Cat.
去看音乐会？问问 Cat。
Weder er noch Airplane sind aufgetaucht.
Neither he nor Airplane
showed up.
他和飞机都没有出现。
Ich werde ihn für dich fragen.
I'll ask him for you.
我会帮你问他。
- Woher kommst du? - Hualien.
- Where do you come from?
- Hualien.
- 你来自哪里？ - 花莲。
Hualien? Das ist ein schöner Ort.
Hualien?
That's a nice place.
花莲？那地方真好。
Ich war einen Monat dort stationiert.
I was stationed there
for a month.
我在那里驻扎了一个月。
Was hat Sie dazu bewogen, nach Taipeh zu kommen?
What made you come to Taipei?
什么原因让您来台北？
Hier passiert noch viel mehr.
There's a lot more
happening here.
这里还发生了很多事情。
Ihr jungen Leute geht dorthin, wo die Massen sind.
You young people go
where the crowds are.
你们年轻人，去人群聚集的地方。
Es stimmt, in Taipeh ist viel los,
It's true,
a lot's happening in Taipei,
确实，台北发生了很多事，
aber nichts im Vergleich zu meiner Heimatstadt.
but nothing compared
to my hometown.
但和我的家乡相比，这算不了什么。
Nehmen wir zum Beispiel meine Heimatstadt.
Take my hometown,
for example.
就拿我的家乡来说吧。
Ich komme aus Qingdao.
I come from Qingdao.
我来自青岛。
Qingdao ist -
Qingdao is -
Ein Schuss für Ihre Augen?
A shot for your eyes?
给你的眼睛打一针吗？
Ich habe keine mehr. Versuchen Sie es nächste Woche.
I've run out. Try next week.
我用完了。下周再试试。
Die Architektur in Qingdao ist etwas ganz Besonderes.
The architecture in Qingdao
is very special.
青岛的建筑很有特色。
Die Deutschen haben es gebaut.
The Germans built it.
它是由德国人建造的。
Das Entwässerungssystem ist bemerkenswert,
The drainage system
is remarkable,
排水系统非常出色，
mit großen breiten Kanälen.
with big wide canals.
有宽大的运河。
Es spielt keine Rolle, wie stark es regnet.
It doesn't matter
how hard it rains.
不管雨有多大都没关系。
Wenn es aufhört, ist nie wieder Wasser auf dem Boden.
Once it stops, there's never
any water on the ground.
一旦停止，地面上就不会再有水。
Nicht wie Taipeh.
Not like Taipei.
不像台北。
Wenn es regnet, ist überall Wasser.
When it rains,
there's water everywhere.
下雨的时候，到处都是水。
Hast du nicht gesagt, dass du zu meinem Probeauftritt kommst?
Didn't you say you'd come
to my screen test?
你不是说要来参加我的试镜吗？
Warum bist du nicht aufgetaucht?
Why didn't you show up?
你为何没出现？
Hast du nicht gehört, dass ich einen großen Tadel bekommen habe?
Didn't you hear
I got a major demerit?
你没听说我被记大过吗？
Und erinnere dich, als etwa 217 Jungs dich und mich sahen
And remember when
some 217 guys saw you and me
还记得有 217 个人看到你和我的时候
am Schießstand?
at the shooting range?
在射击场？
Neulich sind sie hinter mir her, als ich in der Schule war.
They came after me
the other night at school.
有天晚上他们在学校追我。
Ich hatte in letzter Zeit eine Pechsträhne.
I've had a string
of bad luck lately.
最近我的运气很差。
Cat sagte mir, ich solle zur Eisdiele gehen.
Cat told me to go
to the ice cream parlor.
猫叫我去冰淇淋店。
Er wirkte nervös, als ob etwas nicht stimmte.
He seemed nervous,
like something was up.
他看上去很紧张，好像有什么事发生。
Du hast Cat gesehen?
You saw Cat?
你看到猫了吗？
Kein Wunder, dass er und Airplane heute den Unterricht geschwänzt haben.
No wonder he and Airplane
cut class today.
难怪他和飞机今天逃课了。
Ich gehe mit dir. Ich habe etwas für ihn.
I'll go with you.
I've got something for him.
我跟你一起去。我有东西给他。
Haben Sie keine Angst, wieder in Schwierigkeiten zu geraten?
Aren't you afraid of getting
into trouble again?
你就不怕再惹麻烦吗？
Zwischen uns läuft nichts. Wovor gibt es Angst?
Nothing's going on between you and me.
What's to be afraid of?
你我之间什么事也没有，有什么好怕的？
- Was machst du hier? - Ich gebe es dir zurück.
- What are you doing here?
- Returning this to you.
- 你在这里干什么？ - 把这个还给你。
Die Liedtexte sind drin.
The lyrics are inside.
歌词在里面。
- Was machst du hier? - Dir gehört der Laden?
- What are you doing here?
- You own the place?
- 你在这里干什么？ - 这里是你家的吗？
Es ist cool, Mann. Er ist hier, um mich zu sehen.
It's cool, man.
He's here to see me.
太棒了，哥们。他来看我了。
Sie benehmen sich mutiger als beim letzten Mal, als ich Sie sah.
You're acting gutsier
than last time I saw you.
你比我上次见到你时表现得更有勇气。
Ich habe gehört, dass Sie beide in letzter Zeit eine wirklich tolle Zeit haben.
I hear you two are having
a real sweet time lately.
我听说你们俩最近过得很开心。
Von wem sprichst du?
Who are you talking about?
你在說谁？
Was für ein Schauspieler!
What an actor!
真是个出色的演员！
Ein echter Gregory Pecker!
A real Gregory Pecker!
真正的格里高利·佩克！
Jetzt steckst du tief in der Scheiße.
Now you're in deep shit.
现在你陷入了困境。
Lauf nicht weg.
Don't run off.
别想逃跑。
Wir sind alle Brüder. Vergiss es.
We're all brothers.
Forget it.
我们都是兄弟，算了吧。
Harter Kerl, was?
Tough guy, eh?
很硬汉啊？
Wo hast du das gelernt?
Where'd you learn it from?
你從哪裡學到的？
Scheiße! Ich werde dir eine Lektion erteilen.
Fuck! I'm gonna
teach you a lesson.
操！我要教训你一下。
Das tut nicht mehr weh, oder?
This doesn't hurt anymore, huh?
这已经不疼了，嗯？
Es juckt nur, oder?
Just itches, huh?
只是痒痒吧？
Bist du nicht ein Musterschüler? Wie kommt es, dass du wütend wirst?
Aren't you a model student?
How come you're getting angry?
你不是模范学生吗？怎么生气了？
Das ist er nicht.
He's not.
他不是。
Soll ich dir auch eine Lektion erteilen?
Want me to teach you
a lesson too?
也想让我教训你一下吗？
Sich so über so einen Wichser lustig zu machen -
Picking on a squirt like that -
挑选这样的喷水器 -
ziemlich erbärmlich.
pretty pathetic.
真可悲。
Komm mit mir.
Come with me.
跟我来。
Ich habe mich nur um Ihr Geschäft gekümmert.
I was just taking care
of business for you.
我只是在帮你处理一些事情。
- Du siehst aus wie ein guter Junge. - Ich bin hier, um Cat zu sehen.
- You look like a good kid.
- I'm here to see Cat.
- 你看上去是个好孩子。 - 我来见凯特。
Sie haben hier nichts zu suchen.
You have no business here.
你在这里无事可做。
Legen Sie los.
Get going.
开始吧。
Bist du fertig mit Reden?
You done talking?
你说完了吗？
Den meisten Jungs geht es genauso.
Most of the guys
feel the same way.
大多数人都有同样的感受。
So wie es jetzt ist, kann es nicht weitergehen.
Things can't go on
as they are now.
事情不能再像现在这样继续下去了。
Jemand muss die Verantwortung übernehmen.
Someone has to take charge.
总得有人来负责。
Die Dinge müssen weitergehen, wenn Sie nicht hier sind.
Things have to go on
when you're not here.
你不在的时候事情还得继续。
Ihre Probleme mit den 217 Jungen sind persönlicher Natur.
Your problems with
the 217 boys are personal.
你和 217 名男孩之间的问题是个人问题。
Sie kamen aus eigener Initiative, um Frieden zu schaffen.
They came for peace
on their own initiative.
他们是主动来寻求和平的。
Die Jungs sind alle der Meinung, dass wir darüber nachdenken sollten.
The guys all think
we should consider it.
大家都认为我们应该考虑这一点。
Denken Sie darüber nach.
Think it over.
好好考虑一下。
Lassen Sie uns das nächste Mal wissen, was Sie denken.
Let us know
what you think next time.
下次让我们知道您的想法。
Scheiße!
Shit!
拉屎！
Das ist offene Meuterei.
This is open mutiny.
这是公开的叛变。
Bruder.
Brother.
兄弟。
Die Dinge sind nicht so einfach, wie Sie denken.
Things aren't
as simple as you think.
事情并不像你想象的那么简单。
Sagen Sie Eastgate Ling und Third-ring Ye
Go tell Eastgate Ling
and Third-ring Ye
去告诉东门岭和三环叶
dass ich in der Stadt bin.
that I'm in town.
我在城里。
Sag ihnen, sie sollen vorbeikommen.
Tell them to come over.
叫他们过来。
Sag nichts anderes.
Don't say anything else.
别再说了。
Scheiße.
Shit.
拉屎。
Shandong und Threads haben das Konzert zu einer ziemlichen Angelegenheit gemacht.
Shandong and Threads have turned
the concert into quite an affair.
山东和Threads让这场音乐会变得十分热闹。
Lassen Sie uns ein wenig Schärfe hinzufügen.
Let's add a little heat.
让我们加一点热量。
Muss es während des Konzerts sein?
Does it have to be
during the concert?
一定要在演唱会期间吗？
Scheiße! Kein Wunder, dass du Sly nie gewachsen sein wirst.
Shit! No wonder you'll never be
a match for Sly.
妈的！难怪你永远不是史莱的对手。
Sie müssen sich nur darum kümmern, auf die Bühne zu gehen und zu singen.
All you worry about is
getting on stage and singing.
您所担心的只是登台唱歌。
Habe ich recht?
Am I right?
我说得对吗？
Du bist ein hoffnungsloser Fall.
You're hopeless.
你太没有希望了。
- Hast du nicht gesagt, Lao Er wüsste es? - Worüber?
- Didn't you say Lao Er knows?
- About what?
——你不是说老二知道吗？——什么事？
Was Threads und die 217er vorhaben.
What Threads
and the 217s are up to.
Threads 和 217 在做什么。
Lao Er.
老二。
Aufstehen.
Get up.
起床。
Jetzt ist nicht die Zeit zum Reden. Lasst sie uns töten!
This is no time for talking.
Let's kill 'em!
现在不是说话的时候。让我们杀了他们！
Scheiße! Warum sollte man Eastgate und den Dritten Ring um Hilfe bitten?
Fuck! Why look for help
from Eastgate and Third-ring?
操！干嘛找东门和三环帮忙？
Ich habe genug Leute, um die Arbeit zu erledigen.
I've got enough guys
to do the job.
我已经有足够的人手来完成这项工作。
- Was? - Streichhölzer.
- What?
- Matches.
- 什麼？ - 火柴。
Scheiße, lasst sie uns umbringen!
Shit, let's kill 'em!
妈的，让我们杀了他们！
Wie bist du mit Threads in Berührung gekommen?
How'd you get mixed up
with Threads?
您是怎么与 Threads 混淆的？
Ich traf ihn in einer Billardhalle in der Nähe der Schule.
I met him in a pool hall
near school.
我在学校附近的一个台球厅遇见了他。
Er sagte, er wüsste, wie man Geld verdienen könne.
He said he knew
a way to make money.
他说他知道一种赚钱的方法。
Das Geld klang gut, also –
The money sounded good, so -
钱听起来不错，所以——
Ich war nur ein paar Monate im Süden
I was only down south
a few months
我只在南方待了几个月
bevor es euch hier in den Fingern juckte, Geld zu verdienen.
before you guys here
started itching to make money.
在你们开始渴望赚钱之前。
Ist das Leben in Taipeh wirklich so hart?
Is life in Taipei really that hard?
在台北生活真的那么难吗？
Sly hat mich immer angefleht
Sly used to beg me
Sly 曾经求过我
ihn in unsere Gang aufzunehmen.
to take him into our gang.
把他纳入我们的帮派。
Wenn du nicht gesagt hättest
If it weren't for you saying
如果不是你说
sein alter Herr könnte Ihnen den Saal für Ihre Konzerte überlassen,
his old man could let you use
the auditorium for your concerts,
他父亲可以让你使用礼堂举办音乐会，
Dieses Arschloch ist mir scheißegal.
I wouldn't give a shit
about that asshole.
我才不在乎那个混蛋。
Jetzt, da die 217-Bande hinter ihm steht,
Now that the 217 gang
is behind him,
现在有217团伙支持他，
er zeigt sein wahres Gesicht.
he's showing his true colors.
他露出了他的真面目。
Alles für ein paar Dollar.
All for a few bucks.
只需几块钱。
Er ist jetzt der Chef von Little Park,
He's the boss of Little Park now,
他现在是 Little Park 的老板，
verstehen?
understand?
理解？
Sag es den Jungs von Eastgate und Third-Ring
Go tell Eastgate's
and Third-ring's boys
去告诉东门和三环的男孩们
dass wir beschlossen haben, das Konzert nicht zu stürmen.
that we've decided
not to crash the concert.
我们决定不打扰这场音乐会。
Da sowohl Shandong als auch Threads wissen, dass ich zurück bin,
Since both Shandong
and Threads know I'm back,
既然山东和Threads都知道我回来了，
Sie werden Vorkehrungen treffen.
they'll take precautions.
他们会采取预防措施。
Ich werde diese Rechnung ein anderes Mal begleichen.
I'll settle this score
some other time.
我会在其他时间解决这个问题。
In Ordnung.
All right.
好的。
Gehst du zurück zu Doggie's in Tainan?
You going back
to Doggie's in Tainan?
你要回台南的 Doggie's 吗？
Du kannst dich gerne hier bei uns verstecken.
You're welcome
to hide out here with us.
欢迎您和我们一起躲在这里。
Ich gehe zurück nach Tainan.
I'm going back to Tainan.
我要回台南了。
Es hat keine Zukunft, mit diesen Kindern vom Festland herumzuhängen.
There's no future in hanging out
with these mainland kids.
和这些大陆孩子一起玩是没有前途的。
Ich kann jetzt wie Sie Einheimischen Taiwanesisch sprechen.
I can speak Taiwanese
like you locals now.
我现在可以像你们当地人一样说台湾话了。
Ich war wie ein Stummer in Tainan
I was like a mute in Tainan
我在台南就像个哑巴
Ich spreche nicht die Landessprache. Vielen Dank für die Gastfreundschaft.
not speaking the native language.
Thanks for all the hospitality.
不会说母语。非常感谢你们的热情款待。
Erwähne es nicht.
Don't mention it.
别提了。
Ein Freund von Doggie ist ein Freund von mir.
A friend of Doggie's
is a friend of mine.
Doggie 的朋友也是我的朋友。
Teufel.
Deuce.
见鬼。
Singen Sie ruhig beim Konzert.
Go ahead and sing
at the concert.
去音乐会唱歌吧。
Es ist keine große Sache. Mach dir keine Sorgen.
It's no big deal.
Don't sweat it.
没什么大不了的。别担心。
Entspannen Sie sich und bieten Sie eine gute Show.
Relax and put on a good show.
放松心情，好好表现一番。
Du da drüben.
You there.
你在那里。
Komm her.
Come over here.
过来。
Ming sagt mir, dass sie dich sehr mag.
Ming tells me
she likes you a lot.
明告诉我她很喜欢你。
Das habe ich gleich gemerkt, als ich Sie das erste Mal traf.
I could tell right away
when I first met you.
当我第一次见到你时我立刻就看出来。
Ming hat auf deine Rückkehr gewartet.
Ming's been waiting
for you to get back.
明一直在等你回来。
Als mir langweilig wurde, während ich mich versteckte,
When I got bored
while I was hiding out,
当我躲起来感到无聊的时候，
Ich habe jeden Tag Unmengen von Kampfkunstromanen gelesen.
I'd read tons
of martial arts novels a day.
我每天都会读大量的武侠小说。
Ich würde ihnen sagen, sie sollen mir die dicksten Romane besorgen, die sie finden können.
I'd tell them to get me
the thickest novels they could find.
我会让他们给我找来他们能找到的最厚的小说。
Ich habe Menschen in der Vergangenheit entdeckt
I discovered people in the past
我发现过去的人
die genau wie wir Straßengangs waren.
who were just like us street gangs.
他们就像我们街头帮派一样。
Da war dieser eine Typ.
There was this one guy.
有这么一个人。
Alle dachten, er sei verrückt.
Everyone thought he was crazy.
大家都认为他疯了。
Ich erinnere mich...
I remember...
我记得……
alle waren weggelaufen...
everyone had run away...
大家都逃跑了……
und die Stadt geriet in Brand.
and the city was set ablaze.
整座城市被点燃。
Er allein blieb zurück, um Napoleon zu ermorden.
He alone stayed behind
to assassinate Napoleon.
他独自留下来刺杀拿破仑。
Am Ende scheiterte er und wurde gefasst.
In the end,
he failed and was caught.
最后他失败了，并被抓住了。
Krieg und Frieden.
War and Peace.
战争与和平。
Ich habe die Namen aller anderen Romane vergessen.
I've forgotten the names
of all the other novels.
我忘记了所有其他小说的名字。
Das ist das Einzige, woran ich mich erinnere.
That's the only one I remember.
这是我唯一记得的。
Irgendwelche Probleme?
Any problems?
有什么问题吗？
Nein. Komm und setz dich.
No. Come and sit.
不，过来坐吧。
Hier ist Horsecart. Ihr Name ist...?
This is Horsecart.
Your name is...?
这是 Horsecart。你的名字是......？
Xiao Sir.
Xiao Si'r.
Ming wird ein paar Tage hier bleiben.
Ming will stay here a few days.
明会在这里呆几天。
Sie wissen, dass ich in Taipeh bin. Sie werden sie beschatten.
They know I'm in Taipei.
They'll put a tail on her.
他们知道我在台北，他们会派人跟踪她。
Sie wird sich sehr unwohl fühlen.
She'll be very uncomfortable.
她会很不舒服。
Wissen Sie, wenn Sie zurückgeschrieben hätten ...
You know,
if you'd written back...
你知道，如果你回信的话……
nichts davon wäre passiert.
none of this
would have happened.
这一切都不会发生。
Scheiße!
Shit!
拉屎！
Wenn ich schreiben könnte, hätte ich einen Roman geschrieben!
If I could write,
I'd have written a novel!
如果我会写作，我就会写一本小说！
Damit Leute wie ich es in Zukunft lesen können.
For people like me
to read in the future.
以供将来像我这样的人阅读。
Jetzt ist es zu spät.
It's too late now.
现在已经太晚了。
Ich habe nicht fleißig genug gelernt.
I didn't study hard enough.
我学习不够努力。
Sir, Sly ist da drüben.
Si'r, Sly's over there.
先生，Sly 在那边。
Schau ihn dir nur an. Scheiße!
Just look at him. Shit!
看看他。妈的！
Sly, ich möchte dir einen großen Hasen vorstellen.
Sly, let me introduce you
to a big shot.
斯莱，我给你介绍一位大人物。
Nicht überall mitlaufen!
Don't tag along everywhere!
别到处跟着人！
Officer, das ist der, von dem ich Ihnen erzählt habe.
Officer, this is the one
I told you about.
警官，这就是我跟你说过的事。
Er ist der Sohn des Managers.
He's the manager's son.
他是经理的儿子。
Was ist das?
What is it?
它是什么？
Wem willst du mit diesen Polizisten von Juvenile Angst einjagen?
Who you tryin' to scare
with these cops from Juvenile?
你想用《少年》里的这些警察来吓唬谁？
Ich wusste, dass Sie Vorsichtsmaßnahmen treffen,
I knew you were taking
precautions,
我知道你正在采取预防措施，
also habe ich mein eigenes genommen.
so I took my own.
所以我带了自己的。
Sie möchten die Verantwortung übernehmen, wenn etwas passiert?
You want to be responsible
if something happens?
如果发生什么事情你想负责任吗？
Studenten.
Students.
学生。
Wir unterstützen natürlich
We of course endorse
我们当然赞同
außerschulische Aktivitäten wie diese.
extracurricular activities like this.
像这样的课外活动。
Aber wir müssen Zurückhaltung üben, wenn wir Spaß haben.
But we must exercise restraint
as we have fun.
但我们在玩乐的同时必须保持克制。
Ärger würde es für alle nur verderben.
Trouble will only spoil it
for everyone.
麻烦只会破坏每个人的幸福。
Ist das klar?
Is that clear?
清楚了吗？
Jawohl, Sir!
Yes, sir!
是的，先生！
Es ist die Nationalhymne!
It's the national anthem!
这是国歌！
Steht alle stramm!
Stand at attention, all of you!
大家立正！
Wo ist Ihr Ticket?
Where's your ticket?
你的票在哪儿？
Wer hat Ihnen erlaubt, dieses Konzert zu veranstalten?
Who let you put on this concert?
谁让你举办这场音乐会的？
Du konsultierst mich nicht einmal,
You don't even consult me,
你甚至不咨询我，
dann wagst du es, mich nach einer Fahrkarte zu fragen?
then you dare ask me
for a ticket?
那你还敢向我要票吗？
Rauchen Sie nicht, wenn ich spreche!
Don't smoke when I'm talking!
我说话的时候不要抽烟！
Komm schon. Ich kenne diese Nummer schon.
Come on. I've been
through this number before.
拜托。我以前用过这个号码。
Komm, ich nehme es mit dir auf.
Come on. I'll take you on.
来吧，我带你去。
Wo ist dein Chef? Sag Shandong, er soll rauskommen.
Where's your boss?
Tell Shandong to come out.
你老板呢？叫山东出来。
Ich bin gleich wieder da.
I'll be right back.
我马上回来。
Beweg deinen Arsch her!
Get your ass over here!
快过来！
Sehr geehrter Gast...
Distinguished guest...
贵宾...
Kommen Sie herein und genießen Sie die Musik.
please come in
and enjoy the music.
请进来欣赏音乐。
Sie sind zu freundlich. Ich habe gehört, Sie wollen eine Einigung.
You're too kind.
I hear you want an agreement.
你太客气了。我听说你想要一份协议。
Hier bin ich.
Here I am.
我在这里。
Wenn Sie eine Vereinbarung wünschen, sprechen Sie zuerst mit mir.
If you want an agreement,
talk to me first.
如果您想要达成协议，请先与我谈谈。
Hey, es ist ein glücklicher Tag.
Hey, it's a happy day.
嘿嘿，真是开心的一天啊。
Lass uns ein anderes Mal darüber reden.
Let's talk things over
some other time.
我们改天再谈吧。
Zwischen dir und mir herrscht keine glückliche Atmosphäre.
There's nothing happy
between you and me.
你我之间没有什么开心的事。
Wenn Sie den Mut haben, spielen Sie um Geld.
If you've got the balls,
play for the money.
如果你有勇气，就为了钱而玩。
Wer hat gesagt, dass dieses Konzert auf meinem Territorium stattfinden kann?
Who said you could have
this concert on my turf?
谁说你可以在我的地盘举办这场音乐会？
Gut. Komm und spiel.
Fine. Come on and play.
好啊，来玩吧。
Die Jugendabteilung ist drinnen. Lass uns dich jetzt spielen sehen.
Juvenile Division's inside.
Let's see you play now.
少年组就在里面。现在就看你表现了。
Denkst du, du bist hart, weil du in der Überzahl bist?
Think you're tough
'cause you outnumber me?
你以为你人数比我多，所以你很强大吗？
Kommt schon. Alle zusammen, jetzt.
Come on.
All together now.
来吧。现在大家一起来。
Oder einzeln?
Or one at a time?
还是一次一个？
Lass ihn gehen.
Let him go.
放他走吧。
- Wichser! - Halt!
- Motherfucker!
- Hold it!
- 混蛋！ - 等等！
Lass uns da draußen reden.
Let's talk out there.
我们到外面去谈吧。
So geht ihr 217 Jungs immer vor.
This is how you 217 boys
always operate.
你们217小子一贯都是这么行事的。
Die Marine der Republik! Scheiße!
The Navy of the Republic! Shit!
共和国海军！该死！
Ich kenne diesen Trick.
I know that trick.
我知道这个诀窍。
Feiglinge wie er ziehen Uniformen an, um die Bullen zu täuschen.
Chickenshits like him
put on uniforms to fool the cops.
像他这样的胆小鬼穿上制服来愚弄警察。
Ich werde dich der Marine ausliefern!
I'll turn you in to the navy!
我要把你交给海军！
Autogramm!
Autograph!
签名！
Tut mir leid, Leute! Hier entlang, bitte.
Sorry, folks!
This way, please.
抱歉，各位！请这边走。
Suchen Sie jemanden? Hinter die Bühne darf niemand.
You looking for someone?
No one's allowed backstage.
你在找人吗？后台不允许任何人进入。
Nur für eine Minute. Was kann es schon schaden?
Just for a minute.
What'll it hurt?
就一分钟。会有什么伤害吗？
Wer zum Teufel sind Sie? Sie gehören nicht zum Personal.
Who the hell are you?
You're not on staff.
你到底是谁？你不是工作人员。
Willst du es wirklich wissen?
You really wanna know?
你真的想知道吗？
Okay, ich werde ihnen eine Nachricht geben.
Okay, I'll give 'em a message.
好的，我会给他们留言。
Das ist eine Privatsache. Keine Nachrichten.
It's private business.
No messages.
这是私事。没有消息。
Beruhige dich. Sag uns, wen du suchst, und wir schicken nach ihm.
Cool it. Tell us who you want
and we'll send for him.
冷静一下。告诉我们你想要谁，我们会派人去找他。
Flugzeug aus Little Park.
Airplane from Little Park.
从小公园起飞的飞机。
Sie kommen also zurecht, weil Sie viele Leute haben, nicht wahr?
So you get by because
you have lots of people, huh?
所以，因为你们人多，所以你们才能过得去，是吧？
Wenn ihr euch gegen mich verbünden und mir in den Hintern treten wollt, bitte.
If you want to gang up on me
and kick my ass, fine.
如果你想联合起来攻击我，踢我的屁股，那好吧。
Das bleibt unter uns. Lass uns da rübergehen.
This is between you and me.
Let's go over there.
这是你我之间的事。我们去那边吧。
Mir geht es gut. Lass ihn gehen!
I'm okay. Let him go!
我没事。放开他吧！
Das war für die Vorbereitung des Konzerts hinter meinem Rücken.
That was for setting up
the concert behind my back.
那是为了在我背后筹办音乐会。
Okay, lass uns anfangen zu reden.
Okay, let's start talking.
好，我们开始讲吧。
Dies ist ein Friedensgespräch. Sie alle sind Zeugen.
This is a peace talk.
You're all witnesses.
这是和平谈判，你们都是见证人。
Aufleuchten.
Come on.
快点。
Nur zwei Arten von Menschen machen mir Angst, Shandong:
Only two types of people
scare me, Shandong:
山东只有两种人让我害怕：
der Typ, der keine Angst vor dem Tod hat,
the type
that's not afraid to die,
不怕死的人，
und der Typ, der keine Scham kennt.
and the type that has no shame.
以及没有羞耻心的人。
Welcher Typ sind Sie?
Which type are you?
你是哪一類？
Nicht reden?
Not talking?
不说话？
Sie möchten nicht reden oder haben Angst davor?
Don't wanna talk,
or afraid to talk?
不想说话，或害怕说话？
Sie scheinen nicht der Typ zu sein, der keine Angst vor dem Tod hat.
You don't seem the type
that's not afraid to die.
你看起来不像是那种不怕死的人。
Das dachte ich mir.
I thought not.
我认为不是。
Du siehst so düster und trostlos aus.
You look so dark and dreary.
你看上去如此阴暗和阴沉。
Sei nicht so unglücklich.
Don't be so unhappy.
别这么不开心。
Wovor gibt es Grund zur Angst?
What's there to be afraid of?
有什么可害怕的？
Steck das weg! Willst du Ärger?
Put that away!
You lookin' for trouble?
把它拿开！你是在找麻烦吗？
Ich kann ihn nicht finden.
Can't find him.
找不到他。
Fick dich!
Fuck you!
去你的！
Erzähl mir nicht diesen Scheiß.
Don't give me that shit.
别跟我说这些废话。
Lass nicht zu, dass ich dich alleine erwische.
Don't let me catch you alone.
别让我抓到你一个人。
Was machst du hier draußen?
What are you doing out here?
你在这里干什么？
Geh wieder rein.
Get back inside.
回到屋内。
Lass mich das nächste Mal ein Lied von Elvis singen, okay?
Next time let me sing
an Elvis song, okay?
下次让我唱一首猫王的歌，可以吗？
Scheiße! Du singst Elvis!
Shit! You singing Elvis!
操！你这个唱歌的猫王！
Dann singe ich Connie Francis!
Then I'll sing Connie Francis!
那我就唱《康妮·弗朗西斯》吧！
Schauen Sie in den Spiegel!
Take a look in the mirror!
照照镜子吧！
Sie hacken nur auf Ihren eigenen Leuten herum.
You only pick
on your own people.
你只针对你自己的人。
Ich werde dir zeigen, dass ich es kann.
I'll show you I can.
我会让你知道我能做到。
Dann gründe deine eigene Band.
Then start your own band.
然后组建自己的乐队。
Gut. Ich verstehe.
Fine. I understand.
好的。我明白了。
Wir Ärzte sollten einen wohltätigen Geist zeigen.
We doctors should show
a charitable spirit.
我们医生应该表现出一种慈善精神。
Ich erzählte meinem Vater von den Arztkosten.
I told my father
about the medical expenses.
我把医疗费的事告诉了父亲。
Er versteht Ihre finanzielle Situation.
He understands
your financial situation.
他了解你的财务状况。
Es besteht kein Grund zur Sorge.
There's no need to worry.
没有必要担心。
- Danke. - Keine Ursache.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
- 谢谢。 - 别提了。
Es scheint, dass ihr Problem nur teilweise körperlicher Natur ist.
It appears her problem
is only partly physical.
看起来她的问题仅仅部分是身体上的。
Lass sie hier ein paar Tage ruhen.
Let her rest here a few days.
让她在这里休息几天。
Ich werde gut auf sie aufpassen.
I'll take good care of her.
我会好好照顾她的。
Sie alle sagen, Honey sei von den 217ern getötet worden,
They all say Honey
was killed by the 217s,
他们都说哈尼是被 217 杀死的，
aber die Zeitungen sagen, es sei ein Verkehrsunfall gewesen.
but the newspapers say
it was a traffic accident.
但报纸说这是一场交通事故。
Manche Leute sagen, er sei vom Militär desertiert.
Some people say he's AWOL
from the military.
有人说他从军队擅离职守。
Ist er nicht zurück in den Süden gegangen?
Didn't he go back south?
他不是回南方了吗？
Hör auf zu nörgeln! Das geht dich nichts an!
Stop nagging!
It's none of your business!
别唠叨了！这不关你的事！
Sagen Sie es mir. Ich habe gewettet, dass die Nachricht falsch war.
Tell me. I made a bet
that the news was wrong.
告诉我。我打赌这个消息是错的。
Wie konnte er unerlaubt abwesend sein?
How could he go AWOL?
他怎么能擅离职守呢？
Hast du es nicht gesehen, Mama?
Didn't you see it happen, Ma?
妈妈，难道您没看到这一幕吗？
Geht dich nichts an! Hör auf, so ein großes Maul zu haben!
None of your fucking business!
Quit shooting off your mouth!
不关你的事！别再胡说八道了！
Ich werde dich krankenhausreif prügeln.
I'll beat the shit out of you.
我要狠狠地打你一顿。
Los geht's. Zeit für den Unterricht.
Let's go. Time for class.
走吧。上课时间到了。
Bereits?
Already?
已经？
Ich muss auf die Toilette.
I've gotta go to the bathroom.
我得去趟洗手间。
Warum gehst du nicht zwischen den Unterrichtsstunden hin?
Why don't you go between classes?
你为什么不在课间去呢？
Ich habe dich tagelang gesucht. Du bist nicht zum Unterricht gekommen.
I've been looking for you for days.
You didn't come to class.
我找了你好几天了，你都没来上课。
Warst du krank?
Were you sick?
你病了吗？
Ich dachte, er wäre zurück in den Süden gegangen.
I thought he went back south.
我以为他回南方了。
Bevor Sie Taipeh verlassen ...
Before leaving Taipei...
离开台北之前...
er hat mir die Adresse seines Verstecks ​​hinterlassen.
he left me the address
of his hideout.
他给我留下了他的藏身处的地址。
Ich hatte vor, ihn zu besuchen.
I was planning to go see him.
我原本打算去看他。
Er hat mich sogar ausgelacht ...
He even laughed at me...
他甚至还嘲笑我...
für die Sorge.
for being so worried.
因为我太担心了。
Es war seltsam.
It was strange.
这很奇怪。
Viele Tage lang lag ich krank im Bett,
For many days
while I lay sick in bed,
我卧病在床多日，
Ich konnte mich nicht an Honeys Gesicht erinnern.
I couldn't recall Honey's face.
我记不起 Honey 的脸。
Ich hatte Angst und war verwirrt.
I was scared and confused.
我感到害怕和困惑。
Ming, hab keine Angst! Du musst mutig sein!
Ming, don't be afraid!
You have to be brave!
明，别害怕！你要勇敢！
Ich bin bei dir. Du brauchst keine Angst zu haben!
I'm with you.
You needn't be afraid!
有我在，你不用怕！
Ich werde immer bei dir sein! Ich werde für immer dein Freund sein!
I'll always be with you!
I'll be your friend forever!
我会一直陪着你！我会永远是你的朋友！
Ich werde dich beschützen.
I'll protect you.
我会保护你的。
Ich brauche niemandes Hilfe. Mir kann sowieso niemand helfen.
I don't need anyone's help.
No one can help anyway.
我不需要任何人的帮助。反正也没人能帮我。
Hey, da ist Ming! Ganz allein.
Hey, it's Ming! By herself.
嘿，是 Ming！独自一人。
- Hast du Ideen? - Scheiße! Das würde ich nicht wagen.
- You got ideas?
- Shit! I wouldn't dare.
- 你有主意吗？ - 妈的！我不敢。
Hey, schau mal.
Hey, look.
嘿，看。
Gibst du mir immer noch die Schuld an deiner Beinverletzung?
Still blame me
for your leg injury?
还因为你的腿受伤而责怪我吗？
- War Tiger nicht mit ihr aus? - Sie redet nicht mit ihm.
- Wasn't Tiger going out with her?
- She's not talking to him.
- 泰格不是和她一起出去吗？ - 她没有和他说话。
Da kommt er.
Here he comes.
他来了。
Wolltest du nicht mit ihr ausgehen?
Weren't you going out with her?
你不是和她一起出去吗？
Honey ist tot.
Honey's dead.
霍妮死了。
Jetzt kann jeder sie für sich entscheiden ...
Now she's anyone's game...
现在她是任何人的游戏......
aber ich glaube nicht, dass Sie eine große Chance haben.
but I don't think
you stand much of a chance.
但我不认为你有什么机会。
Honey ist kein Problem, ob tot oder lebendig.
Honey's no problem,
dead or alive.
蜂蜜没问题，无论是死的还是活的。
Der Idiot hat sich beim Konzert wie ein arroganter Wichser benommen.
The idiot acted like
an arrogant prick at the concert.
这个白痴在音乐会上表现得像个傲慢的混蛋。
Er wurde von keinem Auto angefahren. Die 217 Jungs ließen es ihm durchgehen.
He wasn't hit by no car.
The 217 boys let him have it.
他没有被车撞到。217 个男孩让他受了苦。
Du hast etwas zu sagen?
You got something to say?
你有话要说吗？
Verdammt!
Goddamn it!
该死！
Beeil dich, sonst verpasse ich den letzten Bus.
Hurry up
or I'll miss the last bus.
快点，不然我就错过末班车了。
Immer mit der Ruhe. Ich fahre dich mit.
Take it easy.
I'll give you a ride.
别着急，我载你一程。
Glaubst du, ich falle wieder darauf herein?
Think I'll fall for that again?
您认为我还会再上当吗？
Versuch noch einmal, es auf mich zu werfen, Junge.
Try throwing it
at me again, boy.
尝试再一次将它扔给我吧，小子。
Schauen Sie sich diesen Kerl an.
Look at this guy.
看看这个家伙。
Meint er es ernst?
Is he for real?
他是认真的吗？
Ich denke schon.
I guess so.
大概吧。
Überlegen Sie es sich gut. Lassen Sie sich nicht unter Druck setzen.
Think it over.
Don't feel pressured.
好好考虑一下。不要有压力。
Ich muss gehen. Es ist spät.
I've got to go. it's late.
我得走了。太晚了。
Si'r auf die Tagesschule versetzen
Getting Si'r transferred
to day school
让 Sir 转入日校
ist kompliziert.
is complicated.
很复杂。
Ich dachte, ich könnte mich da durchreden
I thought I could talk
my way through it
我以为我可以通过谈话来解决这个问题
damit er die Transferprüfungen nicht ablegen muss.
so he wouldn't have to take
the transfer exams.
这样他就不必参加转学考试。
Ich werde es noch einmal bei meinen Freunden im Bildungsausschuss versuchen.
I'll try my friends
on the Board of Education again.
我会再次尝试向教育委员会的朋友寻求帮助。
Vielen Dank.
Thanks a lot.
多谢。
Ich arbeite noch an Ihrer Lehrbefähigung.
I'm still working
on your teaching certificate.
我仍在努力考取你的教师资格证书。
Es wird einige Zeit dauern.
It'll take some time.
这需要一些时间。
Auf Wiedersehen.
Good-bye.
再见。
Wie konnte er mich so um einen Gefallen bitten?
How could he ask me
for a favor like that?
他怎么能请求我做这样的事呢？
Versuchen Sie einfach mitzuspielen.
Try to just play along-
试着一起玩-
Seien Sie nicht zu stur.
Don't be too hardheaded.
别太固执。
Lassen Sie sich davon nicht unterkriegen.
Don't let it get to you.
别让它影响到你。
Versuchen Sie, sich keine Feinde zu machen.
Try not to make enemies.
尽量不要树敌。
Das ist nicht Shanghai,
This isn't Shanghai,
这不是上海，
wo Sie die Unterstützung von Professor Hsia hatten.
where you had
Professor Hsia to back you up.
有夏教授支持你。
Mit Sturheit macht man sich keine Freunde.
Being stubborn
won't make you any friends.
固执己见不会让你交到任何朋友。
Diesmal sind es die neuen Büromöbel.
This time
it's the new office furniture.
这次是新的办公家具。
Das nächste Mal geht es um den Neubauvertrag.
Next time it'll be
the new building contract.
下次将是新的建筑合同。
Es wird kein Ende nehmen.
There'll be no end to it.
这件事将永无尽头。
Hast du ihn noch nicht durchschaut?
Haven't you figured him out yet?
你还没搞清楚他吗？
Sie sind die letzte Person auf seiner Liste.
You're the last person on his list.
你是他名单上的最后一个人。
Gott weiß, wie viele andere noch daran beteiligt sind.
God knows
how many others are involved.
天知道还有多少人参与其中。
Was wisst ihr Frauen schon?
What do you women know?
你们女人知道什么？
Er muss seine eigenen Probleme haben. Ich werde versuchen, mit ihm zu reden.
He must have his own problems.
I'll try to talk to him.
他肯定有他自己的问题。我会试着和他谈谈。
Bist du verrückt? Ming kam heute zur Schule, aber ...
Are you crazy?
MING CAME TO SCHOOL TODAY, BUT...
你疯了吗？MING 今天来上学了，但是……
Warum musstest du es mit ihm aufnehmen?
Why'd you have to take him on?
你为何要接受他的挑战？
Lasst uns ihn suchen. Wir versuchen es auf dem Basketballplatz.
Let's go find him.
We'll try the basketball court.
我们去找他吧。我们去篮球场试试。
Scheiße! Was ist das?
Shit! What's that?
妈的！那是什么？
- Folgen Sie mir, wenn Sie die Eier dazu haben. - Das ist Selbstmord, Mann!
- Follow me if you have the balls.
- It's suicide, man!
- 有胆量就跟我来。 - 这简直是自杀，老兄！
Selbstmord? Ich werde es ihnen zeigen!
Suicide? I'll show them!
自杀？我要让他们看看！
Nimm das!
Take that!
拿着！
Und das!
And that!
还有那！
Es ist nutzlos.
It's useless.
没用的。
Dieses Messer ist für Mädchen.
This knife is for girls.
这把刀是给女孩用的。
Sie werden dich auslachen.
They'll laugh at you.
他们会嘲笑你。
Wo hast du es her?
Where'd you get it?
你從哪買到的？
Auf dem Dachboden, mit allem anderen.
In the attic,
with all the rest of it.
和其他所有东西一起在阁楼里。
Bleib ruhig. Bleib bei deinen Bändern.
Cool it.
Stick to your tapes.
冷静一下。坚持你的录音带。
Ich habe eine Idee. Lass uns Mama um Hilfe bitten.
I've got an idea.
Let's get Ma's help.
我有个主意。让我们寻求妈妈的帮助。
Pst, ihr seid echt dicht.
Sh, you guys are dose.
嘘，你们太厉害了。
Warum andere Leute um einen Gefallen bitten?
Why ask other people
for favors?
为什么要向别人求助？
Wir müssen Rache nehmen, verdammt!
We gotta get revenge,
damn it!
我们必须报仇，该死的！
Leihen Sie sich wenigstens sein Samurai-Schwert.
At least borrow
his samurai sword.
至少借他的武士刀。
Was ist los?
What's up?
这是怎么回事？
Das ist es, was ich wissen möchte.
That's what I want to know.
这正是我想知道的。
Cat sagte, du wolltest mich.
Cat said you wanted me.
猫说你想要我。
Nein, habe ich nicht.
No, I didn't.
不，我没有。
Warum das lange Gesicht?
Why the long face?
脸怎么这么长？
Ist es ein Mädchen?
Is it a girl?
是女孩嗎？
NEIN.
No.
不。
Ich habe dir gesagt, dass es das nicht ist.
I told you it wasn't that.
我告诉过你事实并非如此。
Sich über ein Mädel aufzuregen sieht nicht gut aus.
Getting worked up
over some chick looks bad.
为某个小妞而兴奋看起来很糟糕。
Verstehen?
Understand?
理解？
Schauen Sie, was mit Honey passiert ist.
Look what happened to Honey.
看看 Honey 发生了什么事。
Jeder auf der Straße hatte Angst vor ihm.
Everyone on the street
was scared of him.
街上的每个人都怕他。
Und dann endet es, alles wegen irgendeinem Mädchen, damit –
Then, all because
of some chick, he ends up -
然后，全因为一个小妞，他最终——
Ist es Tiger?
Is it Tiger?
是老虎嗎？
NEIN.
No.
不。
Das ist gut.
That's good.
那挺好的。
Laden Sie es.
Load it.
加载它。
Jetzt festhalten und nach oben zielen.
Now hold on tight and aim up.
现在抓紧并瞄准。
Mach weiter.
Go on.
继续。
Fühlt sich toll an, oder?
Feels great, huh?
感觉很棒吧？
Entladen und ein neues einsetzen.
Unload and put in a new one.
卸下并放入新的。
Geh da rüber, Mann.
Go over there, man.
去那边吧，伙计。
Scheiße, ich zeige dir, was für eine tolle Zeit!
Shit, I'm showing you
a good time!
妈的，我让你玩得开心极了！
Also?
Well?
出色地？
Hast du einen Kuss von ihr bekommen?
Did you get a kiss out of her?
她吻了你吗？
All das und nicht einmal ein Kuss?
All this and not even a kiss?
发生这一切，却连一个吻都没有？
Sie hat es dir nicht erlaubt?
She wouldn't let you?
她不让你去吗？
Mach weiter.
Go on.
继续。
Bring Jade nach hinten.
Take Jade around back.
带着 Jade 绕回去。
Beeil dich-
Hurry UP-
赶快-
Es wird ihr nichts ausmachen.
She won't mind.
她不会介意的。
Scheiße! Was ist das?
Shit! What is this?
妈的！这是什么？
Ich gebe mir alle Mühe für Sie, und Sie –
I'm bending over backwards
for you, and you -
我会尽我所能帮你，而你——
Vergiss es.
Forget it.
忘了它。
Knödel und Brötchen!
Dumplings and buns!
饺子和包子！
Sir, wohin gehen Sie?
Si'r, where are you going?
先生，您要去哪儿？
Ich werde nicht einmal antworten!
Won't even answer!
甚至不回答！
Kleiner Punk! Pass auf, wo du hintrittst!
Little punk!
Watch where you're going!
小混蛋！注意你往哪儿走！
Ich liebe die Nacht...
I love the night...
我愛夜間...
Sie nörgelt immer!
She's always nagging!
她总是唠叨！
Ich kann ihr Nörgeln nicht ertragen!
I can't stand her nagging!
我受不了她的唠叨！
Pech gehabt!
Tough shit!
真糟糕！
Schon wieder? Überstunden machen?
You again?
Working extra hours?
你又来了？加班吗？
Etwas Geld verdienen?
Making some money?
赚点钱吗？
Jeder Cent zählt.
Every penny counts.
每一分钱都很重要。
Warum so viel verdienen? Für eine Frau sparen?
Why make so much?
Saving it for a wife?
干嘛挣那么多？攒着给老婆？
Nicht so einer wie deiner. Du darfst nicht mal zu Hause trinken.
Not one like yours.
You can't even drink at home.
和你的不一样。你甚至不能在家喝酒。
Was machst du? Benimm dich nicht wie ein Rowdy!
What are you doing?
Don't act like a hooligan!
你在干什么？别像流氓一样！
Komm mir nicht zu nahe!
Don't come near me!
别靠近我！
Sergeant Chad.!
查德中士！
- Was ist es? - Komm schnell!
- What is it?
- Come quick!
- 怎么了？ - 快来！
Noch ein Herzinfarkt. Schonen Sie sich.
Another heart attack.
Take it easy.
又心脏病发作了。放轻松。
Du bist sicher schwer.
You sure are heavy.
你确实很重。
Ich hatte Angst, dass Sie Schwierigkeiten haben würden, diesen Ort zu finden.
I was afraid you'd have trouble
finding this place.
我担心你会很难找到这个地方。
Xiao Sir.
Xiao Si'r.
Lasst uns Mao Zedong töten! Häutet Zhou Enlai!
Let's kill Mao Zedong!
Skin Zhou Enlai!
杀毛泽东！剥周恩来的皮！
Erobern wir das Festland zurück!
Let's take back the mainland!
夺回大陆吧！
Pferdewagen!
Horsecart!
马车！
Wie viele Fahrzeuge haben Sie? - Viele.
How many vehicles you got?
- Plenty.
你有多少辆车？ - 很多。
Du musst vorsichtig sein.
You gotta be careful.
你一定要小心。
Sie vertrauen den Fahrern? - Das sind alles unsere Leute.
You trust the drivers?
- They're all our people.
你信任司机吗？ - 他们都是我们的人。
Gut.
Good.
好的。
Wer ist dieser Junge? - Er ist bei mir.
Who's that kid?
- He's with me.
那孩子是谁？ - 他和我在一起。
Warum hast du es ausgeschaltet?
Why'd you turn it off?
你为何把它关掉？
Ich habe es nicht getan.
I didn't.
我没有。
Das Einstellen hat ewig gedauert.
It took forever to tune.
花了很长时间进行调整。
Jetzt muss ich ganz von vorne anfangen.
Now I have to start all over.
现在我必须一切重新开始。
Warum hast du meine Comics verwendet?
Why'd you use
my comic books?
你为什么要用我的漫画书？
Ich habe überall nach ihnen gesucht.
I looked all over for them.
我到处寻找它们。
Wissen Sie, wie lange es dauert, das abzustimmen?
You know how long
it takes to tune this?
您知道调整这个需要多长时间吗？
Geh und lass es reparieren, ja?
Go get it fixed, will you?
去把它修好好吗？
Eisdiele Little Park
LITTLE PARK ICE CREAM PARLOR
小公园冰淇淋店
Was machst du?
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
- Verdammt, Blinder! - Verdammt noch mal!
- Damn you, Blind Man!
- Goddamn it!
- 该死的盲人！ - 该死的！
Fahr zur Hölle!
Go to hell!
去死吧！
Egoistischer Bastard!
Selfish bastard!
自私的混蛋！
Du hast mich ausgenutzt!
You took advantage of me!
你利用了我！
Nehmen Sie Ihre Unterlagen mit!
Take your records with you!
带上你的记录！
Ich will sie nicht!
I don't want them!
我不要它们！
Es wird dir leid tun, wenn ich tot bin!
You'll be sorry when I'm dead!
我死了你就会后悔的！
Du nichtsnutziger, schamloser Bastard!
You no-good,
shameless bastard!
你这个不要脸的、没良心的混蛋！
Jede Frau, die dich berührt, ist verflucht!
Any woman
who touches you is cursed!
任何碰你的女人都会受到诅咒！
Betrüger! Arschloch! Du bist kein Mann!
Cheat! Asshole!
You're not a man!
骗子！混蛋！你不是男人！
Du hast einen tollen Zeitpunkt gewählt, um der Gang beizutreten -
You picked a great time
to join the gang -
你选择了一个加入帮派的好时机——
die Nacht eines Taifuns!
the night of a typhoon!
台风之夜！
Nicht einmal Baldy ist aufgetaucht.
Even Baldy hasn't shown up.
甚至连秃头都没有出现。
Ka Wu ist losgegangen, um ihn zu holen. Warum so nervös?
Ka Wu's gone to get him.
Why so jittery?
嘉武去接他了。干嘛这么紧张？
Wo gehst du hin?
Where you going?
你要去哪儿？
Um zu kacken.
To take a shit.
拉屎。
Lassen Sie uns nicht im Stich.
Don't out out on us.
别对我们发脾气。
Der Taifun kommt. Warum habt ihr nicht dichtgemacht?
The typhoon's coming.
Why haven't you closed up?
台风来了，你们怎么还不关门？
Nutzloser alter Wichser. Geh nach Hause und wichs!
Useless old motherfucker.
Go home and jerk off!
没用的老混蛋。回家手淫吧！
Fick dich!
Fuck you!
去你的！
Entspannen.
Relax.
放松。
Der Strom ist ausgefallen.
The power's out.
停电了。
Wie kommt es, dass niemand da ist?
How come no one's around?
怎么没人呢？
Passt beide auf die Hintertür auf.
You two go watch the back door.
你们两个去看守后门。
Was machen wir mit diesem Kerl?
What do we do about this guy?
我们该怎么对待这个家伙？
Können wir jetzt zurückgehen?
Can we go back now?
我们现在能回去吗？
Leg das Hackmesser weg!
Put that cleaver down!
把那把切肉刀放下！
Alles in Ordnung?
You all right?
你还好吗？
Geh ihnen nach!
Go after them!
去追他们！
Die Initiation beginnt und du schläfst zu Hause!
The initiation's starting
and you're home asleep!
入会仪式已经开始，而你却在家睡觉！
- Es war Mahjong. - Mahjong, von wegen!
- It was mahjong.
- Mahjong my ass!
- 这是麻将。 - 麻将啊！
Du schuldest mir noch was vom letzten Mal, weißt du noch?
You still owe me from last time,
remember?
上次你还欠我人情，记得吗？
Lass uns danach noch ein Spiel spielen.
Let's play another game
afterwards.
之后我们再玩另一个游戏吧。
Bruder Wu!
Ka Wu!
騷哥！
Bruder Wu!
Ka Wu!
騷哥！
Wissen Sie, wie einsam das Leben sein kann?
Do you know
how lonely life can be?
你知道生活有多孤独吗？
Du weißt, wie es sich anfühlt
You know what it feels like
你知道那是什么感觉
in den Tiefen der Verzweiflung?
in the depths of despair?
陷入绝望的深渊？
Dann bring dich um!
Then go kill yourself!
那就去自杀吧！
Du bist eine verdammte Plage.
You're a fuckin' drag.
你真是个累赘。
Niemand respektiert mich.
No one respects me.
没有人尊重我。
Was bringt das Leben? Ich bin besser dran, wenn ich tot bin.
What's the use of living?
I'm better off dead.
活着有什么用？死了还好。
Bitte leih mir das. Hilf mir –
Please let me borrow that.
Help me -
请借我一下。帮帮我——
Laufen!
Run!
跑步！
Verrückt...
Crazy...
疯狂的...
Hast du Honey getötet?
Did you kill Honey?
你杀了 Honey 吗？
Shandong!
山东！
Verrückt...
Crazy...
疯狂的...
Shandong!
山东！
Bitte steh AUF!
Please get UP!
请站起来！
Komm, steh auf.
Come on, get up.
来吧，起来吧。
Shandong!
山东！
Ich könnte schwören, dass er „... einen helleren Sommertag“ singt.
I could swear he sings
“...a brighter summer day.”
我敢发誓他唱的是“...更明亮的夏日”。
Aber ist das grammatikalisch korrekt?
But is that grammatically correct?
但这从语法上来说正确吗？
Herr Zhang.
Mr. Zhang.
张先生。
Was ist das?
What is it?
它是什么？
Könnten wir das morgen während der Bürozeiten machen?
Could we do this tomorrow
during office hours?
我们明天办公时间可以做这件事吗？
Es ist eine ziemlich ungewöhnliche Angelegenheit ...
It's a rather unusual matter...
这是一件相当不寻常的事情...
In Ordnung.
All right.
好的。
Lass mich eine Jacke holen.
Let me get a jacket.
让我去拿一件夹克。
Ist es etwas, was Sir getan hat?
Is it something Si'r did?
这是小四做的事情吗？
Die Bewohner im Südwesten Taiwans sollten auf Überschwemmungen vorbereitet sein.
Residents in southwest Taiwan
should be prepared for floods.
台湾西南地区居民应做好防洪准备。
Menschen auf Schiffen in der Nähe von Taiwan
People on ships
in the vicinity of Taiwan
台湾附近船只上的人员
sollte auch auf der Hut sein...
should also be on the alert...
也应该提高警惕...
Geh du ins Bett. Ich warte auf Morn.
You go to bed.
I'll wait up for Morn.
你去睡觉吧。我等莫恩。
Mama ist zu Herrn Wang gegangen. Sie war zwei Stunden weg.
Mom went to Mr. Wang's house.
She's been gone two hours.
妈妈去王先生家了。她已经走了两个小时了。
Leute kamen und nahmen Papa mit.
People came and took Dad away.
人们来了，把爸爸带走了。
Ich glaube, sie waren bei der Geheimpolizei.
I think they were
with the Secret Police.
我认为他们是秘密警察。
Du bist klatschnass! - Ich habe meinen Regenmantel vergessen.
You're soaking wet!
- I forgot my raincoat.
你浑身都湿透了！——我忘了​​带雨衣。
Es scheint Ihnen an innerer Ruhe zu mangeln.
You seem to lack inner calm.
你似乎缺乏内心的平静。
Erzähl mir nicht von deiner Religion.
Don't give me your religion.
别告诉我你的宗教信仰。
Ich habe ein ehrliches Leben geführt.
I've lived an honest life.
我过着诚实的生活。
Ich habe nichts zu verbergen.
I have nothing to hide.
我没什么可隐瞒的。
Daran haben wir keinen Zweifel.
We have no doubt of that.
我们对此毫不怀疑。
Darf ich dann gehen?
May I go, then?
那我可以走了吗？
Ich muss zur Arbeit.
I have to go to work.
我得去上班了。
Ruhen Sie sich lieber erst einmal ein wenig aus.
You'd better rest a bit first.
你最好先休息一下。
Geht es hier wieder um Professor Hsia?
Is this about
Professor Hsia again?
这又是关于夏教授的事吗？
Wir haben gestern Abend nur ein Element angesprochen.
We only touched
on one element last night.
昨晚我们只讨论了一个元素。
Hier.
Here.
这里。
Entspannen.
Relax.
放松。
Schreiben Sie, was Sie fühlen. Halten Sie sich nicht zurück.
Write what you feel.
Don't hold back.
写下你的感受。不要隐瞒。
Ich habe Musik studiert und bin ein künstlerischer Typ.
I studied music.
I'm an artistic type.
我学的是音乐。我属于艺术型的人。
In dieser Hinsicht sind Sie mir wirklich überlegen.
You're really my superior
in that regard.
从这方面来说你确实比我强。
Ich verstehe wirklich, wie sich gebildete Menschen fühlen.
I really do understand
how educated people feel.
我确实理解受过教育的人的感受。
Nun, ich lasse Sie eine Weile allein.
Well, I'll leave you alone
for a while.
好吧，我就让你独自呆一会儿。
Oh, noch etwas.
Oh, one other thing.
哦，还有一件事。
Es gibt kein richtiges Schild, aber Rauchen ist nicht gestattet.
There's no actual sign,
but smoking's not allowed.
虽然没有实际标志，但不允许吸烟。
Tut mir leid, das sind die Regeln.
Sorry. it's the rules.
抱歉，这是规则。
Aber vorher -
But before -
但在此之前——
Das Blut und die Tränen, die ich für dich vergieße, kennen kein Ende
The blood and tears
I shed for you know no end
我为你流的血和泪是无尽的
Als ich das rote Bohnensymbol meiner Sehnsucht beiseite legte
As I cast aside the red bean
symbol of my longing
当我抛开象征渴望的红豆
Die Frühlingsweiden blühen ewig
The spring willows
bloom eternally
春杨柳永远盛开
Und Frühlingsblumen füllen meine bemalten Kammern
And spring flowers
fill my painted chambers
春花盛开在我的画室里
Mein Schlaf wird durch Wind und Regen gestört
My sleep's disturbed
by the wind and rain
风雨扰乱了我的睡眠
Prasseln auf dem Fliegengitter nach Einbruch der Dunkelheit
Pattering on the screen window
after dusk
黄昏后，纱窗啪啪作响
Ich kann meine neuen Sorgen nicht vergessen
I'm unable to forget
my new woes
我无法忘记新的困境
Oder meine alten Sorgen
Or my old sorrows
或者我的旧日悲伤
Ich kann meine empfindlichen Speisen nicht herunterschlucken
I can't swallow my delicate foods
我无法吞咽精致的食物
Und ich ersticke an der goldenen Brasenia-Suppe
And I choke
on the golden brasenia soup
我被金莼菜汤呛到了
Ich kann nicht glauben
I can't believe
我不敢相信
Wie zerbrechlich ich in meinem geblümten Spiegel aussehe
How frail I look
in my flowered mirror
我在花镜中显得多么脆弱
Ich kann meine gerunzelte Stirn nicht entspannen
I can't unfurrow
my knitted brow
我无法舒展紧锁的眉头
Und ich kann es nicht ertragen, noch eine weitere Träne fallen zu spüren
Nor bear to feel
another tear fall
不忍再落泪
Kennen Sie Li Nan-tien?
Do you know Li Nan-tien?
Äh... ja.
Uh... yes.
呃……是的。
College-Klassenkamerad.
College classmate.
大学同学。
Warum hast du es nicht aufgeschrieben?
So why didn't you write it down?
那你为什么不把它写下来呢？
Er ist nicht nach Taiwan gekommen. Wir haben den Kontakt verloren.
He didn't come to Taiwan.
We've lost contact.
他沒有來台灣。我們已失聯。
Nicht nach Taiwan gekommen?
Didn't come to Taiwan?
沒來台灣？
Kennen Sie Liang Jin-chen?
You know Liang Jin-chen?
你认识梁金晨吗？
Liang Jin-chen?
Ich glaube nicht, dass ich den Namen schon einmal gehört habe.
I don't think
I've heard the name before.
我认为我之前没有听说过这个名字。
Überlegen Sie es sich gut. Sind Sie sicher?
Think carefully. Are you sure?
仔细想想，你确定吗？
Ich glaube nicht.
I don't think so.
我不这么认为。
Denken Sie sorgfältig nach.
Think carefully.
仔细想想。
Im Juli 1939 begannen Sie in einer Buchhaltungsabteilung zu arbeiten.
In July 1939 you began work
in an accounting department.
1939 年 7 月，您开始在会计部门工作。
Wer hat Sie darauf vorbereitet, seinen Job zu übernehmen?
Who trained you
to take over his job?
谁训练你接替他的工作？
Oh ... Herr Liang.
Oh... Mr. Liang.
噢…梁先生。
Ein netter, dicklicher Typ mit einer Goldbrille.
A sort, chubby guy
with gold-rimmed glasses.
一个戴着金边眼镜的胖乎乎的男人。
Du erinnerst dich also. Warum hast du es nicht aufgeschrieben?
So you do remember.
Why didn't you write it down?
所以你确实记得。你为什么不把它写下来呢？
Ich habe nicht gelogen.
I wasn't lying.
我没有撒谎。
Wir arbeiten so hart, um die Wahrheit herauszufinden.
We work so hard
to learn the truth.
我们竭尽全力去寻找真相。
Etwas wegzulassen, von dem man weiß, ist dasselbe wie zu lügen.
Leaving out something you know
is the same as lying.
隐瞒自己知道的事情就等于说谎。
Kennen Sie Chao Nien-lu? – Nein.
You know Chao Nien-lu?
- No.
你认识赵念璐吗？ - 不认识。
Hsun Feng-shih? Kuo Li-an?
Hsun Feng-shih?
Kuo Li-an?
Ja.
Yes.
是的。
Psst, Chun-chuan?
Shh Chun-chuan'?
嘘，春川？
Shih Chun-chuan?
施俊铨？
Ja.
Yes.
是的。
Woher kennst du ihn?
How do you know him?
你怎么认识他的？
Er war ein Freund eines Kollegen.
He was a friend of a coworker.
他是一位同事的朋友。
Als wir zum ersten Mal nach Taiwan kamen,
When we first came to Taiwan,
刚来台湾的时候，
Ich habe ihm ein altes Fahrrad sehr günstig abgekauft
I bought an old bike
from him real cheap
我从他那里买了一辆很便宜的旧自行车
damit die Kinder zur Schule gehen konnten. Ich habe ihn nur einmal getroffen.
so the kids could get to school.
I only met him once.
这样孩子们就可以上学了。我只见过他一次。
Ein Reporter oder so etwas.
A reporter or something.
一名记者或类似的。
Sein Name war irgendwie seltsam. Deshalb erinnere ich mich daran.
His name was kind of odd.
That's why I remember it.
他的名字有点奇怪。所以我记住了。
Ist das alles?
Is that all?
就这些吗？
Ja.
Yes.
是的。
Warum hast du es nicht aufgeschrieben? Wer war der Kollege?
Why didn't you write it down?
Who was the coworker?
你为什么不记下来？那个同事是谁？
Herr Tseng.
Mr. Tseng.
曾先生。
Tseng Hung-yuan. – Wie schreibt man das?
Tseng Hung-yuan.
- How do you write that?
曾宏元：这个怎么写？
„Hung“ wie in „Schwan“.
“Hung” as in “swan.”
“Hung” 类似于“天鹅”。
Sie und Ihre Frau haben 1940 heimlich in Shanghai geheiratet.
You and your wife married secretly
in Shanghai in 1940.
1940年，您和您的妻子在上海秘密结婚。
Wir hatten Trauzeugen und ein Abendessen.
We had witnesses
and a dinner-
我们有证人和一顿晚餐-
Ohne Heiratsurkunde handelt es sich um eine heimliche Ehe.
Without a marriage certificate,
it's a secret marriage.
没有结婚证，就是秘密结婚。
Wir haben uns im Rathaus angemeldet und wir -
We registered at city hall,
and we -
我们在市政厅登记了，然后我们——
Hat Professor Hsia Sie Ihrer Frau vorgestellt?
Did Professor Hsia
introduce you to your wife?
夏教授有把您介绍给您的妻子吗？
Nein, wir haben uns auf einem Tanz kennengelernt.
No, we met at a dance.
不，我们是在舞会上认识的。
Im Juni 1942 war Ihre Frau Grundschullehrerin.
In June of 1942, your wife
was teaching elementary school.
1942年6月，您的妻子正在小学教书。
Warum ist sie zurückgetreten?
Why did she resign?
她为什么辞职？
Meine älteste Tochter wurde geboren.
My eldest daughter was born.
我的大女儿出生了。
Mein Gehalt reichte damals völlig aus.
My salary was enough
at the time.
那时我的工资就够了。
Ich wollte lieber, dass sie sich um das Baby kümmert.
I preferred to have her
care for the baby.
我更愿意让她照顾孩子。
Ist das der einzige Grund?
Is that the only reason?
这是唯一的原因吗？
Darin heißt es, dass sie im Alter von 11 Jahren zu ihrem Onkel nach Shanghai ging.
This says she left for her uncle's
in Shanghai at age 11.
上面说她 11 岁时就离开家去上海她叔叔家了。
Sollte da nicht „der Schwager ihres Vaters“ stehen?
Shouldn't it say
her father's brother-in-law?
难道不应该说她父亲的姐夫吗？
Also, ich -
Well, I -
嗯，我——
Ihnen scheint die Inspiration zu fehlen.
You seem to lack inspiration.
你似乎缺乏灵感。
Es gibt vieles, woran Sie sich noch nicht erinnern.
There's much
you still don't recall.
还有很多事情你还是不记得了。
Keine Sorge. Wir haben alle Zeit der Welt.
Don't worry. We have
all the time in the world.
别担心。我们还有充足的时间。
Du wächst so schnell. Halte den Atem an.
You grow so fast.
Hold your breath.
你长得真快。屏住呼吸。
Erinnere mich daran, es heute Abend für dich rauszulassen.
Remind me to let it out
for you tonight.
提醒我今晚把它给你放出来。
Was ist mit deinem Alten passiert?
What happened
with your old man?
你老爸怎么了？
Wie meinst du das?
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
Hat er in der Nacht nach dem Streit etwas bemerkt, als Sie nach Hause kamen?
That night after the fight, did he notice
anything when you got home?
那天晚上吵架之后，你回家时他有注意到什么吗？
Nein, er war mit meiner Mutter ins Kino gegangen.
No, he'd gone to a movie
with my mom.
不，他和我妈妈去看电影了。
Wow, deine Schwester ist echt cool!
Wow, your sister's really cool!
哇，你姐姐真酷！
Danke.
Thanks.
谢谢。
Bewegen.
Move.
移动。
Ich habe das Bild mit dem Messer gefunden.
I found that picture
with the knife.
我找到了那张拿着刀的照片。
Sie muss es bei einem Liebesselbstmord verwendet haben.
She must have used it
in a love suicide.
她肯定是用它来自杀了。
Hör auf, es anzustarren. Nimm es, wenn du willst.
Quit staring at it.
Take it if you want.
别再盯着它了。如果你想要的话就拿去吧。
Hey, ich habe mit Horsecart gesprochen! - Wozu?
Hey, I talked to Horsecart!
- What for?
嘿，我和 Horsecart 谈过了！- 为什么？
Ich habe ihm gesagt, ich bin dein Kumpel. Er wird uns helfen.
I told him I'm your buddy.
He'll help us.
我告诉他我是你的朋友。他会帮助我们的。
Stehen Sie gerade.
Stand up straight.
站直。
Zwingen Sie mich nicht, mich zu wiederholen.
Don't make me repeat myself.
别让我重复自己的话。
Hast du das?
You got that?
你明白了吗？
Hier ist niemand.
There's no one here.
这里没有人。
Ich wusste, dass du hier sein würdest.
I knew you'd be here.
我知道你会在这里。
Was du mir letztes Mal erzählt hast ...
What you told me last time...
你上次告诉我的...
hast du es wirklich so gemeint?
did you really mean it?
你真的是这个意思吗？
Ich hoffe, Sie haben nicht gelogen.
I hope you weren't lying.
我希望你没有撒谎。
Das könnte ich nicht ertragen.
I couldn't bear that.
我无法忍受这一点。
Es ist schon wieder Samstag.
It's Saturday again.
又到了星期六。
Willst du den Unterricht schwänzen?
Want to cut class?
想逃课吗？
Nein, wir haben alle Zeit der Welt.
No, we have all the time
in the world.
不，我们拥有充足的时间。
Der Frühling verschwindet
Spring disappears
春天消失了
Ohne eine Spur
Without a trace
无踪无迹
Nichts zurücklassen ...
Leaving nothing behind...
沒有任何留下什麼...
Bist du hier für deine Aufnahme? Geh da rüber.
Here for your shot?
Go over there.
来这里打针吗？去那边。
Entschuldigen Sie sich bei ihnen.
Apologize to them.
向他们道歉。
Mach weiter!
Go on!
继续！
Soll ich dich dazu bringen?
Want me to make you?
想要我帮你做嗎？
Wichser!
Motherfucker!
混蛋！
Ist das gut genug?
Is that good enough?
这样够好吗？
Vergiss es. Lass uns gehen.
Forget it. Let's go.
算了，走吧。
Keine Chance!
Not a chance!
没机会了！
Passen Sie von nun an einfach auf, wo Sie hintreten.
Just watch your step
from now on.
从现在起你只要小心行事就行了。
Worüber freuen Sie sich so?
What are you so pleased about?
你为什么这么高兴？
Repariere mich mit Airplane!
Fix me up with Airplane!
帮我修好飞机！
Katze ist süßer.
Cat is cuter.
猫比较可爱。
Ich möchte Airplane kennenlernen!
I want to meet Airplane!
我想见见飞机！
Ich will auch eins!
I want one too!
我也想要一个！
Sie müssen in der Verteidigung aggressiver sein.
You need to be
more aggressive on defense.
你需要在防守上更积极主动。
Lass ihn nicht vorbeikommen. Die nächsten beiden.
Don't let him get by.
Next two.
别让他过去。接下来两个。
Halten Sie zur Verteidigung die Arme ausgestreckt. Weiter.
Keep your arms out on defense.
Go on.
防守时请伸出双臂。继续。
Welche Verbindung besteht zwischen Ihnen und Wang Kuo-cheng?
What's your connection
to Wang Kuo-cheng?
你跟王国成什么关系？
Wang?
王？
Er ist...
He's...
他是…
ein Klassenkamerad.
a classmate.
一个同学。
„Wang“?
“Wang”?
“王”？
Sie scheinen ihn gut zu kennen.
You seem to know him well.
看来你很了解他。
Nun ja... nicht wirklich.
Well... not really.
嗯...不是真的。
Ich sehe ihn ab und zu bei Klassentreffen.
I see him now and then
at class reunions.
我偶尔在同学聚会上见到他。
Hier.
Here.
这里。
Mehr schreiben?
Write more?
写多点儿？
Ich werde vor Sonnenaufgang zurück sein, um es abzuholen.
I'll be back for it before dawn.
我会在黎明前回来取它。
Ich bin fast fertig.
I'm almost done.
我快完成了。
Geben Sie mir noch etwas Zeit.
Give me a little more time.
再给我一点时间。
Das reicht. Du kannst jetzt gehen.
That's enough.
You can go now.
够了，你可以走了。
Beeil dich-
Hurry UP-
赶快-
- Beeil dich. - Mein Knopf ist wieder abgefallen.
- Hurry up.
- My button fell off again.
- 快点。 - 我的纽扣又掉了。
- Hat deine Schwester es nicht gerade für dich repariert? - Ja.
- Didn't your sister just fix it for you?
- Yes.
- 你姐姐不是刚刚帮你修好了吗？ - 是的。
Frau Zhang.
Mrs. Zhang.
张太太。
Hast du Sicherheitsnadeln?
Do you have safety pins?
你有安全别针吗？
Du solltest besser gehen, sonst kommst du zu spät.
You better go or you'll be late.
你最好走吧，不然你就迟到了。
Ist mein Hemd gebügelt?
Is my shirt ironed?
我的衬衣熨好了没有？
Ich muss zur Arbeit.
I have to go to work.
我得去上班了。
So ist es besser.
It's better this way.
这样比较好。
Sie haben jemanden im Büro gefunden, der meine Arbeit übernimmt.
They found someone at the office
to take over my work.
他们在办公室找了一个人来接替我的工作。
Weniger Arbeit bedeutet weniger Ärger.
Less work means less trouble.
工作越少，麻烦就越少。
Sie glauben, es hängt mit Ihrem Verhör zusammen?
You think it's related
to your interrogation?
你认为这和你的审讯有关吗？
Sagen Sie nichts ohne Beweise.
Don't say things with no proof.
不要说没有证据的话。
Wie dumm kann man sein?
How stupid can you be?
你怎么这么蠢？
Haben sie nicht auf ein Geständnis über Wang gewartet, bevor sie Sie freigelassen haben?
Weren't they waiting for a confession
about Wang before they'd release you?
他们不是要等你承认王的罪行后才释放你吗？
Ich dachte, er wollte uns helfen.
I thought
he was trying to help us.
我以为他正试图帮助我们。
So wie ich das sehe ...
The way I see it...
我是这样看待它的...
er hat versucht, sich von Ihnen zu distanzieren.
he was trying
to dissociate himself from you.
他正试图与你断绝关系。
Sie sind zu ehrlich, um seine Korruption zu vertuschen.
You're too honest
to cover up his corruption.
你太诚实了，无法掩盖他的腐败行为。
Was ist das für eine verrückte Idee?
What kind of crazy idea is that?
这是什么样的疯狂想法？
Bist du nicht zu ihm gegangen, während ich festgehalten wurde?
Didn't you go to him
while I was being held?
我被关押期间你没去找他吗？
Hat er nicht sein Bestes getan, um zu helfen?
Didn't he do his best to help?
难道他没有尽力帮忙吗？
Vielleicht hat er nur so getan. Vielleicht steckte er hinter der ganzen Sache.
Maybe he was pretending.
Maybe he was behind the whole thing.
也许他是在假装。也许他是整个事件的幕后黑手。
Und die Beförderung, die er Ihnen verschafft hat –
And that promotion he got you -
他帮你升职了——
Ihr Frauen!
You women!
你们这些女人！
Von Freundschaft zwischen Männern wissen Sie nichts!
You know nothing
about friendship between men!
你对男人之间的友谊一无所知！
Wozu sind Sie gut, außer misstrauisch zu sein?
What are you good for
besides being suspicious?
你除了多疑之外还有什么好处？
Für uns war es schon hart genug.
It's been tough enough
for us already.
对于我们来说这已经够艰难了。
Du und die Kinder sind alles, was mir geblieben ist.
You and the kids
are all I have left.
我剩下的只有你和孩子们了。
Bitte erschrecken Sie mich nicht mehr.
Please don't frighten me anymore.
请不要再吓唬我了。
Wir haben jetzt nur noch einander.
We only have each other now.
现在我们只有彼此。
Wenn Sie keine Angst haben, habe ich auch keine.
If you're not afraid,
then I won't be.
你若不怕，我亦不怕。
Was ist los, Tiger?
What's the matter, Tiger?
发生什么事了，老虎？
Komm schon, sprich.
Come on, speak up.
来吧，说出来。
Du solltest zumindest mit ihm reden.
You should at least talk to him.
你至少应该和他谈谈。
Haben Sie Angst, dass er versucht, sich an Ihnen zu rächen?
You worried
he'll try to get back at you?
你担心他会报复你吗？
Er wird es nicht tun.
He won't.
他不会。
Es ist vorbei.
It's over.
结束了。
Lassen wir ihn fallen, okay?
Let's drop him, okay?
咱们放下他，好吗？
Wie kommt es, dass du mir nie von ihm erzählt hast?
How come you never
told me about him?
你为什么从来没有跟我说过他的事情？
Was gibt es zu erzählen?
What's there to tell?
有什么可说的？
Viele Jungs haben Vorstellungen von mir.
Lots of guys have ideas about me.
很多人对我有自己的想法。
Haben Sie nicht genug gehört?
Haven't you heard enough?
你还没听够吗？
Nehmen wir zum Beispiel den jungen Arzt.
Take the young doctor,
for example.
以那位年轻的医生为例。
Konntest du das nicht erkennen?
Couldn't you tell?
你难道看不出来吗？
Wie fühlen Sie sich, wenn ich Ihnen diese Dinge erzähle?
How do you feel
when I tell you these things?
当我告诉你这些事情时你有何感觉？
Kannst du sie nicht einfach ignorieren?
Can't you just ignore them?
你就不能忽略他们吗？
Sie können von anderen nicht verlangen, das zu tun, was Sie für richtig halten.
You can't ask others to do
what you think is right.
你不能要求别人做你认为正确的事。
Die Leute werden auf Sie herabsehen.
People will look down on you.
人们会看不起你。
Du meinst, du wirst auf mich herabsehen.
You mean
you'll look down on me.
你的意思是你会瞧不起我。
Wer ist da?
Who's there?
谁在那儿？
Lao Er, Sir, stehen Sie auf!
Lao Er, Si'r, get up!
老二、四儿，快起来！
Da ist ein Dieb!
There's a thief!
有小偷！
Lao Er, steh auf, beeil dich!
Lao Er, get up, hurry!
老二，快起来啊！
Lao Er!
老二！
Schau nach, ob die Haustür geöffnet wurde. Beeil dich!
See if the front door's
been opened. Hurry!
看看前门是否打开了。快点！
Die Vordertür ist in Ordnung.
The front door's fine.
前门没问题。
Bist du sicher?
You sure?
你确定吗？
Ja.
Yes.
是的。
Nimm das!
Take this!
拿着！
Er versteckt sich.
He's hiding.
他躲起来了。
Er versteckt sich draußen.
He's hiding outside.
他躲在外面。
Unmöglich! Überprüfe das Dach!
Impossible!
Check the roof!
不可能！检查一下屋顶！
- Hol die Taschenlampe. - Wo ist sie?
- Get the flashlight.
- Where is it?
- 拿到手电筒。 - 它在哪里？
Beeil dich!
Hurry!
匆忙！
- Wo ist es? - In der Küchenschublade. Schnell!
- Where is it?
- In the kitchen drawer. Hurry!
- 它在哪儿？ - 在厨房抽屉里。快点！
Ich kann es nicht finden.
I can't find it.
我找不到它。
Warum machst du nicht ein paar Lichter an?
Why don't you turn on some lights?
你为什么不开灯呢？
Was ist das für ein Lärm? Ich versuche zu schlafen!
What's with all the noise?
I'm trying to sleep!
怎么这么吵？我想睡觉！
Er versteckt sich unter dem Bett.
He's hiding under the bed.
他躲在床底下。
Er stand genau hier und war dann plötzlich verschwunden!
He was standing right here
and then suddenly vanished!
他就站在这里，然后突然消失了！
Das kann nicht sein! Ich habe ihn hier gesehen!
It can't be!
I saw him right here!
不可能！我亲眼看见他了！
Wie konnte er einfach verschwinden?
How could he just vanish?
他怎么会就此消失呢？
Er konnte nicht entkommen!
He couldn't have gotten away!
他不可能逃脱！
Lass sie erstmal ruhen. Alles ist unter Kontrolle.
Let her rest for now.
Everything's under control.
让她暂时休息一下。一切都在掌控之中。
Zum Glück hast du sie rechtzeitig hergebracht.
Luckily you rushed her over
in time.
幸亏你及时赶到了她。
Habe ich sie nicht vor Holzkohlerauch gewarnt?
Didn't I warn her
about charcoal smoke?
我不是警告过她有关木炭烟的事吗？
Seit der Antike lieben die Chinesen Kamelien
Since ancient times
the Chinese have loved camellias
中国人自古以来就喜爱山茶花
für ihre Eleganz und raffinierte Schönheit.
for their elegance
and refined beauty.
因其优雅和精致的美丽。
Die Kinder spielten hier
The kids used
to play around here
孩子们过去常常在这里玩耍
und die Blumen pflücken, als sie klein waren.
and pick the flowers
when they were little.
并在他们小时候采摘花朵。
Das erinnert mich an deinen Großvater.
This reminds me
of your grandfather.
这让我想起了你的祖父。
Die Blüten wecken schöne Erinnerungen an ihn.
The blossoms bring back
happy memories of him.
这些花儿使他回想起快乐的时光。
Wer ist diese Dame?
Who's that lady?
那位女士是谁？
Meinen Sie Hsiang-li?
You mean Hsiang-li?
您指的是香梨吗？
Wir heiraten im September.
We're getting married
in September.
我们将于九月结婚。
Ich mag sie nicht.
I don't like her.
我不喜欢她。
Sie ist seltsam.
She's strange.
她很奇怪。
Zwischen euch herrscht keine Liebe. Sie ist nicht für dich.
There's no love between you.
She's not for you.
你们之间没有爱情。她不适合你。
Ihr Kinder versteht so etwas nicht.
You kids don't understand
such things.
你们这些孩子不懂这些事情。
Sie müssen nichts sagen, wenn Sie nicht möchten.
You don't have to say anything
if you don't want to.
如果你不想说的话，你什么都可以不说。
Warum denkst du, dass ich das nicht verstehe?
Why do you think
I don't understand?
你为什么认为我不明白？
Liebe ist kein Spaß und kein Spiel.
Love isn't fun and games.
爱情不是玩乐。
Viele Jungs sagen, dass sie mich lieben,
Lots of guys say they love me,
很多男人说爱我，
Aber...
but...
但...
Sobald es Ärger gibt, laufen sie alle weg.
the minute there's trouble,
they all run away.
一旦有麻烦，他们全都逃跑了。
Wenn Sie über etwas beunruhigt sind,
If you're troubled about something,
如果你对某事感到烦恼，
Sie müssen es mir sagen, bevor ich Ihnen helfen kann.
you must tell me
before I can help you.
你必须先告诉我，我才能帮助你。
Ich werde es dir nicht sagen.
I won't tell you.
我不会告诉你。
Du würdest es mir nicht sagen, oder?
You wouldn't tell me, right?
你不会告诉我，对吧？
Machen Sie sich keine Sorgen um die Arztkosten Ihrer Mutter.
Don't worry about
your mother's medical expenses.
你妈妈的医疗费不用担心。
Wir sind zu nah dran, um uns über solche Dinge Sorgen zu machen.
We're too close
to worry about such things.
我们距离彼此太近，没必要担心这些事情。
Willst du es mir immer noch nicht sagen?
Still don't want to tell me?
还是不想告诉我吗？
Zhang Zhen.
Komm mal kurz her.
Come here a minute.
过来一下。
Dies ist zu Ihrem Besten.
This is for your own good.
这是为了你好。
Ich will nicht neugierig sein,
I don't mean to pry,
我不是有意打探，
aber für eine Liebesbeziehung in deinem Alter brauchst du gute Ratschläge.
but for a love affair at your age,
you need good advice.
但是对于你这个年龄的恋爱，你需要好的建议。
Du benimmst dich wie ein Hooligan, was?
Behaving like a hooligan, huh?
像流氓一样行事吧？
Stehen Sie aufrecht, wenn der Arzt spricht!
Stand up straight
when the doctor's talking!
医生讲话时请站直！
Verdammte Schlampe.
Motherfucking bitch.
他妈的婊子。
Was seid ihr? Die Geheimpolizei?
What are you?
The secret police?
你们是谁？秘密警察？
Was hast du gerade gesagt?
What did you just say?
你刚才说什么？
Sag das noch einmal. Was hast du gesagt?
Say that again.
What did you say?
再说一遍。你说什么？
Ich sagte, Sie sind von der Geheimpolizei.
I said you're the secret police.
我说你是秘密警察。
Davor. Über meine Mutter.
Before that.
About my mother.
在此之前，我要说一下我的母亲。
Versuch es noch einmal zu sagen! - Verdammte Schlampe!
Try saying it again!
- Fucking bitch!
再说一遍！- 他妈的婊子！
Was ist los?
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
Was ist das hier?
What's this here?
这是什么？
Ihre Schüler benehmen sich wie ein Haufen Hooligans.
Your students act
like a bunch of hooligans.
你的学生表现得就像一群流氓。
Unflätig und gewalttätig!
Foul-mouthed and violent!
满口脏话，暴力十足！
Mädchen daten und mit Beziehungen herumspielen!
Dating girls and messing around
with relationships!
与女孩约会并搞乱关系！
- Kümmere dich um deinen eigenen Scheißkram! - Zhang Zhen!
- Mind your own fucking business!
- Zhang Zhen!
— 管好你自己的事！— 张震！
Zum Verhaltensbüro!
To the conduct office!
到行为办公室！
Na und! Wen interessiert das?
Big deal! Who cares?
有什么大不了的！谁在乎呢？
Sie haben letztes Mal einige harte Worte über uns verloren.
You had some harsh words
about us last time.
上次你对我们说了一些刻薄的话。
Wie steht es mit Ihrer elterlichen Aufsicht?
What about
your parental guidance?
您的父母指导怎么样？
So eine vulgäre Sprache! Sogar mir war es peinlich.
Such foul language!
Even I was embarrassed.
这么粗俗的语言！连我都感到很尴尬。
Ihr Eltern macht eure Arbeit nicht und gebt uns dann die Schuld.
You parents don't do your job
and then blame it on us.
你们这些父母没有尽到责任，然后又把责任推到我们身上。
Du hast Nerven!
You have some nerve!
你还真有胆量！
Bitte geben Sie ihm noch eine Chance.
Please give him another chance.
请再给他一次机会。
Zu spät!
Too late!
为时已晚！
Er ist schon so weit gefallen. Wenn wir ihn nicht angemessen bestrafen,
He's fallen this far already.
If we don't punish him properly,
他已经堕落到这个地步了。如果我们不好好惩罚他，
Sie werden uns erneut vorwerfen, dass wir unsere Arbeit nicht gemacht haben.
you'll blame us again
for not doing our job.
你会再次责怪我们没有做好工作。
Ich möchte dafür nicht verantwortlich sein.
I don't want to be
responsible for that.
我不想为此负责。
Es war meine Nachlässigkeit.
It was my negligence.
这是我的疏忽。
Kinder verlieren manchmal den Kopf.
Kids sometimes lose their heads.
孩子们有时会失去理智。
Bitte entschuldigen Sie ihn nur dieses eine Mal.
Please excuse him just this once.
请原谅他这一次。
Wenn er dafür noch einen Tadel bekommt,
If he gets
another demerit for this,
如果他因此再次被扣分，
er kann nicht in die nächste Klasse wechseln.
he can't move on
to the next grade.
他不能升入下一个年级。
Das wäre...
That would be...
那将是...
zu unfair ihm gegenüber.
too unfair to him.
对他来说太不公平了。
Unfair? Fanden Sie uns letztes Mal nicht unfair?
Unfair? Didn't you think
we were unfair last time?
不公平？你不觉得我们上次很不公平吗？
Haben Sie nicht gesagt, dass Ihnen Tadel egal seien?
Didn't you say
you didn't care about demerits?
你不是说你不在乎缺点吗？
Wie kommt es, dass es dir jetzt wichtig ist?
How come you care now?
你怎么现在才关心呢？
Wir arbeiten alle für dieselbe Regierung.
We all work
for the same government.
我们都为同一个政府工作。
Was macht dich so hochnäsig?
What makes you
so high and mighty?
你凭什么这么趾高气扬？
Herr Zhang, kaufen Sie Brötchen!
Mr. Zhang, buy some buns!
张先生，买点包子吧！
Was ist los? Schlechte Laune?
What's wrong?
In a bad mood?
怎么了？心情不好吗？
Mach dir keine Sorge!
Don't worry!
不用担心！
Morgen wird die Sonne wieder aufgehen.
The sun will rise again tomorrow.
明天太阳还会再次升起。
Eine lebendige Seele wird nie durch einen Furz erstickt, oder?
A lively soul is never
stifled by a fart, right?
一个活泼的灵魂是不会被一个屁扼杀的，对吧？
Knödel und Brötchen!
Dumplings and buns!
饺子和包子！
Keine Sorge, Papa. Von der Schule zu fliegen ist nicht so schlimm.
Don't worry, Dad.
Getting expelled isn't that bad.
别担心，爸爸。被开除并不是那么糟糕。
So kann ich diesen Sommer an der Übertrittsprüfung teilnehmen.
This way I can take
the transfer exam this summer.
这样我今年夏天就可以参加转学考试了。
Ich werde dich in die Tagesschule bringen.
I'll get into day school for you.
我会帮你进入日校。
Mach dir keine Sorgen um mich, Papa.
Don't worry about me, Dad.
爸爸，别担心我。
Ich erinnere mich an alles, was du gesagt hast.
I remember everything you said.
我记得你说的每一句话。
Ich werde dir immer zuhören.
I'll always listen to you.
我会一直听你的。
Ich erinnere mich, dass Sie sagten, die eigene Zukunft
I remember you said
one's own future
我记得你说过自己的未来
kann durch eigene Anstrengungen ermittelt werden.
can be determined
by one's own efforts.
都可以通过自己的努力来决定。
Ich habe ihn mit dem Schläger geschlagen, weil er zu weit gegangen ist,
I hit him with the bat
because he went too far,
我用球棒打了他，因为他走得太远了，
genau wie letztes Mal, als du -
just like last time when you -
就像上次你一样——
Wenn ich mit dem Rauchen aufhöre,
If I quit smoking,
如果我戒烟，
das Geld, das ich jeden Monat spare ...
the money I save every month...
我每个月存的钱...
wird ausreichen, um dir eine Brille zu kaufen
will be enough
to buy you glasses
足够给你买眼镜了
auf dem Ratenzahlungsplan.
on the installment plan.
分期付款。
Also, wann sehen wir uns wieder?
So when will we see
each other again?
那么我们什么时候可以再见面？
Nicht bevor ich die Transferprüfungen abgelegt habe.
Not until I've taken
the transfer exams.
直到我参加完转学考试之后。
Du kannst jederzeit in die Schule kommen, um mich zu besuchen.
You can always come
to school to see me.
你可以随时来学校看我。
Wenn ich das nächste Mal durch das Schultor gehe, werde ich ein Tagesschüler sein.
Next time I enter the school gate,
I'll be a day school student.
下次我走进校门时，我将是一名走读学生。
Klingt wie Honey, als er sagte, er würde nach Tainan zurückkehren.
Sounds like Honey when he said
he was going back to Tainan.
听起来就像 Honey 说他要回台南一样。
Du bist nicht glücklich.
You're not happy.
你不开心。
Ich werde mir Sorgen um dich machen.
I'll be worried about you.
我会担心你的。
Sei nicht albern. Lerne fleißig.
Don't be silly. Study hard.
别傻了，好好学习。
Ich stehe voll und ganz hinter Ihnen.
I'm behind you all the way.
我会一直支持你。
Aber lass uns heute nicht gehen, okay?
But let's not go today, okay?
不过我们今天就不要去，好吗？
Alles ist arrangiert.
Everything's all arranged.
一切都安排好了。
Außerdem sind Katze und Flugzeug beide eingeladen.
Plus Cat and Airplane
are both invited.
此外，Cat 和 Airplane 也均受邀请。
Oh je! Unser Diener hat gekündigt.
Oh, dear!
Our servant has quit.
噢，天哪！我们的仆人辞职了。
Entschuldigen Sie, dass ich nicht früher vorbeigekommen bin, um Hallo zu sagen.
Sorry I didn't come out
earlier to say hello.
抱歉我没有早点出来打招呼。
Keine Sorge, wir helfen uns selbst.
Don't worry.
We'll help ourselves.
别担心，我们会自己解决的。
Ist das dein Klassenkamerad?
Is this your classmate?
这是你的同学吗？
Sie ist so hübsch.
She's so pretty.
她真漂亮。
Als ich mit ihm schwanger war, wollte ich ein Mädchen.
When I was carrying him,
I wanted a girl.
当我怀着他的时候，我想要一个女孩。
Schauen Sie, wie groß er jetzt ist.
Look how big he is now.
看看他现在有多大了。
Da bist du schon wieder!
There you go again!
你又来了！
Nehmen Sie die Füße vom Tisch.
Take your feet off the table.
把脚从桌子上拿开。
Wo sind die anderen?
Where are the others?
其他人在哪儿？
- Reichweite? - 640 Meter.
- Range?
- 700 yards.
— 范围？— 700 码。
- Wie viele? - Ein Zug.
- How many?
- A platoon.
- 多少？ - 一个排。
Zu weit. Es reicht nicht.
Too far. It won't reach.
太远了。够不着。
Benutze meins.
Use mine.
用我的。
Scheiße! Die haben Panzer!
Shit! They've got tanks!
妈的！他们有坦克！
Es ist okay. Wir haben Granaten.
It's okay.
We've got grenades.
没关系，我们有手榴弹。
Wer geht da hin? Passwort!
Who goes there? Password!
谁在那里？密码！
Kommunistische Frau. Hände hoch.
Commie woman.
Hands up.
共产主义女人。举起手来。
- Was machst du? - Mädchen stehen nicht auf so etwas.
- What are you doing?
- Girls aren't into this stuff.
- 你在做什么？ - 女孩不喜欢这些东西。
Bleib zurück!
Stay back!
退后！
Kopf hoch, ja?
Cheer up, will you?
振作起来好吗？
Bedeutet meine Nachdenklichkeit nichts?
Doesn't my thoughtfulness
mean anything?
难道我的体贴就没有任何意义吗？
Ein Schulverweis ist keine große Sache.
Getting expelled from school
is no big deal.
被学校开除没什么大不了的。
Du kümmerst dich nicht einmal um deine eigene Freundin.
You don't even look
after your own girlfriend.
你连自己的女朋友都不照顾。
Die Regierungskarriere Ihres Vaters
Your father's government career
你父亲的政府生涯
ist deswegen zum Scheitern verurteilt
is doomed because of it
注定失败
und wegen seiner Beziehungen zu Professor Hsia.
and because of his relations
with Professor Hsia.
以及他和夏教授的关系。
Ich bin stolz auf euch alle, Kinder, dass ihr durchgehalten habt.
I'm proud of all you kids
for pulling through.
我为你们这些坚持下来的孩子感到骄傲。
Besonders Sir.
Especially Si'r.
尤其是小四。
Er ist so entschlossen, nach allem, was passiert ist, wieder auf die richtige Bahn zu kommen.
He's so determined to get back
on track after all that's happened.
经历了这一切之后，他决心重新回到正轨。
Mama, nach dem Abschluss werde ich eine Weile arbeiten, bevor ich ins Ausland gehe.
Mom, after graduation,
I'll work a while before going abroad.
妈妈，我毕业后会先工作一段时间再出国。
Nein, Sie gehen, sobald Sie Ihr Stipendium bekommen.
No, you go as soon as you get
your scholarship.
不，你一拿到奖学金就可以去。
Aber Lao Er geht aufs College, und außerdem gibt es noch Si'r und den Jüngsten.
But Lao Er's going to college,
plus there's Si'r and the youngest one.
可是老二要上大学，而且还有四儿和最小的一个。
Es ist zu viel für dich.
It's too much for you.
这对你来说太过分了。
Bis jetzt ist uns das gelungen.
We've managed up to now.
我们已经成功做到了现在。
Machen Sie sich keine Sorgen, bis Sie es in Amerika geschafft haben.
Don't worry until
you've made it in America.
在你到达美国之前别担心。
Vier Pfund Reis.
Four pounds of rice.
四磅大米。
Kannst du das auf Kredit buchen, Onkel Fat?
Can you put this on credit,
Uncle Fat?
你能把这记在账上吗，胖叔叔？
Kein Problem.
No problem.
没问题。
Darf ich mich einmischen?
May I butt in?
我可以插嘴吗？
Viele Leute sagen, ich sei zu neugierig,
Many people say I'm too nosy,
很多人说我太爱管闲事，
aber eigentlich bin ich Ihrem Mann sehr ähnlich.
but I'm actually
a lot like your husband.
但事实上我很像你的丈夫。
Sie haben konservierte Eier?
You have preserved eggs?
你有皮蛋吗？
Da drüben.
Over there.
在那边。
Dein SH hat mir das Leben gerettet.
Your SH saved my “fie.
你的 SH 拯救了我的“fie。
Ich denke, jetzt bin ich an der Reihe, Ihnen zu helfen.
I think it's my turn to help you.
我想现在该轮到我来帮助你了。
Onkel Fat sagte, Herr Lin sei gebürtiger Taiwaner.
Uncle Fat said Mr. Lin
is native Taiwanese.
胖叔说，林先生是土生土长的台湾人。
Ein sehr ehrlicher Mann.
A very honest man.
非常诚实的人。
Er gründet ein Obstexportunternehmen.
He's starting
a fruit export business.
他正在开展水果出口业务。
Er braucht einen Partner mit formaler Ausbildung.
He needs a partner
with formal education.
他需要一个受过正规教育的伴侣。
Das Anfangsgehalt ist vielleicht nicht viel,
The starting salary
may not be much,
起薪可能不多，
aber wenn Sie hart arbeiten, werden Sie Ihr eigener Herr.
but if you work hard,
you'll be your own man.
但只要你努力工作，你就会成为你自己的主人。
Was ist, wenn er in einem Monat bankrott geht?
What if he goes bankrupt
a month from now?
如果他一个月后破产了怎么办？
Sprechen Sie zuerst mit ihm. Fühlen Sie sich gegenseitig aus.
Talk to him first.
Feel each other out.
先和他谈谈。互相了解一下。
Man kann einem Mann nicht misstrauen, ohne ihn zu kennen.
You can't doubt a guy
without knowing him.
你不能在不了解一个人的情况下怀疑他。
Ich habe mein ganzes Leben für die Regierung gearbeitet.
I've worked
for the government all my life.
我一生都在为政府工作。
Ich bin an die Stabilität und Sicherheit gewöhnt.
I'm used
to the stability and security.
我已经习惯了这种稳定和安全。
Glauben Sie wirklich, dass das stabil und sicher ist?
You really think
this is stable and secure?
你真的认为这是稳定和安全的吗？
Ich wollte es heute abschicken, wenn Sie nicht aufgetaucht wären.
I was gonna mail it today
if you didn't show up.
如果你没出现的话，我今天就会把它寄出去。
Hast du deiner Freundin Hausschuhe mitgebracht, Cat?
Did you bring your friend
some slippers, Cat?
凯特，你给你的朋友带了拖鞋吗？
Warum bin ich da rausgegangen?
What did I go out there for?
我出去干什么？
Warum hast du es ausgeschaltet?
Why'd you turn it off?
你为何把它关掉？
Das klingt furchtbar! An wen schickst du es?
It sounds awful!
Who are you mailing it to?
听起来太糟糕了！你要把它寄给谁？
Das wirst du später herausfinden.
You'll find out later.
您稍后就会发现。
Wie läuft es in der Schule? Alles okay?
How's school?
Everything okay?
学校怎么样？一切都还好吗？
Das Gleiche wie immer. Nichts ändert sich jemals.
Same as always.
Nothing ever changes.
和往常一样。没有任何变化。
Hast du Ming kürzlich gesehen?
You seen Ming lately?
最近你见过 Ming 吗？
Ihr geht es gut!
She's fine!
她很好！
Konzentrieren Sie sich einfach auf Ihre Bücher.
Just concentrate
on your books.
只需专心于你的书即可。
Ich und Airplane werden auf sie aufpassen.
Me and Airplane
will look after her.
我和飞机会照顾她。
Chiung, komm und hilf mir.
Chiung, come give me a hand.
琼，来帮我一下。
Onkel Fats Familie wird um 7:00 hier sein.
Uncle Fat's family
will be here at 7:00.
胖叔叔一家七点钟就会来。
Würdest du bitte den Tisch abräumen?
Clear the table, would you?
你能把桌子收拾一下吗？
Wo ist sie?
Where's Sh'?
她在哪？
Ich habe ihn ins Kino geschickt.
I sent him to the movies.
我送他去看电影。
„Die Rechnung mit Sly wird bis heute beglichen sein.“
“The score with Sly
will be settled by this day.”
“今天，斯莱的账就算算了。”
Listig?
Sly?
狡猾？
Er ist seit Ewigkeiten nicht mehr vorbeigekommen.
He hasn't come around in ages.
他已经很久没有回来了。
Er verschwand, nachdem er dem Massaker entkommen war.
He disappeared
after he escaped the massacre.
他在逃过那场大屠杀后就失踪了。
Seinetwegen haben sie seinen alten Herrn gefeuert.
They fired his old man
because of him.
他们因为他而解雇了他的父亲。
Sie halten politische Versammlungen im Auditorium ab,
They hold political meetings
in the auditorium,
他们在礼堂举行政治会议，
aber Außenstehende können es nicht mehr mieten.
but outsiders
can't rent it anymore.
但外来者不能再租用它。
Ich habe es am schlimmsten erwischt.
I got the worst of it.
我遭遇了最坏的情况。
Mein Geschäft ist den Bach runtergegangen.
My business has gone to hell.
我的生意彻底完了。
Die verdammten Bullen kommen ständig vorbei.
The damn cops
come round all the time.
该死的警察总是来。
Schon schließen?
Closing up already?
已经打烊了嗎？
Scheiße! Schau mal, wer da ist!
Shit! Look who's here!
天啊！看看是谁来了！
S?r.
S? r.
是。
Jade sagte, sie habe dich in der Bibliothek gesehen.
Jade said she's been
seeing you at the library.
杰德说她在图书馆见过你。
Du wurdest auch von der Schule geflogen?
You got kicked
out of school too?
你也被学校开除了吗？
Du scheinst wirklich anders zu sein.
You seem really different.
你看上去确实与众不同。
Bewegen Sie Ihre Füße.
Move your feet.
移动你的脚。
Das war mir damals echt zu viel...
I was really too much back then...
我那时候真的是太过分了……
die ganze Zeit so angespannt.
wound up so tight all the time.
总是很紧张。
Es bringt mich zum Lachen!
It makes me laugh!
这让我笑了！
Lass dich von der Vergangenheit nicht unterkriegen, okay?
Don't let the past
get you down, okay?
别让过去的事情困扰你，好吗？
Ich fühle mich deswegen wirklich schlecht.
I feel really bad about it.
我对此感到非常难过。
Komm schon, Mann. Es war alles meine Schuld.
Come on, man.
It was all my fault.
拜托，哥们，这都是我的错。
Lassen Sie es gehen.
Let it go.
放手吧。
Auf welche Schule möchten Sie gehen?
What school
are you trying to get into?
你想考入哪所学校？
Ich versuche, die Aufnahmeprüfung für die Tagesschule zu bestehen.
I'm trying to test
into day school.
我正在努力通过考试进入日校。
Du hast Eier!
You got some balls!
你真有胆量！
Nicht einmal Militärakademien nehmen Punks wie mich auf.
Even military academies
won't take punks like me.
就连军事学院也不会接收像我这样的小混混。
Du und ich waren solche Feinde.
You and I were such enemies.
你和我曾经是仇敌。
Jetzt sitzen wir im selben Boot.
Now we're in the same boat.
现在我们处于同样的境况。
Sogar mit Freundinnen haben wir das gleiche Pech.
We even have the same
bad luck with girlfriends.
我们甚至在交女朋友方面也有同样的不幸。
Wie meinst du das?
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
Diese Mama!
That Ma!
那個妈！
Er ist wirklich glatt.
He's really slick.
他确实很狡猾。
Ich denke, Sie werden wie ich sein und es ihm nicht übel nehmen.
I figure you'll be like me
and not hold it against him.
我想你会像我一样，不会怨恨他。
Er hat mir Jade gestohlen.
He stole Jade from me.
他从我身边偷走了 Jade。
Jetzt macht er mit Ming rum.
Now he's messing around
with Ming.
现在他正在和明混在一起。
Wann meldest du dich zu den Prüfungen an?
When are you signing up
for the exams?
你什么时候报名参加考试？
Meine Mathe- und Englischkenntnisse sind miserabel -
My math and English
are the pits -
我的数学和英语很糟糕 -
S?r.
S? r.
是。
Bleiben wir in Kontakt.
Let's keep in touch.
让我们保持联系。
Wofür war das? Willst du Ärger, Arschloch?
What was that for?
You want trouble, asshole?
那是为了什么？你想惹麻烦吗，混蛋？
Leg dich mit mir an und ich rufe die Polizei!
Mess with me
and I'll call the cops!
敢惹我我就报警了！
Wichser! - Komm schon, vergiss es.
Motherfucker!
- Come on, forget it.
混蛋！——来吧，忘掉这件事吧。
- Wen willst du sehen? - Ist Mama zu Hause?
- Who are you here to see?
- Is Ma home?
- 你来见谁？ - 妈妈在家吗？
Warte hier.
Wait here.
在这儿等着。
Wie heißen Sie?
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
Herr.
Si'r.
先生。
Mist, lange her! Was hast du so gemacht?
Shit, it's been a long time!
What have you been up to?
妈的，好久不见了！你最近在忙些什么呢？
Das möchte ich Sie fragen.
That's what I want to ask you.
这就是我想问你的。
Ich bin immer noch der Alte. Was sonst?
I'm the same old me.
What else?
我还是老样子。还有什么？
Hey, wusstest du, dass Ming jetzt hier wohnt?
Hey, did you know
Ming's living here now?
嘿，你知道明现在住在这里吗？
Weißt du noch, als ihr vorbeigekommen seid?
Remember
when you guys came over
还记得你们来过的时候
und unser Dienstmädchen hatte gekündigt?
and our maid had quit?
我们的女佣辞职了吗？
Ming kam morgens zu mir, um zu sehen, ob ihre Mutter die Stelle übernehmen könnte.
Ming came to my morn to see
if her mother could fill the job.
明早上来找我，看看她妈妈是否能胜任这份工作。
Meine Mutter mag sie wirklich und hat ihrer Mutter den Job gegeben.
My morn really likes her
and gave her mother the job.
我妈妈非常喜欢她，并把这份工作给了她妈妈。
Ming ist nicht schlecht.
Ming's not bad.
明还不错。
Sie ist drinnen. Willst du reinkommen?
She's inside.
Want to come in?
她在里面。想进来吗？
Was höre ich da über dich und sie?
What's this I hear
about you and her?
我听到了关于你和她的什么事？
Wie meinst du das?
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
Mädels, es ist immer der gleiche alte Mist.
Girls. it's the same old shit.
女孩们，这都是同样的事情。
Zieh sie schön an, füttere sie gut, albere ein bisschen herum.
Dress 'em nice, feed 'em well,
fool around a bit.
给他们穿得漂亮，给他们吃好，玩一会儿。
Was gibt es sonst noch?
What else is there?
还有什么？
Du siehst nicht besonders glücklich aus.
You don't look too happy.
你看上去不太高兴。
Lass nicht zu, dass irgendein dummes Mädchen zwischen uns kommt, Kumpel.
Don't let some stupid girl
come between us, buddy.
别让这个愚蠢的女孩介入我们之间，哥们。
Es ist okay.
It's okay.
没关系。
Als ihr beide herumgealbert habt, hat sie Honey oft erwähnt ...
When you two were fooling around,
did she mention Honey a lot...
你们俩鬼混的时候，她有没有多次提到Honey……
und sagen, dass Sie ihr kein Gefühl der Sicherheit gegeben haben?
and say you weren't giving her
a sense of security?
并说你没有给她安全感？
Was ist los? Reg dich nicht wegen irgendeinem Mädchen auf!
What's wrong? Don't get
all worked up over some girl!
怎么了？别为了某个女孩子太兴奋啊！
Komm rein. Lass uns ein paar Runden schießen.
Come on in.
Let's shoot a few rounds.
进来吧，我们打几发吧。
Das ist okay. Ich gehe ins Kino.
That's okay.
I'm gonna catch a movie.
没关系。我要去看电影。
- Hast du Geld dabei? - Ein bisschen.
- Got any money on you?
- A little.
- 你身上有钱吗？ - 有一点。
Wie viel?
How much?
多少？
Wieviel brauchst du?
How much you need?
你需要多少？
Egal.
Never mind.
没关系。
Betrachten Sie es als ein Treffen mit Freunden zum Abendessen.
Look at it
as meeting friends for dinner.
将其视为与朋友共进晚餐。
Sei einfach entspannt.
Just be relaxed.
放松点。
Chuan, ich brauche meine Uhr.
Chuan, I need my watch.
川，我需要我的手表。
Ich habe es zurückgelegt.
I put it back.
我把它放回去了。
Nun, es ist nicht hier.
Well, it's not here.
嗯，它不在这里。
Onkel Fat ist hier.
Uncle Fat's here.
胖叔叔来了。
- Ich will gehen. - Ich bringe dir Kaugummi mit.
- I want to go.
- I'll bring you bubble gum.
- 我想去。 - 我会给你带泡泡糖。
Mieser Kaugummi!
Lousy bubble gum!
糟糕的泡泡糖！
Wie viele zum Abendessen?
How many for dinner?
晚餐吃多少人？
Si'r lernt in der Bibliothek.
Si'r is studying at the library.
四儿正在图书馆学习。
Wie wäre es mit Lao Er?
How about Lao Er?
老二呢？
Ich weiß nicht.
I don't know.
我不知道。
Er hatte in letzter Zeit einen guten Appetit.
He's had a good appetite lately.
最近他的胃口很好。
Was ist los?
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Du bist immer draußen, wenn Mama weg ist.
You're always outside
whenever Mom's gone.
妈妈不在家的时候你总是在外面。
Komm und iss dein Abendessen!
Come eat your dinner!
快来吃你的晚餐吧！
Ich habe noch keinen Hunger.
I'm not hungry yet.
我还不饿。
- Du hast es so gewollt! - Ich komme.
- You're asking for it!
- I'm coming.
- 这是你自己想要的！ - 我来了。
- Ist es jetzt eine Angewohnheit, Mamas Uhr zu stehlen? - Ich habe sie nicht genommen.
- Is stealing Mom's watch a habit now?
- I didn't take it.
- 偷妈妈的手表现在成习惯了吗？ - 我没有拿。
Sie bemerkte, dass es weg war! Was wirst du jetzt tun?
She noticed it was gone!
What will you do now?
她发现它不见了！你现在该怎么办？
Worum geht es?
What's this about?
这是关于什么的？
Das ist für Erwachsene. Halte dich da raus.
It's for grown-ups.
Stay out of it.
这是成年人的事。别管它。
Du bist so gemein!
You're so mean!
你真卑鄙！
Wo gehst du hin?
Where are you going?
你要去哪儿？
- Sind deine Eltern zu Hause? - Sie sind zum Abendessen ausgegangen.
- Are your folks home?
- They went out to dinner.
- 你的家人在家吗？ - 他们出去吃饭了。
- Was ist mit Lao Er? - Oh, nichts.
- What's with Lao Er?
- Oh, nothing.
- 老二怎么了？ - 噢，没什么。
Es ist schon ewig her. Geht es ihnen gut?
It's been ages.
Are they doing all right?
已经过去好久了。他们都还好吗？
Ich komme gleich vorbei und warte.
I'll come in a while and wait.
我过会儿就来等一下。
Wo sind all die Aschenbecher?
Where are all the ashtrays?
烟灰缸都在哪儿？
Papa hat mit dem Rauchen aufgehört.
Dad quit smoking.
爸爸戒烟了。
Benutzt du das Ding immer noch?
You still using this thing?
你还在用这个东西吗？
Es ist nutzlos!
It's useless!
没用的！
Weißt du, ich habe deinen Vater mitgenommen, um dieses Radio zu kaufen.
You know, I took your dad
to buy this radio.
你知道，我带你爸爸去买这个收音机。
Im Kaufhaus Wing On in Shanghai.
At the Wing On
department store in Shanghai.
在上海永安百货。
Ihr Morgen war noch nicht einmal so alt wie Sie jetzt sind.
Your morn wasn't even
as old as you are now.
你那时的年龄甚至还没有现在这么大。
Sie sollten diesen nutzlosen Müll wegwerfen.
You should throw
that useless junk away.
你应该把那些没用的垃圾扔掉。
Was hast du in der Kirchenbibliothek gemacht?
What were you doing
at the church library?
你在教堂图书馆做什么？
Meine Schwester hat mir davon erzählt. Und du?
My sister told me about it.
How about you?
我姐姐告诉我的。你呢？
Ich spiele, wenn es Zeit zum Spielen ist, und lerne, wenn es Zeit zum Lernen ist.
I play when it's time to play,
study when it's time to study.
该玩的时候就玩，该学习的时候就学习。
Also ist Chiung deine Schwester?
So Chiung is your sister?
那么 Chiung 是你的妹妹吗？
Sie ist sehr religiös.
She's really religious.
她确实很虔诚。
Wir waren beide einmal im Kirchenchor.
We were both
in the church choir at one point.
我们俩都曾参加过教堂唱诗班。
Was machen wir nach dem Film? - Irgendeinen Rock'n'Roll-Laden?
What'll we do after the movie?
- Some rock and roll joint?
看完电影后我们做什么？ - 去摇滚乐吧？
Nein, zu teuer.
No, too expensive.
不行，太贵了。
Du willst wie Mama sein? Sei nicht dumm.
You want to be like Ma?
Don't be stupid.
你想成为像马云那样的人吗？别傻了。
Hast du nicht aufgehört?
Didn't you quit?
你不是辞职了吗？
Wie wäre es mit 300 pro Spiel?
How about 300 a game?
每场 300 怎么样？
Scheiße! Du brauchst so dringend Geld?
Shit!
You need money that bad?
妈的！你就这么需要钱吗？
Dies ist eine echte Chance für Sie.
This is a real opportunity for you.
这对你来说是一个真正的机会。
Ich war von Herrn Lin beeindruckt. Er ist ehrlich und direkt.
I was impressed with Mr. Lin.
He's honest and direct.
林先生给我留下了深刻的印象。他很诚实，很直率。
Es ist Zeit, mit der Zögerlichkeit aufzuhören.
It's time to stop
dragging your feet.
现在是停止拖延的时候了。
Papa, Herr Wang war hier.
Dad, Mr. Wang was here.
爸，王先生来了。
Ich habe deinen Kaugummi vergessen!
I forgot your bubble gum!
我忘了你的泡泡糖！
Ich werde es das nächste Mal wiedergutmachen.
I'll make it up to you next time.
下次我会补偿你的。
Warum das traurige Gesicht? - Die große Schwester hat mich angeschrien.
Why the sad face?
- Big sister bawled me out.
为什么一脸悲伤？——姐姐大声呵斥我。
Hat sie das? Warst du unartig?
She did?
Were you naughty?
她真的这么做了？你太淘气了吗？
NEIN.
No.
不。
Warum hat sie das dann getan?
Then why'd she do that?
那她为什么要这么做？
- Wo ist Lao Er? - Er ist ausgegangen.
- Where's Lao Er?
- He went out.
- 老二呢？ - 他出去了。
Wo ist er hin?
Where'd he go?
他去哪儿了？
Kleine Göre! Du musstest einfach petzen, oder?
Little brat!
Just had to snitch, didn't you!
小混蛋！你就是想告密，不是吗！
Ich habe Sly gestern Abend gesehen.
I saw Sly last night.
我昨晚见到了史莱。
Er hat sich völlig verändert.
He's totally changed.
他完全变了。
Ich glaube, Menschen ändern sich wirklich.
I guess people really do change.
我想，人是确实会改变的。
Es war ein beruhigendes Gefühl.
It was a comforting feeling.
那是一种令人欣慰的感觉。
Was redest du da?
What are you going on about?
你到底在说什么？
Jade, können wir nah beieinander sein?
Jade, can we be close
to each other?
杰德，我们可以靠近一点吗？
Ich könnte Ihnen helfen, dasselbe zu empfinden.
I could help you feel
that same way.
我可以帮助您有同样的感受。
Brauchen Sie das nicht manchmal?
Don't you need that sometimes?
有时候你不需要这个吗？
Sie meinen es ernst, nicht wahr?
You're a serious one,
aren't you?
你是个认真的人，不是吗？
Hast du vorher nicht auf mich herabgeschaut?
Didn't you look down
on me before?
你之前不是还瞧不起我吗？
Eigentlich -
Actually -
实际上 -
Jetzt scheinen Sie mich unbedingt ändern zu wollen.
Now you seem eager
to change me.
现在你似乎急于改变我。
Bin ich Ihr kleines biologisches Experiment oder was?
Am I your little
biology experiment, or what?
我是你的小生物学实验吗？
Sie haben viele philosophische Ideen.
You have a lot
of philosophical ideas.
你有很多哲学想法。
Ich bin zufrieden, so wie ich bin, aber bist du es auch?
I'm happy with the way I am,
but are you?
我对自己现在的状态很满意，但是你呢？
Was passiert, wenn ich mich nicht ändere?
What if I don't change?
如果我不改变会怎么样？
Was passiert, wenn ich mich nicht Ihren Vorstellungen entsprechend verändere?
What if I don't change
to suit your ideas?
如果我不按照你的想法改变会怎么样？
Wirst du einfach weggehen?
Will you just walk away?
你就这么走开吗？
Du bist so egoistisch! Was glaubst du, wer du bist?
You're so selfish!
Who do you think you are?
你太自私了！你以为你是谁？
Jade, ich wollte dir nichts Böses tun.
Jade, I didn't mean any harm.
杰德，我没有恶意。
Danke übrigens für die Gerüchte, die du damals in die Welt gesetzt hast.
By the way, thanks for the rumors
you started back then.
顺便说一句，谢谢你当时开始散布的谣言。
Was für Gerüchte? Wann damals?
What rumors? Back when?
什么谣言？什么时候的事？
Dumm stellen?
Playing dumb?
装傻？
Als die 217 Jungen Sly in der Schule in die Enge trieben.
When the 217 boys
cornered Sly at the school.
当 217 名男孩在学校围住 Sly 时。
Haben Sie wirklich nicht gesehen, dass er mit Ming zusammen war?
Did you really not see
it was Ming he was with?
你真的没看出来他和明在一起吗？
Sly hatte Angst, dass Honey es herausfinden könnte.
Sly was scared
Honey might find out.
斯莱担心霍妮会发现。
Er ließ mich allen sagen, dass ich es war.
He made me tell everyone
it was me.
他让我告诉每个人那就是我。
Ich war so ein Idiot!
I was such an idiot!
我真是个白痴！
Warum halten Sie Ming nicht Ihre Philosophievorlesung?
Why don't you give Ming
your philosophy lecture?
你为什么不给明上一堂哲学课呢？
Sie ist mir um Längen voraus.
She's got me beat by a mile.
她远远地打败了我。
Du bist schamlos! Hoffnungslos!
You're shameless!
Hopeless!
你太不要脸了！太没救了！
Sag deinem Vater, dass es dir leid tut.
Tell your father you're sorry.
告诉你父亲你很抱歉。
Das reicht, Papa.
That's enough, Dad.
够了，爸爸。
Das reicht, Papa.
That's enough, Dad.
够了，爸爸。
Das reicht!
That's enough!
够了！
Papa, hör bitte auf!
Dad, please stop!
爸爸，请停下来！
Bitte hör auf!
Please stop!
请停止！
Kommen Sie besser später wieder.
You better come back later.
你最好晚点再回来。
Mama und Papa denken, du lernst in der Bibliothek.
Mom and Dad think
you're studying at the library.
爸爸妈妈以为你在图书馆学习。
Wenn sie herausfinden, dass Sie die Uhr genommen haben ...
If they find out
you took the watch...
如果他们发现你拿走了手表……
Ihr Unglück wird noch größer sein.
they'll be even more heartbroken.
他们会更加伤心。
Lao Er kam mit einer Menge Bargeld.
Lao Er came up
with a load of cash.
老二拿出了一​​大堆现金。
Er wollte die Uhr für Sie zurückkaufen ...
He wanted to buy back
the watch for you...
他想帮你买回这块手表……
aber Mama hat das Geld zuerst bei ihm gefunden.
but Mom found
the money on him first.
但妈妈先在他身上发现了钱。
Sie dürfen sich nicht allein fühlen.
You mustn't feel alone.
你一定不要感到孤独。
Ich bin immer bei dir.
I'm always with you.
我一直和你在一起。
Weise mich nicht noch einmal ab.
Don't turn me away again.
不要再拒绝我。
Lass Gott in dein Herz. Er wird dir seine Kraft geben.
Let God into your heart.
He'll give you his strength.
让上帝进入你的内心。他会赐予你力量。
Aber...
But...
但...
es gibt zu viel Leid ...
there's too much suffering...
有太多的痛苦……
zu viel Ungerechtigkeit.
too much injustice.
太多的不公正。
Geben Sie anderen nicht zu wenig Anerkennung
Aren't you giving others
too little credit
你是不是太不相信别人了
und immer nur an sich selbst denken?
and always thinking
only of yourself?
总是只想着自己？
Christus gab sein Leben
Christ gave his life
基督献出了生命
für unsere Sünden.
for our sins.
为了我们的罪孽。
Sogar Lao Er hat die Schuld für Ihre Fehler auf sich genommen.
Even Lao Er took the blame
for your wrongs.
连老二都替你背了罪。
Sie sollten Dankbarkeit für das zeigen, was andere für Sie getan haben.
You should show gratitude
for what others have done for you.
你应该对别人为你所做的一切表示感激。
Haben Sie jemals etwas für jemanden getan?
Have you ever done
anything for anyone?
你曾为任何人做过任何事吗？
Sie sollten es sich gut überlegen.
You should think it over carefully.
你应该仔细考虑一下。
Honey hat mir dasselbe erzählt.
Honey told me the same thing.
霍妮也告诉我同样的事情。
WHO?
Who?
WHO？
Egal.
Never mind.
没关系。
Ein guter Freund.
A good friend.
一个好朋友。
Haben Sie jemals Krieg und Frieden gelesen?
Have you ever read
War and Peace ?
你读过《战争与和平》吗？
Warum besprechen Sie das nicht morgen mit Reverend Chen?
Why don't you talk it over
with Reverend Chen tomorrow?
明天你去跟陈牧师商量一下好吗？
- Was ist los? - Wir sind noch nicht fertig.
- What's up?
- We're not finished yet.
- 怎么了？ - 我们还没有完成。
- Worum geht es hier? - Stell dich nicht dumm, Arschloch.
- What's this about?
- Don't play dumb, asshole.
- 这是怎么回事？ - 别装傻了，混蛋。
Fick dich, du gehst wegen irgendeinem Mädchen auf mich los!
Fuck you, going off on me
over some girl!
操你，为了某个女孩对我发火！
Bist du nicht mein Kumpel?
Aren't you my buddy?
你不是我哥们吗？
Machen Sie weiter wie eine alte Dame.
You go on like an old lady.
你继续像一位老太太一样。
Sie sagten, Sie hätten Mädchen für Bücher aufgegeben.
You said you'd given up
girls for books.
你说过你为了书籍放弃了女孩。
Jetzt fang an zu meckern. Du hast Nerven!
Now you start bitching.
You got some nerve!
现在你开始抱怨了。你还真有胆量！
Ich war immer gut zu dir. - Halt den Mund!
I've always been good to you.
- Shut your mouth!
我一直对你很好。——闭上你的嘴！
Halt den Mund und hör gut zu.
Shut your mouth and listen good.
闭上你的嘴，听好了。
Ich habe genug von Ihren Theorien über reiche Kinder.
I've had enough
of your rich-kid theories.
我已经受够了你的富家子弟理论。
Ab heute...
Starting today...
从今天开始...
Wenn ich höre, dass du immer noch mit Ming rumhängst,
if I hear you're still
hanging out with Ming,
如果我听说你还和 Ming 在一起
Ich bin hinter dir her!
I'm coming after you!
我来追你了！
Verdammter Punk! Du bist mein bester Freund!
Motherfuckin' punk!
I let you be my best friend!
混蛋！我让你成为我最好的朋友！
Scheiße! Vergiss nicht, mit wem du dich anlegst!
Fuck! Don't forget
who you're messing with!
操！别忘了你在跟谁混！
Ich warte auf dich, Kumpel!
I'll be waitin' for you, buddy!
我会等你的，朋友！
Ich werde dir in den Arsch treten!
I'll kick your ass!
我要踢你的屁股！
Ich habe überall nach dir gesucht. Bleib ruhig. Wir sind alle gute Freunde.
I've been looking all over for you.
Cool it. We're all good friends.
我一直在找你。没事的。我们都是好朋友。
Beruhige dich mir zuliebe, okay?
Cool it for my sake, okay?
为了我，冷静点，可以吗？
Lass uns darüber reden. Ich bringe ihn zu dir.
Let's talk it over.
I'll bring him to you.
我们讨论一下吧。我会带他给你。
Komm schon, Mann. Benimm dich nicht so.
Come on, man.
Don't act this way.
拜托，老兄，别这样。
Es lässt uns in einem schlechten Licht dastehen.
It makes us look bad.
这让我们看起来很糟糕。
Warte im Filmstudio.
Wait at the film studio.
在影棚等候。
Ich werde mit ihm reden. Ich werde ihn zu Ihnen bringen.
I'll go talk to him.
I'll bring him to you.
我会去和他谈谈。我会带他来见你。
Beruhige dich, mir zuliebe.
Cool it for my sake.
为了我，冷静一下。
Komm schon, Mann.
Come on, man.
来吧，伙计。
Lassen wir es für heute. Ich brauche Zeit, um mit ihm zu reden.
Let's drop it for today.
I need time to talk to him.
今天就到此为止吧。我需要时间和他谈谈。
Er brachte sein Samurai-Schwert zum Unterricht mit.
He brought
his samurai sword to class.
他带着他的武士刀来上课。
Lass es uns morgen machen, okay?
Let's do it tomorrow, okay?
我们明天再做吧，可以吗？
Geh nach Hause und kühl dich ab.
Go home and cool down.
回家冷静一下。
Tu es für mich, okay?
Do it for me, okay?
帮我做一下，可以吗？
Lass es uns morgen machen, okay?
Let's make it tomorrow, okay?
我们明天再来吧，可以吗？
Okay? Sicher?
Okay? For sure?
好嗎？确定吗？
Ich muss los. Ich bin zu spät zum Unterricht.
I gotta go.
I'm late for class.
我得走了。我上课要迟到了。
Dein Bruder ist noch nicht da?
Your brother's not here yet?
你哥哥还没來嗎？
Meine Familie sagte, er sei auf dem Weg.
My family said he was on his way.
我的家人说他正在路上。
Also...
Well...
出色地...
warten wir noch eine halbe Stunde.
let's wait another half hour.
我们再等半小时吧。
- Es tut mir leid, Reverend Chen. - Es ist okay.
- I'm sorry, Reverend Chen.
- It's okay.
- 对不起，陈牧师。 - 没关系
Nun... entschuldigen Sie.
Well... excuse me.
嗯...不好意思。
Hallo!
Hey there!
嘿！
Können Sie mir helfen, das junge Mädchen zu finden, mit dem Sie vorher zusammen waren?
Can you help me find
that young girl you were with before?
你能帮我找到你之前在一起的那个年轻女孩吗？
Sie ist nach dem Probedreh umgezogen.
She moved after the screen test.
试镜结束后她就搬家了。
Wissen Sie, wohin?
You know where to?
你知道去哪儿吗？
Sie weint und lacht und lässt alles natürlich aussehen!
She cries and laughs,
and makes it all look natural!
她哭、她笑，一切看起来都很自然！
Natürlich?
Natural?
自然的？
Man kann nicht einmal echt von falsch unterscheiden.
You can't even tell real from fake.
你甚至无法辨别真假。
Wie kann man Filme machen?
How can you make movies?
你怎么能拍电影呢？
Wissen Sie überhaupt, was zum Teufel Sie filmen?
You even know
what the hell you're filming?
你知道你到底在拍什么吗？
Die Katze ist in der Schule.
Cat's at school.
猫在学校。
Ich leihe mir nur ein Buch aus.
I'm just borrowing a book.
我只是借一本书。
Welches Buch?
What book?
什么书？
Ich weiß, wo es ist.
I know where it is.
我知道它在哪儿。
Wie kommt es, dass sein Fahrrad noch hier ist?
How come his bike's still here?
他的自行车怎么还在这里？
Seltsam. Normalerweise ist er der Erste, der hier rauskommt.
Strange. He's usually
the first one out of here.
奇怪。他通常是第一个离开这里的人。
Und?!
Si?!
和？！
Was ist los?
What's the matter?
怎么了？
Was führt Sie hierher zur Schule?
What brings you here to school?
你为什么来学校？
Was ist das?
What's that?
那是什么？
Hör auf, dich so zu benehmen. Was ist das?
Stop acting like this.
What's that?
别这样。那是什么？
Du bist wegen Mama hier.
You're here for Ma.
你是为了妈妈而来的。
Sag es mir! Bist du?
Tell me! Are you?
告诉我！你是吗？
Wie konntest du so etwas tun?
How could you do
a thing like that?
你怎么能做出这样的事？
Ich werde nicht zulassen, dass jemand auf dich herabsieht.
I won't let anyone
look down on you.
我不会让任何人瞧不起你。
Worüber redest du?
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Solltest du nicht zu Hause lernen?
Aren't you supposed
to be home studying?
你不是应该在家学习吗？
Ming, ich weiß alles über dich.
Ming, I know all about you.
明，你的事我都知道。
Aber es macht mir nichts aus.
But I don't mind.
但我不介意。
Weil nur ich es weiß.
Because only I know.
因为只有我知道。
Ich bin der Einzige, der Ihnen helfen kann.
I'm the only one
who can help you.
我是唯一一个可以帮助你的人。
Ich bin die einzige Hoffnung, die Ihnen noch bleibt.
I'm the only hope you have left.
我是你仅存的希望。
Genau wie Honey früher war.
Just like Honey used to be.
就像 Honey 以前那样。
Deshalb kannst du Honey immer noch nicht vergessen.
That's why
you still can't forget Honey.
所以你还是忘不掉亲爱的。
Denn im Moment bin ich ein weiterer Schatz.
Because right now,
I'm another Honey.
因为现在，我是另一个 Honey。
Du meinst, du bist der Einzige, der mir helfen kann, mich zu ändern, richtig?
You mean you're the only one
who can help change me, right?
你的意思是你是唯一一个可以帮助我改变的人，对吗？
Warum bist du wie alle anderen?
Why are you like all the rest?
为什么你和其他人一样？
Ich habe mich in dir geirrt. Du bist genau wie die anderen.
I was wrong about you.
You're just like the others.
我看错了你。你和其他人一样。
Du bist nett zu mir, damit ich auch nett zu dir bin.
You're nice to me
just so I'll be nice to you.
你对我好，我也会对你好。
Dann fühlen Sie sich sicher, oder?
Then you'll feel secure, right?
这样你就会感到安全了，对吧？
Du bist so egoistisch.
You're so selfish.
你太自私了。
Du willst mich ändern?
You want to change me?
你想改变我吗？
Ich bin wie diese Welt.
I'm like this world.
我就像这个世界。
Diese Welt wird sich nie ändern! Wer denkst du -
This world will never change!
Who do you think -
这个世界永远不会改变！你认为谁 -
Du bist ein hoffnungsloser Fall!
You're hopeless!
你真没救了！
Schamlos und hoffnungslos!
Shameless and hopeless!
无耻又无望！
Ming.
明。
Aufstehen.
Get up.
起床。
Schnell, steh auf.
Quick, get up.
快，起来。
Steh auf.
Get on your feet.
站起来。
Du wirst nicht sterben. Glaub mir.
You won't die. Believe me.
你不会死的。相信我。
Beeil dich und steh auf.
Hurry and get up.
赶紧起来吧。
Du kannst es schaffen.
You can do it.
你能做到。
Bitte steh auf.
Please get up.
请站起来。
Aufstehen!
Get up!
起床！
Warum stehst du nicht AUF?
Why won't you get UP?
你为什么还不起来？
Wo ist er?
Where is he?
他在哪里？
Ich suche meinen Bruder. Du hast die falsche Person!
I'm looking for my brother.
You got the wrong person!
我在找我弟弟。你找错人了！
Sie haben einen Fehler gemacht!
You've made a mistake!
你犯了一个错误！
Sie haben die falsche Person erwischt!
You got the wrong person!
你抓错人了！
Wo ist sie?
Where's Sh'?
她在哪？
Das ist also der Typ.
So that's the guy.
原来是他啊。
Seltsam. Das kenne ich nicht.
Strange.
I don't know this one.
奇怪。我不认识这个。
Zu welcher Gang gehört er?
What gang is he with?
他是哪个帮派的？
Ich kenne jedes dieser Arschlöcher in der Stadt.
I know every one
of these assholes in town.
我认识城里每一个混蛋。
„Liebe Schwester …“
“Dear Sis...”
“亲爱的姐姐……”
Das habe ich in seiner Tasche gefunden.
Found that in his pocket.
在他的口袋里发现了它。
"Es tut mir Leid.
“I'm sorry.
“对不起。
Ich weiß, dass du der Einzige bist, der es versteht.
I know you're the only one
who understands.
我知道只有你才明白。
Bitte helfen Sie, es Morn und Dad zu erklären ...
Please help explain
to Morn and Dad...
请帮忙向妈妈和爸爸解释一下……
für den Fall, dass ich dich nie wieder sehe.“
in case I never see you again.”
以防我再也见不到你。”
Wie heißt der kleine Trottel?
What's the little jerk's name?
那个小混蛋叫什么名字？
Kann nicht mal seinen Namen schreiben. Habe ein lustiges Gesicht gezeichnet!
Can't even write his name.
Drew a funny face!
甚至不会写他的名字。画了一张搞笑的脸！
Was ist sein Problem?
What's his problem?
他有什么问题？
XIAO Sl'R
肖思乐
Steh auf. Zeit für eine Veränderung.
Get up.
Time to change.
站起来。该改变了。
Aufstehen.
Get up.
起床。
Steh auf und zieh dich um!
Get up and get changed!
快起床换衣服！
Du kleiner Punk!
You little punk!
你这个小混蛋！
Sie gehört mir!
She's mine!
她是我的！
Du kannst sie nicht wegnehmen!
You can't take her away!
你不能把她带走！
Das kannst du nicht machen!
You can't do this!
你不能这么做！
Es gehört meinem alten Herrn. Frag ihn, wo er es her hat.
It belongs to my old man.
Ask him where he got it.
这是我老爸的。问问他从哪儿弄来的。
Ich habe ihn nicht gefragt!
I didn't ask him!
我没问他！
Ich frage dich!
Fm asking you!
我在问你！
Warum hast du dieses Schwert zum Unterricht mitgebracht?
Why'd you bring
this sword to class?
你为什么把这把剑带到课堂上？
Ich weiß, dass Sie in all das verwickelt sind!
I know
you're mixed up in all this!
我知道你也参与了这一切！
Wir kennen Ihren Vater gut.
We know your father well.
我们很了解你的父亲。
Können Sie nicht einfach kooperieren?
Can't you just cooperate?
你就不能合作一下吗？
Das ist mein Sohn! Was tust du ihm an?
That's my son!
What are you doing to him?
那是我儿子！你对他做了什么？
Das ist unerhört! Wir sind eine anständige Familie!
This is outrageous!
We're a respectable family!
这太过分了！我们可是受人尊敬的家庭啊！
Ein unschuldiges Kind so zu behandeln!
Treating an innocent child
like this!
这样对待一个无辜的孩子！
Der neuste Bericht:
The latest report:
最新报道：
Die Mutter des Mädchens hat gerade Selbstmord begangen.
The girl's mother
just committed suicide.
女孩的母亲刚刚自杀。
Wer hat hier das Sagen?
Who's in charge here?
这里谁是负责人？
Das bin ich! Ich bin hier der Boss!
I am! I'm the boss here!
是的！我是这里的老板！
Jetzt geh raus!
Now you get out!
现在你就出去！
- Wie kannst du es wagen, so mit mir zu reden! - Raus!
- How dare you speak to me like that!
- Out!
- 你怎么敢这样跟我说话！ - 出去！
Wer ist dieser Mann? Ich will seinen Namen!
Who is that man?
I want his name!
那人是谁？我想知道他的名字！
Wie heißt er?
What's his name?
他叫什么名字？
Schreiben Sie seinen Namen auf!
Write down his name!
写下他的名字！
Er war der einzige Freund, den ich hatte.
He was the only friend I had.
他是我唯一的朋友。
Und jetzt...
And now...
现在...
Wir haben gehört, dass die Mutter des Mädchens versucht hat, sich das Leben zu nehmen.
We heard the girl's mother
tried to kill herself.
我们听说女孩的母亲试图自杀。
Erzählen Sie uns davon.
Tell us about it.
请告诉我们。
Lass uns mit ihr reden.
Let us talk to her.
让我们和她谈谈。
Jeder möchte wissen, was wirklich passiert ist.
Everyone wants to know
what really happened.
每个人都想知道到底发生了什么。
Sie versuchte, sich das Leben zu nehmen, indem sie ihren goldenen Ring verschluckte.
She tried to kill herself
by swallowing her gold ring.
她试图吞下金戒指自杀。
Viel mehr weiß ich wirklich nicht.
I really don't know much else.
我确实不太了解其他的事情。
Bitte seien Sie rücksichtsvoll.
Please be considerate.
请您体谅。
Kennst du den Jungen?
Do you know the boy?
你认识那個男孩嗎？
Bleib ruhig. Die Mutter hat überlebt. Keine große Sache.
Relax. The mother survived.
No big deal.
放心吧。母亲活了下来。没什么大不了的。
Ich habe gehört, Sie hatten eine Affäre mit dem Mädchen.
I heard you had
an affair with the girl.
我听说你和那个女孩有染。
Irgendwelche Kommentare? - Wir haben dasselbe gehört.
Any comment?
- We heard the same thing.
有什么评论吗？ - 我们听到了同样的事情。
Was? Hast du keinen Anstand?
What?
Have you no decency?
怎么？你就这么没礼貌吗？
Raus hier! Alle!
Get out! All of you!
全部都出去！
Was glaubst du, wer du bist? Raus!
Who do you think you are?
Out!
你以为你是谁？滚！
Er hat ein schlechtes Gewissen.
He has a guilty conscience.
他心里有愧疚。
Was ist falsch daran, eine Frage zu stellen?
What's wrong
with asking a question?
问一个问题有什么错吗？
Schauen wir uns die Polizeidienststelle noch einmal an.
Let's check out
the police department again.
我们再去警察局看看吧。
Es gibt einen Ort des Friedens und der Ruhe
There is a place
of peace and calm
有一个和平与安宁的地方
Geborgen in Gottes Umarmung
Safe in God's embrace
在上帝的怀抱中安全
An diesem Ort
In that place
在那个地方
Kein Übel wohnt
No evil dwells
无邪恶存在
Geborgen in Gottes Umarmung
Safe in God's embrace
在上帝的怀抱中安全
Jesus, unser gütiger Retter
Jesus, our benevolent savior
耶稣，我们的仁慈救世主
Kommt aus Gottes Umarmung
Comes from God's embrace
来自上帝的怀抱
Wir warten sehnsüchtig auf die Zeit
We earnestly await the time
我们热切地等待着
Wenn wir in Gottes Umarmung ruhen
When we'll rest in God's embrace
当我们在上帝的怀抱中安息时
Im Sommer 1961
In the summer of 1961,
1961年夏天，
Xiao Si'r erhielt das Todesurteil
Xiao Si'r received
the death sentence
小四儿被判处死刑
vom Bezirksgericht Taipeh.
from the District Court of Taipei.
台北地方法院。
Der erste Jugendmordfall in Taiwan
Being the first juvenile
homicide case in Taiwan
台湾第一起未成年人杀人案
unter nationalistischer Regierungsherrschaft,
under Nationalist
government rule,
在国民党政府统治下，
Der Fall und das Urteil wurden ausführlich diskutiert.
the case and sentence
were widely debated.
该案件和判决引起了广泛争论。
Das Bezirksobergericht wandelte das Urteil später um
The District High Court
later commuted the sentence
地方高等法院后来减刑
zu 15 Jahren Gefängnis.
to 15 years in prison.
最高可判处 15 年监禁。
Xiao Si'r wurde kurz vor seinem 30. Geburtstag aus dem Gefängnis entlassen.
Xiao Si'r was released from prison
shortly before his 30th birthday.
小四儿在即将满30岁生日的时候出狱了。
Zwei Monate nach dem Vorfall ...
Two months after the incident...
事件发生两个月后……
Die anderen Herren sagten, Sie akzeptieren Kassetten.
The other gentlemen said
you accept tapes.
另一位先生说你接受磁带。
Wer hat das gesagt?
Who said that?
谁说的？
Du erfindest es.
You're making it up.
你是在编造。
Wir akzeptieren niemals Bänder.
We never accept tapes.
我们从不接受磁带。
Ich wollte einen Brief hinterlassen.
I wanted to leave a letter.
我想留下一封信。
Er sagte, dass in der Poststelle leicht Briefe verloren gehen.
He said letters get lost easily
in the mail room.
他说信件在邮件室很容易丢失。
Er schlug stattdessen ein Band vor.
He suggested a tape instead.
他建议改用磁带。
- Sind Sie ein Familienmitglied? - Nein.
- Are you a family member?
- No.
- 您是家庭成员吗？ - 不是。
Herr, haben Sie nicht gesagt, dass Sie Kassetten annehmen?
Mister, didn't you say
you accept tapes?
先生，你不是说你接受磁带吗？
Tun Sie es oder tun Sie es nicht?
Do you or don't you?
你会还是不会？
- Für wen ist es? - Zhang Zhen.
- Who's it for?
- Zhang Zhen.
- 给谁的？ - 张震。
In Ordnung.
All right.
好的。
Lass es einfach liegen und geh!
Just leave it and go!
放手去吧！
Sir, erinnern Sie sich an dieses Lied, das ich aufgenommen habe?
Sir, remember
this song I recorded?
先生，还记得我录的这首歌吗？
Raten Sie mal, wem ich es geschickt habe.
Guess who I mailed it to.
猜猜我把它寄给了谁。
Elvis!
猫王！
Er hat sogar zurückgeschrieben.
He even wrote back.
他甚至还回信了。
Er war überrascht, dass seine Musik so beliebt ist
He was surprised to learn
his music is so popular
他很惊讶自己的音乐如此受欢迎
auf dieser unbekannten kleinen Insel.
on this unknown little island.
在这个不为人知的小岛上。
Er war gerührt und hat mir sogar ein Geschenk geschickt.
He was touched.
He even sent me a gift.
他很感动，还送了我一份礼物。
Schade, dass Sie es nicht sehen können.
Too bad you can't see it.
可惜你看不到。
Ich trage den Ring, den er mir geschickt hat, jeden Tag.
I wear the ring
he sent me every day.
我每天都戴着他送我的戒指。
Es ist wirklich cool!
It's really cool!
真的很酷！
Ich weiß nur nicht, wann ich es Ihnen zeigen kann.
I just don't know
when I'll get to show it to you.
我只是不知道什么时候才能将它展示给你。
Was ist das für ein Ding?
What's this thing?
这是啥东西？
Scheiße!
Shit!
拉屎！
Hey, das Radio funktioniert!
Hey, the radio's working!
嘿，收音机正常运转！
Beweg es nicht! Es fliegt wieder raus!
Don't move it!
It'll out out again!
别动它！它会再次出来！
Kang Fu-mei, Wang Chao-jen, Yeh Hsin-ming...
Kang Fu-mei,
Wang Chao-jen, Yeh Hsin-ming...
Chao Hung, Chen Chang-chem ...
Chao Hung,
Chen Chang-chem...
赵宏、陈昌化工...
Die Vorgenannten haben sich für die Abteilung für chinesische Literatur qualifiziert.
The preceding have qualified
for the Chinese Literature Department.
以上人员已取得中国文学系学位。
Für die Abteilung für ausländische Literatur haben sich qualifiziert:
The following have qualified
for the Foreign Literature Department
以下人员已获得外国文学系资格
an der National Taiwan University:
at National Taiwan University:
国立台湾大学：
Chou Fu-jung, Chang Shih-ling...
Chen Cheng-fu, Chang Chih-ho...
Außerdem
Also Featuring
其他特色
WANG CHUAN, CHANG HAN CHIANG HSIU-CHIUNG
WANG CHUAN, CHANG HAN
CHIANG HSIU-CHIUNG
王川、张汉江修琼
STEPHANIE LAL WONG CHI-ZAN, LAWRENCE KO
STEPHANIE LAl
WONG CHI-ZAN, LAWRENCE KO
STEPHANIE LAL WONG CHI-ZAN、LAWRENCE KO
TAN CHIH-KANG CHANG MING-HSIN, JUNG CHUN-LUNG
TAN CHIH-KANG
CHANG MING-HSIN, JUNG CHUN-LUNG
陈志刚 张明信、郑俊龙
ZHOU HUI-GUO TANG HSIAO-TSUI, LIN HONG-MING
ZHOU HUI-GUO
TANG HSIAO-TSUI, LIN HONG-MING
BOSEN WANG CHEN HUNG-YU
BOSEN WANG
CHEN HUNG-YU
HSU MING, CHO MING
Bühnenbild von EDWARD YANG
Set Decoration by
EDWARD YANG
EDWARD YANG 的布景设计
Produktionsdesign von YU WEI-YEN
Production Design by
YU WEI-YEN
制作设计：YU WEI-YEN
Kostümdesign von WU LE-CHIN
Costume Design by
WU LE-CHIN
服装设计：吴乐勤